Preach the word. Be ready in season and out of season. Convince, rebuke, exhort with all long
suffering and teaching. For the time will come when they will not endure sound doctrine, but
according to their own desires, because they have itching ears, they will heap up for themselves
teachers, and they will turn their ears away from the truth and be turned aside to fables.
The 2nd Timothy chapter 4 verses 2 through 4. As I start this message, I am reminded of the truth
of these verses, because when I have brought this topic up before, many have proven to be a
confirmation of just how truthful this prophecy of these times are. People have itching ears,
and they heap up for themselves teachers that will teach them what they want to hear,
and they will often remove themselves from truths that are uncomfortable, but are necessary to deal
with. For many people with their
eyes, they have itching ears, and they heap up for themselves teachers that will teach them
It's apparent that we are in the last days. We are in the end times. There are many reasons for
this understanding. When understanding this, depending on who you are and your level of faith,
it can come with either a feeling of anticipation and excitement, or a feeling of anxiety and fear.
Are you ready is the question that you may ask yourself. One of the hardest things many of us
have to deal with is the possibility that we are not. And the biggest reason that we might not
be ready is because we may have been following the wrong influence. I recently made a video
discussing all the beliefs of all the other religions of the world. I showed that all
religions have a belief in the end times. But if you are a Christian, you know that those other
religions lead to the Antichrist. That should be understood. But what about your belief as a
Christian? Is the belief of Christianity something that is Satan-proof? Meaning that, is it not
possible that Christianity also can be leading to the Antichrist? Is it not possible that Christianity
is leading to the same place as all those other false religions are leading to? I mean,
Christianity is the largest religion in the world. Almost one-third of the world identify
as Christians. So, does that mean that it's only the rest of the world that's deceived and not
Christians? Or maybe it's deeper than that. Maybe it's possible that some Christians are
deceived, but not you, or not your denomination. Like for instance, of the almost 2.5 billion
people that identify as Christians, more than half of them are Christians. And that's because
half of them identify as Catholics. So, maybe you feel that that's where the deception really is.
It's with the Catholics, not with you. You are a Bible-believing Christian. You are a firm Acts 2
38 believer. For me personally, I have been a Christian a majority of my whole life. Predominantly
Baptist, and then later non-denominational. I love our Father, and I love our Messiah.
I believe that all can be saved through the blood of Messiah. But many years ago, I began to realize
a major problem, and I tried to fight through it as much as possible to shift blame away from
the major point, the major elephant in the room. I was making many different excuses before I had
to deal with the conclusion I had to really come to terms with. This right here is a dangerous
topic, and it's hard to hear at first. But I promise you, it's the truth. I want you to know
that first, that this video is not trying to steer you away from your belief in the Messiah
who took the penalty for your sins. It is not trying to steer you away from the Bible at all.
It is not trying to steer you away from the way, the actual faith that the apostles had and followed
in the book of Acts. You may see this video or this title and immediately get defensive and say,
oh he's wrong, just another blasphemer, without ever trying to understand me. And listen, that is
your choice to make. I've had people I have conversed with on this channel for years just
unsubscribe without giving any feedback just because they didn't like the title of my video.
They didn't hear me out, but assumed that they knew.
At the end of the day, this is of course your choice on how you deal with what I am presenting.
But I promise you that I am trying to save many of you from the grips and deception of the enemy.
You know, unfortunately, there are just some things that we just take at face value
because we just grew up under it for so long. But we never really looked under the hood to really
test it. Some things we just felt that they didn't need to be actually tested. But the scriptures
tell us to test everything, don't they? ...That's what we do. Test all things, hold fast to what is
good. 1st Thessalonians Chapter five verse 21…. zag glass is leather-zip- abrir plastic gloves
So yeah, that's what we must do, test all the things. And yeah, test me too.
You can disagree with certain conclusions I have made.
You may disagree that the Israelites are the Negroes scattered around around the world that
have been under the curses. You can disagree with that. Now, I do feel if you disagree,
you must agree with the actual facts not emotions but either way I believe you're and I think that enjoy
you can disagree. But even if you disagree with my conclusion, does me having that thought make
me against our Messiah? It shouldn't, because nothing could be further from the truth.
You see, as I said, I grew up in a Christian home. My mother and my grandmother were both
strong Christians. Both sides of my family, my mom and my dad's side, were Christians.
Everyone believed in Jesus. But as I got older and started my own family,
I began having questions. And the same strong Christians I was raised under,
when I started asking them questions, these strong Christians rejected me. Actually,
they got angry with the questions and called me prideful for walking in my convictions because
they never answered my questions. That behavior, it never made sense to me, and it still doesn't.
It is exactly why so many of my friends and people I've met in my lifetime, why they reject
the Bible and why they reject the church. They have questions, and instead of people answering
them, they're just like, oh, I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't
know. I just got rejected or just told that's not important. That's hypocrisy. To me, if you are
strong on something, you should be able to answer questions about why, especially for people who
call themselves Christians, and they've been doing this for a much longer time than I have been.
They were simple questions, too. Questions like, where did this Christmas tree come from?
Like, Dad, I could not understand where it came from. Granted, I never read the whole Bible,
but with some internet searches, I could not.
I asked questions, and people would just say, it's what we do. I didn't accept that.
That led me deeper into asking, why do we even celebrate Christmas on December 25th?
I couldn't find that date in the Bible anywhere. I couldn't even find that they celebrated
Christmas. And then it made me wonder, why do we do a lot of things? I asked questions just so I
can get clarity. I wasn't trying to go against the faith. I just really wanted to know. And
when I'm asking these questions,
I realize how much I've been wronged. People avoided giving me answers, and in fact,
they got angry because I was asking it. That started my journey over a decade ago,
maybe longer. I can't even count at this point, to really understand Christianity without asking
others who I was offending. I was just offending people by asking questions, and that led me to
where it should lead everyone. Straight to the Bible, to read it for myself. And when I did that,
what I found after reading it for myself many times has led me to a wonderful change.
I'm going to be a better person. And I'm going to be a better person. I'm going to be a better person.
a better person. I'm going to be a better person. I'm going to be a better person.
But when I did that, what I found after reading this for myself many times, has led me to a wonder.
has led me to a wonderful place.
First, it led me to a very strong relationship
with our Father in Heaven,
where I understand Him and His will and His plan for us.
But it also removed people from my life
that did not truly love me or Yah,
and this has been able to protect my peace.
It exposed the snakes in my grass.
What happened is that I found out
that the faith of Christianity does not actually match
with the faith that I was actually reading about
in the scriptures.
In fact, they are two extremely different things.
I realized that if I never came to this understanding,
I would be very different today,
probably in an unhappy, immoral home
filled with an unknown substance in my body
because I was trying to protect myself
from something I couldn't even see,
while either voting for my blackness
or voting for Donald Trump trying to save America.
I would be thinking too much about money
and I'd just be immoral.
But I would be saved because I'm a Christian.
But all the while, I would be heading straight to the beast.
Now, listen, I'm not saying this is all Christians.
I say this based off my life.
I know based off the people in my life before my awakening
and being that that's where most of them are now,
that's what I base that conclusion off.
That's not to offend anyone,
but me just keeping it real about myself
and the Christians that I know.
I am not in any way saying
that all Christians are tied
to making all those wrong decisions
that the Christians that I know made.
Please don't misunderstand me.
Anyways, like I said,
I found out that Christianity does not actually match
with what the Bible says.
And in fact, our Messiah actually prophesied
multiple times about this.
This subject was hard for me to embrace
because of the implications behind it.
So I made many excuses early on
and tried to finagle my way around it
and say maybe it was this and maybe it was that.
Maybe.
Maybe it was those Mike Todd type of Christians
or maybe it was Catholicism or more.
It was just a bunch of different things,
but it wasn't Christianity as a whole.
It was really hard for me to embrace it.
First off, what if I'm wrong?
I'm literally damning myself and my family to hell
by making these kinds of statements.
Secondly, a third of the world are Christians.
So by me declaring this,
I'm literally going against the beliefs
of a third of the world population.
And that's not easy to do.
Also,
even if I am right,
is it worth stirring up a pot like this
when I have such a large audience?
I went through a lot of those thoughts
and you know what I came up with?
Yeah, it's worth stirring up the pot
because it's extremely important.
And Yahuwah gave me an audience for a purpose
and I must use it for his will
and not to protect my own self from conflict.
I realized that this is why Yahuwah,
when he led me into ministry,
he didn't give me a Christian name
or a Christian handle.
The ministry,
is truth unedited
because truth has been edited
and these things need to be brought out
regardless of conflict or backlash.
So I need to talk to you about Christianity.
Again, as I said earlier,
I recognize that your first thought is to reject me
and find a reason to speak against me.
I mean, I get it.
Let me tell you,
I am not forcing you to believe me
and you can do what you want
with what I'm presenting to you.
My job is not to force you to believe
with it,
what it is I'm saying,
but it is for me to present you with this information
so that you can make a wise decision
given all the facts.
I understand that your first thought is to just reject me.
I mean, that's what defense is.
But if you're able to hear out the whole matter,
by the time I get to the end,
you should have clarity
and there should not be much confusion.
I don't expect everyone to agree,
but if I can help some of you from being led to the beast
and being burned in the furnace,
I would like to try.
And yeah, I just said that.
This is a deep subject.
I have made many videos in the past about this subject,
but they have not been comprehensive.
I recently did another important series
about another important subject
that many others disagree with.
That subject being who biblical Israel really is
and why it's important.
In that series, I broke things down piece by piece.
And so I have been led to do the same with this.
If you're able to hear me out by the end of the series,
I think you will understand completely why Christianity,
is something you want to come out of.
So this series is going to go over
what is exactly wrong with Christianity.
This topic is extremely important
and there are consequences
for being on the wrong side of it.
All I ask is that you hear me out before you get defensive.
I am not your enemy.
This right here is just an introduction
and there is not a lot of meat in it.
So there's no reason to get defensive yet.
That time will come.
But as we are preparing for tribulation to start,
it's important that this topic is brought out in clarity
so that everyone can hear the truth concretely
and from that make up their own minds.
So we will now start the discussion
about what is wrong with Christianity.
Let's begin.
Okay, so first off, let's get this straight.
This is not a fight about a label.
I am not coming in talking about labels of Christianity.
I was speaking with a brother about this
and he could not get this point out of his head
that he was fighting for this label of Christianity.
And then when he heard my explanation, he said,
that's not what he understood Christianity to be.
This brother, I believe is sincere in his faith
and truly loves Yah.
And so I believe that Yah sent him to me
to have this discussion to prepare me
to handle this whole thing.
So let's deal with this first.
If you became a Christian in isolation
and never had any influence
and you came up with the religion of Christianity on your own,
please tell your story in the comments for us all to see.
I will pin it at the top.
For the most part, this is not the case for the majority.
The thing is that people don't actually want to recognize this.
I have actually never met anyone like this.
Even if you read the Bible on your own
and you begin to believe on your own,
that still does not mean that you're without influence.
There are churches on every corner,
especially in the United States here.
If you have never heard of Christianity
and you're acting like you don't associate Christianity
with the Bible, you're deceiving yourself.
The people believe, and I put emphasis on believe.
People believe that Christianity is synonymous
with belief in the Bible.
Once people start reading their Bible,
they start calling themselves Christians
because Christianity is the biggest influence in this world.
Christianity is the largest religion in the world.
There are over 8 billion people in the world
and 2.5 billion people classify themselves as Christians.
There is no other bigger religious group.
So for someone to act as if their definition of Christianity
is without any influence, it's very much naive
or not really thought out.
I mean, how do you feel that you cannot be influenced at all
by the biggest religion in the world?
You know, for the people here in the United States,
the United States was once classified.
I don't know if they still classify themselves at this,
but they were once classified as a Christian country.
This is a Christian country.
So the influence of this country was surrounded by Christians.
They were surrounded around Christianity for decades,
centuries maybe, I don't know,
but they claimed to be Christians in this country
from the get-go.
I mean, very hypocritical Christians
and not really based in truth, but whatever.
They call themselves Christians.
So for people here to act like they never had any kind
of influence from Christianity at all, you're being naive.
So let's be clear.
I want to make it clear.
This is what I'm talking about.
I'm not talking about your label.
I'm talking about the religion of Christianity.
It's hard to pinpoint because once you say Christianity,
then it can mean multiple other things,
like what type of Christian are you?
Baptist, Catholic, Lutheran, Calvinist, Methodist,
Presbyterian, Jehovah's Witness, Seventh-day Adventist.
I mean, the list goes on and on.
So maybe that's why you say you're non-denominational.
But okay, there are still doctrines
that Christians believe in overall,
no matter what denomination.
These things are spoken out and written,
and others are foundational.
And though they are never communicated,
it's what people believe.
For instance, here's a major one.
Let me ask you, who is our father, Yahuwah, the Most High?
Who is he actually in covenant with according to the Bible?
What's the biblical answer to that question?
Now, you won't find written doctrine that says this,
but Christians as a whole believe that our father
is in covenant with Christians.
And everything that the Bible is,
is about them in the long run.
But here's the deal.
That's a very wrong thought to have.
And the implications of applying that thought are huge.
But you know what?
When you look in the mainstream,
there is no one really challenging
this major false understanding
and clarifying it in these Christian churches.
And believe me, I'm gonna back all this up.
I'm just setting the stage here.
What I'm going to do in this video is give you a test.
That's how we're gonna start.
And if you disagree with what I am saying about Christianity,
you can take this test and back it up and prove it.
I challenge you to find two or three Christians,
more if you can.
If you have access to your pastor, even better.
I'm going to give you simple questions,
about five simple questions.
And all you need to do is get the answer to them.
And at the end, if you review the answers to these questions
and see how biblically wrong they are,
then you will have to admit that there is a problem.
There is a problem with Christianity.
Is that fair?
I hope so.
So here are the questions.
Question one.
I started it earlier.
Who did our father, Yahuwah, the most high,
make the new covenant with?
Question two.
What scripture gives the covenant for Christians?
Question three.
What does our father plan to do in the last days
before Messiah comes back and becomes king?
Question four.
What are you waiting for our father to do with Christians
during these last days?
Like, are you waiting for the pre-tribulation rapture?
Are you ready to go in a bunker and hide out
during the tribulation to escape the antichrist?
What do you expect our father to do with Christians
in these last days?
And question five.
Are we trying to go to heaven or stay on earth?
That's it.
These are very simple, very basic questions.
They are not hard.
Hard theological questions, not questions
that should draw a great deal of debate,
but they are fundamental to this faith.
I've written these questions out and put them on a PDF
so you don't even have to write them down yourself.
I placed a link in the description box for you
to save and print them out.
I want you to hold on to these questions.
I'm not going to answer these questions now.
What we will do is go through the subject methodically.
And by the end of the series, all these questions
will be covered biblically.
And you can review your answers.
And the answers of those that you have asked.
And I am sure that you will find that there
are a large majority of people that have the answers
to these questions wrong.
Then you have to admit that there is a major problem
with this faith and religion.
Because for the largest religion in the world,
and the fact that everyone has a Bible,
and there are more churches in this world than hospitals
or schools, these questions should be easily answered
and answered accurate according to the scriptures.
And this is regardless of denomination.
What is the point of where I'm going?
And why is this important?
First thing is that most people don't understand
that Satan has a plan for those following Christianity.
I will go over that plan later and show you.
But the plan is that once the tribulation period starts,
and many people find out that their faith in Christianity
was not actually based on truth, but religion,
they will not be directed into the truth,
but they will be directed into the doctrines of Lucifer.
Which will be brought out in main view for the world
during the tribulation.
I mean, the doctrines of Lucifer are actually being brought out
right now in everyone's faces, and most people don't even see it.
It is my belief that if you wake up to this agenda,
and maybe if you don't even believe me now,
but when things do change, you may remember this series.
And then you may remember that there was an alternative explanation
rather than the garbage that they're going to feed you during that time.
And hopefully you will have enough courage and sense at that time to repent,
and make changes.
I don't believe that these messages will be available at that time.
So it's important to plant the seeds now.
If you remember during COVID, anyone who had a different perspective
about what was happening, were suppressed and not tolerated.
When the world changes, I expect things to be similar.
And I feel better knowing that I did my best to warn whoever I could.
The second reason, and this is the most important.
Our Messiah, which is the reason everyone calls themselves a Christian, he actually prophesied about this.
And that this would be a problem in the last days.
And he explained what would happen to those who are a part of it.
If you're attached to this, you run a very great risk.
And I will absolutely explain to you why.
Listen, Christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical.
But when you dig deep into the doctrines, it is not a doctrine of service to our Father,
but a doctrine of abusing grace, editing covenants, rejecting the
way our Father actually chose to reach humanity, and making it only be about the way Christians
want to receive him.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our Father that he deserves.
And in the end, it does not prepare those who follow it to be ready for what our Father
actually plans to do in the last days.
If you desire to be ready for our Father and his plan for us, you must come out of this
religion of terror.
And come to our Father in truth.
So I recognize that the next stumbling block and defense is that the word Christian is
literally written in your King James Bible.
So how in the world is it that Christian is in the Bible, and I'm here speaking against
Christianity?
Maybe you're asking, am I just going against the word?
That is a fair defense.
And so being that I want to be thorough, I'm going to deal with that next.
Please move to part two in this playlist.
And understand that the word Christian is literally written in your King James Bible.
And understand why even though you see Christian in the Bible, I still reject that word and
that label.
But it's important to really understand why.
So we're going to discuss it.
Click the link to the next video, and we'll talk some more about it.
Be blessed.
Hallelujah.
Praise.
Yah.
Okay.
Thanks again for watching.
If this has blessed you, please like this and share this video with your family and
your friends.
This video series is highly important for those trying to be ready for our Father.
And if you want to learn more, please subscribe to our YouTube channel and hit the bell so
you don't miss any of our videos.
This is part one of the series.
Click this link or just move on to the next video in the playlist.
As always, I want to thank all who donate and contribute to this ministry.
This series would not be possible without your support.
I thank you sincerely.
Be blessed.
Okay.
Thanks again, everyone, for watching.
See you in part two.
I love you all.