Okay, so you should be coming from part one of this series.
These videos are part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is being presented.
So please, if you have not watched part one, please stop this video and start back to video one.
Okay, so in part one, I introduced this topic about what's wrong in Christianity.
I must reiterate, this video is not an attack on your biblical faith, but it is made to help you hone in on what is actually biblical versus what is religious.
As I discuss Christianity, I know that there is a major stumbling block just due to the translation of the King James.
The word Christian is literally written in your King James Bible.
So how is it that the word Christian is in the Bible and that I can speak against Christianity?
Am I just going against the word?
Like I said earlier, that's a fair defense.
And so being that I want to be thorough, I must deal with that first.
So let me explain this first.
I said this in the first video.
Christianity is not synonymous with the Bible.
And what I mean by that is that when I speak against Christianity, I am not speaking against the Bible.
They are not synonymous, meaning they don't mean the same thing, even if right now you attach them together.
If you feel that way, you are wrong.
If I speak against Christianity, I am not speaking against the Bible.
I believe in the Bible fully, all of the Bible, no exclusions.
So if you believe that me saying I'm against Christianity is the same thing as me being against the Bible, you are incorrect.
The actual truth is that Christianity is against the Bible.
But we'll get there.
Understand, Christianity is a religion.
It is a belief that claims to be centered around the Bible.
And if this was entirely true, then I would not be making this video.
It does me no good to talk about something that is actually directly correlated with the scriptures.
In my conversations with others, they want to live according to the definition that they want to view Christianity as.
But we can't do that.
That's just deception.
We are in the 21st century.
Most things we know are based upon influence.
Most things we speak about are due to how it has been presented over time to us.
and we choose how we adapt to it or not.
I'm going to use this conversation I had with a brother about this conversation
because I think his way of thinking is the way of the majority
that naturally have an issue with this topic.
He said this,
I've always believed a Christian is someone who has repented of their sins
and put their faith in Jesus Christ, Yahusha, for payment slash atonement of sins
and was raised by Yah himself the third day,
giving us assurance we too will be resurrected.
That's been my understanding.
The believer is also filled with the Holy Spirit and sealed until the day of redemption.
Reread the whole Bible, not just the New Testament.
A Christian in my eyes was always a Gentile who got to get in
because Israel has been blinded for a season.
And that is his definition of a Christian.
And let me say that I have no problem with this definition for the most part.
I do think it needs some refinement.
And maybe I would ask more questions because it sounds like
he's going with the once saved, always saved, but whatever.
At the end, it's nothing that would make me at odds
and make me make a whole video series against Christianity.
You understand?
So please, I get it.
This is what people believe Christianity is for the most part.
Now listen, there is a deeper problem with this and that definition
that is actually the biggest problem with Christianity.
And that is the hijacking of the covenant.
But I am not ready to discuss that yet.
I want to take it slow so there's no confusion.
What I'm saying is that if this is your definition of Christianity
and this is what you are thinking I'm coming against,
then you are incorrect.
Just because this is what you believe Christianity is,
it does not mean that this is actually what it is.
Christianity is a religion.
It is a world religion.
It is a religion.
It is a religion that has been spread through our modern era
for about 2,000 years.
That definition that he gave and believed Christianity is
will be better presented as what the way is.
This is what the apostles said that they actually practiced.
Not Christianity.
They practiced the way.
Understand this.
After the apostles were killed
and the spreading of the way was done,
there is about a 300 year gap of history
that is not widely known.
It is not widely spoken about in regards to the way.
At some point,
the main spreading of Christianity
was not done by those following the way.
In the Hebrews, the Yahudim,
what you call Jews,
they were removed out of the picture of spreading the way.
And then later Rome made Christianity their main religion.
If it was not for this move in history,
two and a half billion people in this world today
would not be Christians.
Again,
Christianity is the biggest religion in the world.
You need to really understand how it became this.
Now, we will go through the history of Christianity soon.
But before that,
let me deal with this big stumbling block, as I said,
and that is the word Christian.
You see, people feel justified and rejected in what I'm saying
because they see the word Christian in their Bible.
So of course, they say,
how can I come against them for being a Christian
because it's clearly written in the scriptures?
So I want to deal with that first
because I get it.
And it's a very good point.
Someone may challenge me and ask,
well, how do you deal with these scriptures?
Yet, if anyone suffers as a Christian,
let him not be ashamed,
but let him glorify God in this manner.
1 Peter 4, verse 16.
Another one.
And when he had found him,
he brought him to Antioch.
So it was that for a whole year,
they assembled with the church
and taught a great many people.
And the disciples were first called Christians in Antioch.
That's Acts chapter 11, verse 26.
So let's be clear about a couple of things
when using these scriptures.
First thing, when dealing with Peter,
saying anyone suffers as a Christian,
let's be clear that that is not what Peter wrote.
That is a translation.
I mean, Peter's name is a translation.
If you're holding onto this
and using this as a basis to be called a Christian,
you are incorrect.
But why do I say this?
Understand this,
by understanding who Peter actually was.
Peter, whose name is actually Kepha,
but let's just say Peter.
Peter was from the tribe of Judah.
He was a Hebrew.
He spoke Hebrew.
He did not speak Greek.
How do we know this?
Well, this is why.
Mark was with him as he traveled.
He was there as his interpreter.
When looking at the writings of the early church,
when speaking of Mark,
this is why.
This is what was written.
Irenaeus writes,
Mark, the interpreter and follower of Peter,
begins his gospel narrative in this narrative.
Also, the Clement of Alexandria,
another Gentile of the early church,
he writes this about Mark.
Mark was the follower of Peter.
Peter publicly preached the gospel at Rome
before some of Caesar's equestrian knights
and adduced many testimonies to Messiah
in order that, thereby,
they might be able to commit to memory
what was spoken by Peter.
Mark wrote entirely what is called
the gospel according to Mark.
So, this is how we know.
If Peter spoke Greek or Latin,
then he would not have needed an interpreter.
And he definitely,
he definitely did not write his epistle in Greek.
He was a Hebrew.
Now, I will speak more to this later,
but this is one major problem with Christianity.
So, let's just talk about it quick.
They want to be a part of the blessing.
Christians, I'm talking about.
But they want to misappropriate culture
and apply the doctrine of Hellenization to the faith.
The Bible is not a book defined by many cultures.
That's not what it is.
The Bible is a book about one culture
and one people,
Yasharel, the sons of Jacob,
who Yahuwah made a covenant with.
Their culture is based off their Torah,
the first five books of the Bible.
Christians want to take the covenant
and engage in the covenant with God.
They want to ignore that culture
and rebrand it for themselves.
When you do this,
you ignore the very special way Yahuwah led Yasharel.
He did not attach to the cultures of the other nations.
He did not allow them to do this.
He, in fact, told them to not learn the ways of the other nations.
That was their culture.
One of the books of the Bible that was not included
was the book of Maccabees.
If this was included,
most people would know that the war
that the Yahudim had with the Greeks,
before the time of Messiah came,
there was a war with the Greeks.
There were Yahudim,
that's the word again for Jew,
there were Yahudim that bowed to Greece
and they assimilated with them.
They adapted to Hellenism,
which is just the spreading of Greek culture,
and they rejected the culture of the Yahudim.
The Yahudim who fought against Greece and they won,
they rejected those sellout Yahudim who assimilated
and they called them Greeks or Gentiles.
This is who were there in so many synagogues
set up in Asia Minor and in Greece and in Spain
that made Paul visit them.
The Yahudim in Rome that Peter went to
were not the same assimilated ones,
but the ones that were taken by Titus as slaves
when Rome first conquered and took control of Judea.
That's a quick summary of the history,
but I need you to understand that.
What I'm sharing is that if this history was understood,
then attaching Greek culture to the Yahudim
would not be something that we would understand.
We would tolerate.
But unfortunately, this is what Christians do.
They attach any culture from the Gentile nations
and they make it apply to the one nation of people
in this world that were set apart
from the other nations of the world.
The rest of the world had it their way.
Yahuwah set Yahshu'el apart from all nations.
This was their way.
And what Christianity does is it ignores all of that.
It ignores the special set apart way
that Yah had Yahshu'el.
And they say all cultures come together
and they can make and be whatever Christianity wants it to be.
That's overgeneralization, but this is really what the struggle is.
I can show this very clearly that this is not right
by using the writings of Josephus.
Who is that?
A Yahudim named Josephus wrote a book called
The Antiquities of the Jews.
He wrote this history of the Jews in Greek
around the year 93 or 94.
This was after Rome destroyed the temple
and pushed the Jews out of Judea.
The Antiquities of the Jews contains an account
of the history of the Yahudim for Gentiles
who come to know Josephus.
And so maybe you want to say like,
see, they did write in Greek.
Just hold on, read this.
There's a lot of history in that book.
And it is understood who his audience is.
But what he said in the last chapter of the 20th volume
is important for historical context.
I want you to read what he wrote.
And I am so bold as to say,
now I have so completely perfected the work
I proposed to myself to do,
that no other person,
whether he were a Jew or foreigner,
had he ever so great an inclination to it,
could so accurately deliver these accounts to the Greeks
as is done in these books.
For those of my own nation
freely acknowledge that I far exceed them
in the learning belonging to Jews.
I have also taken a great deal of pains
to obtain the learning of the Greeks
and understand the elements of the Greek language.
Although I have so long accustomed myself
to speak our own tongue
that I cannot pronounce Greek with sufficient exactness.
For our nation does not encourage those
that learn the languages of many nations
and so adorn their discourses
with the smoothness of their periods.
I understand that."
I mean, this is very clear if you just apply it.
This was the mindset of a Jew
20 years after the temple was destroyed.
The culture of the Jews did not encourage those
to learn the language of many nations.
Notice he said he took a great deal of pains to learn Greek.
It's not like it was just an easy subject
people learned in high school.
That was not the way of the Yahudim.
And if you truly understood this faith,
you must understand them.
When Greece Hellenized the world,
the Yahudim were to be set apart from all that.
They were not to be allowed to be steered
in the pagan culture of the Romans or the Greeks.
And if you understand the history of the Yahudim,
this understanding would always be a part of you.
You can never forget it.
He said it very clearly.
Our nation does not encourage those
that learn the languages of many nations.
The Hebrew language and culture was very big
to the Hebrews.
And so you cannot understand this people
while ignoring their culture.
But this is exactly what Christianity does.
So what am I getting at here?
When dealing with that verse from Peter,
it says,
Yet if anyone suffers as a Christian,
let him not be ashamed,
but let him glorify God in this manner.
That's 1 Peter 4.16.
What I'm getting at is that
Peter did not write Christian.
Because Christian comes from Christos of Greek.
He would have said Mashiach.
He was with the Messiah.
Mashiach is the word for Messiah.
He wouldn't say Christos.
He would have said Mashiach.
He literally was with the Messiah.
It would be better translated Messianus
rather than Christian.
You see, the reason why Rome uses Christos
instead of Mashiach
is because of syncretism.
And I will get back to that word
when we go over the history.
When we use Christos instead of Mashiach,
it's because we are attaching to the Greek
pagan culture of this idea of an anointed one.
The Greek word Christos means anointed one
or chosen one.
That's their word for it.
By using Christos of Greek,
you are attaching with their pagan culture
of an anointed one.
This is how syncretism works.
But I will explain that deeper
as we get into the history.
But my point is simple.
When Peter wrote this epistle,
he did not write Christos,
attaching to the pagan Greeks of his time.
It's also why we adapt to the Greek form
of the Messiah's name
and not the Hebrew name.
Jesus does not match with Yahushua
in transliteration from Hebrew.
They adapted Greek culture to the faith
very subtly
and made the faith adapt to the Greeks
instead of the Hebrew influence
that it actually came from.
And if you know the history,
you'll understand why later.
Christos is what Christians identify themselves from.
Jesus is what they call our Messiah.
All that influence is Greek.
None of this is influenced from the culture
that the Bible is written after.
If you think that that's just a coincidence
and is not something bigger behind it,
you're not thinking deep enough.
Let's look at the other scripture.
What it says in Acts 11, verse 26,
that the disciples were called Christians.
It says,
And when he had found them,
he brought him to Antioch.
So it was that for a whole year
they assembled with the church
and taught a great many people.
And the disciples were first called
Christians in Antioch.
Okay, and listen,
this is the same understanding,
but it still does not matter.
Again, it's translating using the Greek influence
and not the Hebrew one.
But even without that point,
this is not what they call themselves.
This is what others call them.
Listen, read it, what it says.
It says,
The disciples were first called Christians.
It's not what they call themselves.
It's what others call them.
And it's still a translation.
But listen,
just because they were called this
does not supersede the rest of the Bible
and how our Father made the new covenant.
Yeah, whatever.
They were called Christians.
But it does not say that they called themselves this.
They, in fact,
if you actually are applying the scriptures,
they said that they followed the way.
Let me show you.
Then Saul,
still breathing threats and murder
against the disciples of the Adon,
went to the high priest
and asked letters from him
to the synagogues of Damascus,
so that if he found any who were of the way,
whether men or women,
he might bring them down to Jerusalem.
Acts 9, verses 1 and 2.
Paul speaks and says,
I persecuted this way to the death,
binding and delivering into prisons
both men and women.
He didn't say,
I persecuted Christians.
He said,
I persecuted this way.
Also,
but this I confess to you,
that according to the way,
which they call a sect,
so I worship the Elohim of my fathers,
believing all things which are written in the law
and in the prophets.
Acts 24, verse 14.
According to the way,
which they call a sect.
He didn't say according to Christianity,
He said according to the way.
So what am I getting at here?
When Christianity was spread throughout the world,
there was a direct effort to remove the influence
that Yahweh had on his people,
and they merged in the already pagan culture
in with the culture of the Hebrews.
They've done this through doctrine,
but they've also done this through language,
like the Pope says about language.
Sort of a comparison and an example would be
they're sort of like different languages
in order to arrive at God.
But God is God for all.
That is the doctrine of Rome.
Many languages lead to the path of God.
And they use this to bring the world
into neo-pagan belief system
that sounds biblical,
but only from a top glance.
When you dig deeper,
the truth comes staring right back at you.
So this is dealing with the fact
that Christians is written in the scriptures.
Yes, this is true.
But this is because of a neo-pagan culture
that was tied to the translation.
Now, listen.
I'm not just drawing straws here.
If this was the main issue
and it wasn't deeper than that,
none of what I said would matter.
Because the true culture and faith,
it would still be there.
But I want you to understand that
every time you twist
and you water down the truth,
the truth becomes hidden step by step.
And the more different times that you see this happen,
you can then see how the truth has become hidden.
So listen.
I get it.
You might want to justify
that you call yourself a Christian
because in your King James Bible,
it says Christian.
But listen.
Peter did not write Christian.
He did not speak Greek.
Paul even tried to make a problem about Peter
because Peter wouldn't sit with the Gentiles.
In Galatians 2, Paul writes,
Now, we don't actually have Peter's side of the story
to be able to understand each other's views.
But we do know that he withdrew
and separated from the Gentiles,
as Paul says.
To think that this man,
who walked with Yahushua
and denied him three times,
who cut off the ear
of a Roman soldier,
to think that he later rejected
the culture of his people
to attach to the culture of those
he deemed as sellouts
is ridiculous.
And because our teachers in Christianity
do not stand for the word in this way,
this is why this has never been brought to you
like this until now.
Just because the outsiders
call these people Christians,
if that's even the actual word that they used,
but even if they actually did,
that's not what the apostles called themselves.
They said they were of the way.
How come you're not a follower of the way?
And this is the actual faith that I'm protecting.
Christianity is not the way.
It's just masquerading as so.
And I hope that's clear.
In the next part,
I'm going to explain exactly what Christianity is.
What we must do is explain
what our Messiah prophesied
in regards to Christianity.
Did he prophesy that there would be a version
of his truth that would be planted in this world
that would look like it was his
until it grew in fullness?
Yeah, he absolutely did.
If you're going to understand the basis
of this discussion against Christianity,
this is the next part that you must learn
and understand.
So we will deal with that next.
Understand, Christianity is a religion
that on the surface seems biblical,
but when you dig deep into the doctrines,
you find it is not.
It is not a doctrine of service to our Father,
but a doctrine of abusing grace,
editing covenants,
rejecting the way our Father actually chose
to reach humanity,
and making it only be about the way
Christians want to receive him.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence
for our Father that he deserves.
And in the end,
it does not prepare those who follow it
to be ready for what our Father plans to do
in the last days.
If you desire to be ready for our Father
and his plan for us,
you must come out of this religion of tares
and come to our Father
in truth.
Please move to part three in this playlist
and understand what our Messiah prophesied
about this religion.
Click the link in the next video
and let's talk some more.
Be blessed.
Hallelujah.
Praise Yah.
Okay.
Thanks again for watching.
If this has blessed you,
please like this and share this video
with your family and your friends.
This video series is highly important
for those trying to be ready for our Father.
This is part two
of this series.
Please click the link
or just move on to the next video
in the playlist.
As always,
I want to thank all who donate
and contribute to this ministry.
This series would not be possible
without your support.
I thank you sincerely.
Be blessed.
Okay.
Thanks again everyone for watching.
See you in part three.
I love you all.