Okay, so you should be coming from part two of this series.
These videos are part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is being presented.
So please, if you have not watched part one, please stop this video and start back from video one.
Okay, so in part two, we dealt with the stumbling block about the word Christian being in the Bible.
We had to deal with that because how can I speak against being a Christian when that word is literally in the scriptures?
I hope that that video brought clarity on that because there are many different falsehoods attached when Rome took over and started their subtle and silent doctrine of syncretism.
Now, I haven't gone over the history of Christianity yet, so that teaching about syncretism has not been covered yet.
So if you still have questions about that word, I will be covering that next.
In dealing with this topic about Christianity, I need to explain my overall conclusion about Christianity.
I normally build up to my conclusions with information that leads up to it.
So it can be clearly understood why I say what I'm saying.
But in putting this series together, I think it's important that I go here now so that as I begin to explain the problems, this topic really can be understood piece by piece because this is the overall problem.
You see, our Messiah did prophesy about this religion of Christianity, and it's important that this is understood.
Now, of course, he didn't say Christianity, but if you understand what he said, you will understand what I'm speaking of.
So let me backtrack a bit.
I have repeatedly said that Christianity is the biggest religion in the world.
Let's review that.
I want to begin with some foundational numbers just to illustrate that there is a problem, even if people may not want to recognize it.
According to a chart done by Statista using data from sources of Pew Research Center, the CIA, the World Bank, this survey is from data from two years ago in 2022.
Of the approximate world population of about 8 billion people, 31% of the world are declared.
Christians and almost 26% are declared Muslims.
So of the 8 billion people in the world, approximately two and a half billion of them are declared Christians.
Christianity is the largest religious denomination in the world.
Now, if we dig a bit further in the numbers, according to this chart on Wikipedia.
Now, I don't claim that this is 100% accurate, being that it is Wikipedia, but I think it's close enough that I can use it.
Of that two and a half billion, it said that 50% are wrong.
Roman Catholic, 36% are Protestant, nine and a half percent Eastern Orthodox, and two and a half percent Oriental Orthodox.
Now, I won't focus on Roman Catholic at this time or the Eastern and Oriental Orthodox.
All those are different sides of the same coin.
I will probably cover that later.
What I want to deal with is the Protestant number.
900 million people in this world are declared Protestant Christians.
Almost 9% of the world population is declared.
To be a Protestant Christian, believing that they are not tied to the doctrine of the Roman Catholic Church.
That's a big number.
Over 31% declare Jesus Christ as their Lord and Savior.
I use the English name here because I believe that a large majority that use his real name, they're not even taking these surveys.
But let's not get distracted by that.
Over 31% of the world population declare Jesus Christ as their Lord and Savior, and 9% of the world population have split away from the Roman Church.
And declare that they are the true faith.
And then when you dig even further in the Protestant churches, the numbers get even more separated and divided because of the different denominations in the Protestant churches.
There's Lutherans, Anglicans, Methodists, Presbyterians, Seventh-day Adventists, Baptists, etc.
This is a lot of religion, a lot of beliefs and doctrines mixed into Christianity.
But I want you to look and understand the problem.
Because with all this declared belief in Jesus.
The world hasn't gotten more pure and righteous, but actually the complete opposite.
With these kind of numbers and the power that Messiah truly has, the way this world is today, it should not be possible.
And also think about it.
Why would belief in Jesus be the largest faith in the world if this world is being led to a satanic agenda to worship Satan?
And why would belief in Jesus be the largest faith in the world if Yahushua said that the world would hate him?
Shouldn't Christianity be the smallest faith?
Even if you subtract the Catholic numbers, there is something wrong here.
And if you're at least honest with yourself, you should be able to agree with that.
So what is truly going on?
As I have been alluding to, the fact and truth is that there has been editing of the overall truth in relation to our faith and the scriptures.
And most people following Christianity are not aware of it because they are following religion and following man in their application of their faith.
Our Messiah spoke and prophesied of this.
Here are some of the scariest verses in the Bible.
Here's one.
Not everyone who says to me, Adonai, Adonai, shall enter the kingdom of heaven, but he who does the will of my Father in heaven.
Many will say to me in that day, Adonai, Adonai, have we not prophesied in your name, cast out demons in your name, and done many wonders in your name?
And then I will declare to them, I never knew you.
Depart from me, you who practice lawlessness.
That's Matthew chapter 7, verses 2-3.
So I want you to think about what he prophesied.
He said, not everyone who says Adonai, meaning my master, or what people like to use Lord for today, even though the word Lord means Baal in Hebrew, but I'm not even going that deep.
He says not everyone who says Jesus is Lord will enter the kingdom of heaven.
So look, just because he said this.
That I came to know Jesus Christ for myself and embrace him as my Lord and Savior.
Or, he said this.
It does not mean that they will enter into our Father's kingdom.
When I use that example, it's probably easier to see, right?
I mean, Yahushua said many will say he is master, and say that they prophesied in his name.
They even cast out demons in his name, and done many wonders in his name.
But he will tell them to depart from him because he never knew them.
Those who practice lawlessness and do not do the will of our Father.
That's very deep, and it's very scary.
Yahushua also prophesied to enter by the narrow gate.
For wide is the gate, and broad is the way that leads to destruction, and there are many who go in by it.
Because narrow is the gate, and difficult is the way which leads to life, and there are few who find it.
That's Matthew chapter 7 verses 13 and 14.
So he also told us to enter by the narrow gate, but many will choose to go in the broad gate that leads to destruction.
Because narrow is difficult, that leads to life, and there are few who find it.
So there are some issues here clearly.
First, there are many that will call him master or lord, but he never actually knew them.
And there will be many that are trying to go to him, but they're trying to enter into a very broad gate that leads to destruction.
And the problem is that those practicing Christianity as a whole are greatly a part of this because they are practicing religion and not practicing the actual faith.
In the end, the problem is that those practicing religion and not practicing the actual faith.
And it will only be each of our individual faults if he rejects us.
Because while we were practicing religion, we never actually sought after him diligently enough with our hearts.
I mean, we say we love him, but there are other things more important to us that we put in front of him.
I mean, you know how many Christians know more about senseless gossip about celebrities like all the stuff about Diddy?
But if you ask them what the will of our father is, they don't know.
And this is the answer, by the way.
And you shall love Yahuwah, your Elohim, with all your heart.
With all your soul, with all your mind, with all your strength.
This is the first commandment, and the second is like it.
You shall love your neighbor as yourself.
There is no other commandment greater than these.
Mark chapter 12, verses 30 and 31.
But I really want you to look at what he prophesied and understand.
He said,
Because narrow is the gate and difficult is the way which leads to life, and there are few who find it.
And as I said, Christianity is the largest religion in the world.
So that kind of contradicts what he's actually saying.
His truth and those who accept it should actually be the smallest minority in the world.
If you actually believe what he's actually saying and you're actually applying his words and not man-made doctrine.
Just saying.
You see, this all can be very hard to hear, and it's possible that you want to reject what I'm saying.
And listen, again, I keep saying that is your choice.
But I think you may just want to hear me out a little bit more before you make your mind up.
And those who don't, I'm not saying that.
Those prophecies I spoke about, they are telling.
But that's not even the main case and the main problem I'm speaking about.
Let's go to the main prophecy that Yahushua spoke about, and you will understand what it is I'm referring to.
We'll go to this parable.
Another parable he put forth to them, saying,
The kingdom of heaven is like a man who sowed good seed in his field.
But while men slept, his enemy came and sowed tares among the wheat and went his way.
But when the grain had sprouted and produced good seed,
Then the tares also appeared.
So the servants of the owners came and said to him,
Sir, did you not sow good seed in your field?
How then does it have tares?
He said to them,
An enemy has done this.
The servants said to him,
Do you want us then to go and gather them up?
But he said,
No, lest while you gather up the tares, you also uproot the wheat with them.
Let both grow together until the harvest.
And at the time of harvest,
I will say to the reapers,
First, gather together the tares and bind them in bundles to burn them.
But gather the wheat into my barn.
As Matthew chapter 13, verses 24 through 30.
Let's keep going with it.
Then Yahushua sent the multitude away and went into the house.
And his disciples came to him, saying,
Explain to us the parable of the tares of the field.
He answered and said to them,
He who sows the good seed is the son of man.
The field is the world.
The good seeds are the sons of the kingdom.
But the tares are the sons of the wicked one.
The enemy who sowed them is the devil.
The harvest is the end of the age.
And the reapers are the angels.
Therefore, as the tares are gathered and burned in the fire,
so it will be at the end of this age.
The son of man will send out his angels,
and they will gather out of his kingdom all things that offend,
and those who practice lawlessness,
and will cast them into the furnace of fire.
There will be wailing and gnashing of teeth.
Then the righteous will shine forth as the sun in the kingdom of their father.
He who has ears to hear, let him hear.
That's Matthew chapter 13, verses 36 to 43.
This parable is truly remarkable, and it's important.
Understand, we are in the harvest right now.
To understand this parable, it's important that you understand what tares are.
You see, they are indistinguishable from wheat until the final fruit appears.
That's what a tare is.
We'll revisit that.
What he's explaining in this parable is that all those who are following his word
and living for our father and his will,
they are the sons and daughters of the kingdom.
That's the seed that he planted.
But the devil has planted the wicked in the same soil.
Remember, the soil is the world.
The devil is sowing his tares amongst us.
If you look at the world from a top view down,
we would be the wheat, and the wicked are the tares.
Someone asked him,
shouldn't we just pluck the tares out now?
But he said, when you do that, you can uproot the wheat too.
You see, farmers will be trying to pull out the tares,
but because they look like wheat, they would also pluck out the good wheat too.
You see, we're all growing together, the righteous and the counterfeit.
This isn't about those who are Satanists and working in the darkness.
The tares are counterfeit, who look and act like believers,
but in the end, when they grow, they don't produce righteous fruit.
With all these doctrines, all these false traditions,
all these believers who say they love him,
but side with the world more than they ever care about him.
They practice the traditions of men
before they ever turn to the word of Elohim for justification.
They deeply offend those who are just preaching righteousness
and living according to the word.
These are counterfeit.
They look like wheat as they are growing,
but in the end, they are not the same.
Understand, when the angels come to gather the righteous,
all those who offend and practice lawlessness
will be cast into the fire.
They'll be wailing,
and gnashing of teeth,
but the righteous will be good.
So, if you're going to understand the history of this world,
it's important to have a better perspective
at how you are learning about this world.
In the past, if you have been under Christian doctrines,
learning Christian history,
most people that tell the story of the church,
today, they tell it in a way of power.
They tell it in a way that shows what they feel is the power of Yahuwah.
Basically, by their logic,
because Christianity has been able to be spread all over the world
over such a long period of time,
it just shows the power of the church
and the power of the gospel.
That's the overall theme.
But if you are now to review this overall perspective
and understand that the people that have been telling you history,
the people that we have been told about in our history books,
these characters that have been given a lot of credibility
throughout our history,
and depending on who was telling the story,
they were either heroes or villains.
But overall, the story of how Christianity
has been built up in the world
is told in a way that gives people a lot of credibility.
So, if you are now to understand the story of Christianity,
people the point of view that it was put in place by the power of Yah in order to bring the world to
the truth of the gospel. And this is the reason why Christianity is the dominant religion in this
world. But if you change your way of viewing history and recognize that the history you're
actually being told in terms of biblical truth is all actually reversed, and you are only hearing
about the history of the satanic side, you are only hearing the side about the history of the
tares. The history that you know is one that comes from the side of the weeds, the counterfeit.
Then you realize that you have been lied to and fully indoctrinated in order to accept a
satanically led and controlled world. All the history that is noted in this world and recognized
in our history books is only told and it's only supported because it helps promote the satanic
agenda of satan being worshipped as the most high. This is where the world is leading to.
The doctrine of Christianity in
the history books is only told and it's only supported because it helps promote the satanic
this world has been told to us from a false perspective that we have been praising and
rooting for tares, rooting for the counterfeit. From the time that Rome made Christianity the
religion of Rome, there had been a weed that has been planted in the field by Satan. And over the
years, the weed kept being spread in the field, which is the world. It branched out, yes, and
there have been changes over the centuries, yes, but it is the same weed. When the Greek Orthodox
split from Rome, they felt that they are different, but they're not. It's the same weed.
When the Reformation happened and the Protestant church was built in Europe,
there was a different name and different doctrines. They feel that they're different,
but they're not. Their root was the same weed. When it gets to England, it's a different name,
different doctrines, yes, but it's still the same weed. When it gets to the Americas and then
the missionaries want to take their doctrines and spread it around the world, it's a different name,
the same weed. It's all counterfeit. It all comes from Rome, which is the root from the tares
that Satan has planted. And this is how history has been told to us. We just don't recognize it.
So as we hear the history of the world, we want to hear about it as the history of how the church
was spread. But it's actually the history of how satanic doctrine that will be used to make the
world believe Satan is the most high. It's how this doctrine was able to be spread and believed.
We are learning history from the wrong perspective. And because we are learning from
our enemies who have pledged allegiance to Satan, we are learning to love our enemy and reject our
heroes. We seek to be controlled. We seek to be under their influence. And so because we are
indoctrinated, we keep learning and learning. But it's never the truth. We keep attaching
ourselves to falsehoods, but never come to the truth. Because we have committed ourselves to a
system that intends to draw us into worship of Satan. We don't know we have done this,
but this is the world that we live in. This is the matrix.
And this video series has been made to wake you up out of it. But it has to be in depth. And that's
why I'm taking it slow and methodically. The main point that I'm making here is that Christianity
is a religion of tears. This is what Yahushua was prophesying about. Please know, I know that
I have not concretely proved it in this video. But it's important for me to lay down this
foundational understanding so that it can be understood. And as we go through this series,
all my points will be proving exactly this main conclusion.
What I need to do is go back to the parable of the weed of tears again, and explain it a little
more in depth. When Yahushua said the kingdom of heaven, it's like a man who sold good seed in
the field. He is talking about himself. Yahushua
planted good seed in the world, through his disciples, who carried on with his teachings,
showing the way, baptizing the nations, and spreading the good news to those who desire
to come to it. And today, all those who are following His word and living for YAH
and his will are the sons and daughters of God that will come at the funding and that are still
there in money's worth. He is the light on kind-heartedness in the nosaltres. all when God comes
he'll praise God for the good good of you, meltsה and means the good of young people and
is in the Light on a piece that will bring prosperity to all those who think they are
are the sons and daughters of the kingdom. The field, again, it's the world, and we are the sons
and daughters of the kingdom. Now, that is the good part that most everyone wants to understand
and be a part of. Yeah, I get it. But here's the issue. Satan is the enemy. And while Yahusha was
planting his good seed and waiting for it to grow, the enemy, the devil, came into the field,
which is the world, and planted his weeds right amongst Yahusha's good seed. He planted his weeds
in the same field as the righteous ones. Remember, the soil is the world. The devil has planted his
weeds amongst us, and it's very important to understand that. Let me explain the danger of
this scheme. Before the wheat and tares are fully grown and are ready for harvest, they look
identical to each other. You actually wouldn't know what was what. So the danger we face is that we
can be learning or trying to grow from weeds. Or we could even be weeds ourselves. You have to
understand this point about the tares.
Because it's crucial. They aren't discernible at first glance. They aren't easily seen and able
to be identified until they're fully grown. You don't know that they're actually weeds until they
are fully grown. That's why they're tares. And this is why the enemy keeps so many as babes in
their faith, only able to deal with milk, not solid food. Because he doesn't want people to
really recognize where they fit. So the longer people can try to be a part of the faith while
they lack in growth, they never actually come into the understanding that they are a weed,
and have been influenced by weeds. I mean, I know people that have been babes in Christ for almost
80 years. If you remember how I started this series, I gave a test. And if you use those
questions and ask people to answer to those questions, you will see when we go over each
of those questions, you'll see just how many people don't actually know the truth about this
faith. They're actually tares. They just don't know it. What our job is, is to witness to them
and minister to them and help them understand the truth.
If you were under these falsehoods and these false doctrines, this is why this video was being
made. It's not to judge you or to bring condemnation on you, but it's to wake you up so
that you can no longer be a weed and you could be full wheat. It's not judgment. I'm trying to
help you. So as this parable showed, later on, as the grain started to grow in the field,
the wheat started to grow. But all of a sudden, there are all these weeds growing up amongst the
wheat. And as we have grown in our relationship with him and are now his servants, as he
showed in the parable, we're asking him, wait, I don't understand. You're holy. You're righteous.
We know you sowed good seed in the world. What is going on with all these fakers? What is going on
with all these people that like to claim that they love you and follow you, but they don't
produce any good fruit? And Yahushua explains that this is all from the enemy. The enemy has
sown weeds amongst us. And we're asking him, you wanted to do something about all of them?
This is ridiculous. These people are out here praying in your name,
songs of praise in your name. They're saying they worship you, but it's so false. And others
are following their ways of wickedness. Do you want us to go disrupt all of it? And Yahushua says,
no, because he doesn't want us to make the mistake of pulling out some of the wheat while
we're coming at those tares. So he's allowing both the wheat and the tares to grow at the same
time. When it's time to reap the harvest, he will have them separated because at that time,
it will all be clear. The wheat and tares are all growing together, or maybe it's better said,
the righteous and the
counterfeit are all growing together. Now, for many, it's easy to make this in reference to an
evil Satanist and devil worshipers that are present all around us. But like I said earlier,
wanting to apply this characterization of weeds to the wicked, it's not accurate. This isn't
about those who are Satanists and those who are working in darkness. They don't look like us.
The tares are the counterfeit who look and act like believers. You must remember what a tare is.
This is why he said a tare. A tare is indistinguishable to wheat.
Until they are grown. In the end, the weeds do not produce righteous fruit.
If you do not look at this parable correctly, you can be deceived. I want you to understand this
about tares because in Christianity, we are taught to view the faith in just one way. We
are taught that there are believers and there are unbelievers. And our jobs are to bring the
souls to Messiah. So our focus is always on the unbelievers. And I'm not saying that that's a bad
thing. But what we fail to see is that while we're doing that, we also need to be on the lookout for
the weeds.
Here's the deal. Because we're so close to Yah's kingdom, the wheat and the tares, they're finally
grown. So it's easier to discern between the two. But the problem is the majority are too weak to
deal with the fact that there are tares and that they may be influenced by them. How much of your
doctrine comes from tares? How much condoning do you give the false ways of our faith that have
been taught and treated because you were led by tares? I mean, we can call it the easy ones for
now. For instance, the Roman Catholic Church who started conquering the world in the name of Jesus.
Do you understand how much doctrine we get from them that many of us condone because it has been
propped up for so long? Like I spoke about in part two when I mentioned Hellenization. In Christianity,
we have learned a culture of adaptation instead of holiness, which means being set apart. We were
taught tolerance instead of separation. We were taught about doctrines and traditions that come
from man that we think have to do with Yah, but they don't. Then we have the Church of England
doctrine that many take from and don't recognize where it's come from.
When we practice the ineffable name doctrine, for instance, that makes us say God and the Lord
instead of saying Yahuwah, his name, which he tells us not to take in vain. When you deal with
people that don't say his name but only say God, that's because most of them are following a man-made
tradition that was not actually taught to them. Then people, instead of recognizing that this is
doctrines of men, they justify it by saying, Yah has many names, and that's not true at all.
Satan has many names. Or in this American church, politics has gone into the churches
and people use the faith towards a social gospel that has nothing to do with Yah's kingdom and they
make it that our faith is about bringing about a better world. But it doesn't have anything to do
with Yah's word. This is why people who are voting for Donald Trump right now, they're following a
social gospel. All these different groups look similar, and as they are growing, they might have
been indistinguishable, because in the beginning they focused more on the things that were similar,
like our Messiah. But as the enemy's agenda starts to grow, the differences become more clear,
because the fruit that was being produced was the fruit that was being produced.
And right now, I'm just calling things out, and there's much more, particularly the hijacking of
the covenant, which when I get to, it completely rests my case. My point is that all of this is
what Christianity is. And unfortunately, what you will find with most people is that they dip in and
out of these falsehoods and say they understand that, but this doesn't apply with them. That's
not how they apply what Christianity is. There's a bunch of different rationalizations trying to
fit in a justification of Christianity.
People see the problems, but instead of dealing with the elephant in the room and understanding
that the problem is actually Christianity, they want to pick what parts of Christianity they want
to attach to and not. But what they don't recognize is that because Christianity hijacked
the covenant, when you learn the Bible from a perspective of a Christian, you don't ever
actually understand the Bible in the way it was truly written. You don't truly understand our
Father, the covenant, and you don't understand the promise. You don't
understand what our Father plans to do because the unspoken doctrine in Christianity is that the
church has replaced Israel and therefore the covenant is about Christians and not about
Israel. And I will get to all of that, but it was important that I let you understand the
conclusion. What is the conclusion? The conclusion is that Christianity is a religion of tares that
Satan planted in the same field Yahushua planted his good seed in. It may feel like it's biblical,
but when it is fully grown, the faith, it's completely seen to be opposite
the scriptures. It does not match the scriptures. People don't recognize this for many reasons.
The main reason is that people don't read the scriptures. But I have found like with this
brother I've been speaking to who has said he has read the scriptures many times over,
the problem is reading the scriptures from a Christian perspective and not a Hebrew mindset.
This is not a Christian Gentile faith. This is a Hebrew faith. And if you were there 2,000 years
ago learning from men like Peter or Paul or James, they would not have allowed you to understand
it from your Greek or your Roman pagan mindset. If you know you are Yashorel, you have no business
learning it as a Gentile. What I'm saying here is that the religion of Christianity is a religion
of tares. And when you move away from your defensive position about it, you will understand
completely what it is I'm saying. This foundation was important that it was laid, but it's important
that I prove it conclusively. I'm just laying the groundwork here. I personally believe I've given
enough evidence in this video, but I want to make sure that there is no room for doubt for those who
are trying to understand rather than those that just desire to defend. What needs to be done next
is go over the history because this is not understood enough. You see, people love speaking
about what their definition of Christianity is, and this is how they want to see Christianity
or believe what it was. But your definition of it does not matter. What matters is how you have
heard of the religion of Christianity in the first place. And the fact is,
this religion is not the largest religion in the world by accident. So we need to go over
the history and understand clearly how you even came to know to be a Christian. Do you honestly
think that Satan will let the belief in Messiah be the largest belief in the world? Honestly,
you think that Satan would let the true name of our savior be known by the world so the whole
world really calls on the name of our savior? You really think that that's what the case is?
You don't think that the enemy would be trying to stop that over this 2000 years of history?
Maybe you do believe that. I'll show you how false that way of thinking is though.
In regards to you personally, I'm not talking about how you came into the faith personally,
but how this religion of Christianity made it into your scope to be influenced by it in the
first place. There's a reason that you are a Protestant Christian if you're in North and
South America, and the Caribbean as well, as well as the colonized parts of Africa.
There's a reason why many are mostly Catholics in Europe. There's a reason why people are mostly
Muslims in the Middle East, in North Africa. It's about your influence and
how it got to you. I want you to understand Christianity and understand it's not by
accident that you're a Christian. You were indoctrinated to be so. America claimed to
be a Christian nation from its get-go, so all the churches here were Christian churches.
So we're going to take the time and go over the history. But before I do that, I'm going to go
back and review the tests that I gave you in part one and review the answers because now that I have
to understand that I am saying that the religion of Christianity is a religion of tares, after you
review the biblical answers to those questions and then review what it is others believe that have
taken the test, you will understand what it is I'm saying about this religion of Christianity.
So we will next go over the answers to the question of the testing Christianity test.
So listen, maybe you question me and you're still wondering, what is my goal here?
The answer is simple. My goal is for you to have an actual
biblical
faith and truly be wheat. I desire that I bring as many with me as I can to the gathering
so that you're with us when our father gathers Yashorel. And even if you're not with us,
when the truth about Christianity finally comes out in the open because there is a satanic plan
for Christians, I hope that this information counters the satanic Luciferian agenda
to bring the majority of you into the truth. I hope that you recognize that there was other
information there and you grab to that instead of following the beast.
That's my goal.
So in the next part, I'm going to review the answers to the test of Christianity so that we can truly review if the religion of Christianity is based upon biblical truth or the rationalizations of men.
It's important that you take time and understand what it is I'm saying.
If what I am saying is wrong, it should be easily proven.
You should easily be able to go to the word and prove it directly.
So let's do it.
If what I am saying is false, it should be very easily proven.
By the word.
So we're going to go over the answers and test it all.
In the meantime, please remember, Christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical.
But when you dig deep into the doctrines, it is not a doctrine of service to our father,
but a doctrine of abusing grace, editing covenants, rejecting the way our father actually chose to reach humanity,
and making it only be about the way Christians want to receive him.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our father.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our father that he deserves.
And in the end, it does not prepare those who follow it to be ready for what our father plans to do in the last days.
If you desire to be ready for our father and his plan for us,
you must come out of this religion of tares and come to our father in truth.
Please move to part four in this playlist.
And let's go over the answers to the questions of testing Christianity.
Click the link to the next video and let's talk about it some more.
Be blessed.
Hallelujah.
Praise Yah.
Okay.
Thanks again for watching.
If this has blessed you, please like this and share this video with your family and your friends.
This video series is highly important for those trying to be ready for our father.
This is part three of the series.
Click the link or just move on to the next video in the playlist.
As always, I want to thank all who donate and contribute to this ministry.
I thank you for your support and encouragement.
This series would not be possible without your support.
I sincerely thank you.
Be blessed.
Okay.
Thanks again, everyone for watching.
See you in part four.
I love you all.