Okay so you should be coming from part 3 of this series. These videos are a part of a topical
series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is
being presented. So please if you have not watched part 1 please stop this video and start back from
video 1. Okay so in part 3 we dealt with an important conclusion that needed to be brought
out. The conclusion was that Christianity is a religion of tares that Satan planted in the same
field Yahushua planted his good seed in. It may feel like it's biblical but when it is fully grown
the faith is completely seen to be opposite of the scriptures. It does not match the scriptures.
Now understandably there is some hesitation and resistance from a statement like this.
It can first feel like you're going against your own faith because the powers that be have made
it that people feel that Christianity is the original religion and original faith. This is
very far from the truth. In stepping away from Christianity you're
not going to be a Christian. You're not going to be a Christian. You're not going to be a
Christian. You're not going against the word. You're actually embracing and enforcing the word.
How many people call themselves Christians and dwell in wickedness? How many Christians
celebrate pagan holidays? How many tell you that the law is done away with? How many believe in
being part of this world? Today anybody can call themselves a Christian and people believe it.
I mean anyone can say it. Like whenever you're going through a sticky situation you know that
no matter what if your family's not there you've got the Lord. And I had no idea that
you guys were such um hardcore Christians. Yeah. Um do you and Kanye have bible studies
just by yourselves? We don't. I mean we'll send each other like different biblical verses and
he'll he'll he'll definitely come to church. He'll love it um when we're there. You know I
think we're more spiritual. I think we really believe in like the afterlife and heaven and
just really spiritual.
Yeah. And um my whole family is. And we just live our lives like that. We just try to be
good people and respect other people and be kind. Well that's a Christian. And that is yeah like
you know really we grew up really Christian. Yeah. And our spirit my whole life my favorite
bible verse because I am Christian uh is acts something. I mean look at Christianity today.
Kirk Franklin is the best example of Christianity today. This man he actually was wicked from the
get-go but because the veil of Christianity was still masking as we he was much more milder in
how he displayed himself to Christians. He brought in subtle changes in gospel music very subtly
over time. But now that we're in the last days and the tears have finally grown in full he has
come out to be an example of what Christianity is. It is a faith of do what thou wilt.
No one judges anyone in Christianity because the faith does not require being set apart
and is totally an attachment to this world. So Kirk can easily push away another Christian
and call out their hypocrisy because all dwelling in the religion of Christianity
are dwelling in a religion of tears. Kirk he's just exposing it. You see if Christianity was
true the body as a whole would tell that man to sit his butt down somewhere.
Anyways what I'm saying is that the religion of Christianity is a religion of tears.
It will not lead those who follow it to the destination that they believe they are going.
And listen I know it sounds like judgment and maybe it is hard to hear but it absolutely
needs to be understood. In the last video someone said I am a born-again believer in
Jesus Christ who puts his faith in him alone. I believe in the gospel found in 1 Corinthians 15.
I have been delivered from a dark lifestyle of drugs, sex, homelessness, etc.
Each day trying to mimic him and he is at the forefront of my mind all the time.
I am now married with two boys and a ministry leader at my church. All glory to God.
Am I a tear? I feel like this question it was a sincere one and it is a good example of what
I'm speaking of. First off to answer this question let me say that nothing that he said here would
allow any one of us to make a diagnosis of his faith. There are many Christians that are like
this. It really means nothing.
A long time ago over 10 years ago at least as I was growing in my faith another brother that I
knew was living a worldly lifestyle. He used to get drunk, smoke a lot of weed, did immoral things
and around his friends he was seen as the low man on the totem pole. At that time I was seeking
fellowship because I had left the church and when me and him started speaking about our faith
I got excited. I instantly started to try to help him out any way I could. We started a men's Bible
study together in my home and it started off good until things started getting dicey. When I was
speaking against the world and pagan holidays he kept saying that I was wrong and he couldn't
explain it but he needed an elder of his church to come and talk about it. Now at that time I was
nowhere near the understanding that I have now so a lot of it I would get angry and there was
conflict let's just say that. Anyways long story short we disconnected and had a complete falling
out. At the time I called him up and he said I'm going to go to church. I said I'm going to go to
a super churchy type of Christian. Now here's the thing in a very general sense judging off this
world's standards I have seen that in his life going to church was good for him. He was not the
same as he was before. He even later started a family and is in ministry at his church. You see
the pastor of the church embraced him gave him a job and let him grow inside the family of the
church and basically he was tied to that minister in the church completely. His life was very much
like what the church was like for him. He was a Christian. He was a Christian. He was a Christian.
His brother was saying in this testimony in this question. Now knowing this brother that I'm
speaking about from my past he absolutely is a tear. The change in his lifestyle and being in
the ministry in the church they're all good things in regards to this world but in serving
Yah this is not what matters. All that is a way that the world justifies and measures faith and
how they review faith. But this man he still puts up Christmas trees and is very much aligned to
mainstream church doctrine. I know this because he puts up Christmas trees and he puts up Christmas
trees and he puts it on social media. For all I know he could very well be the one who made that
comment because it's exactly the same testimony. My point is based on the criteria of what this
man said in the comment and asking if he was a tear we cannot make a determination because people
they do clean up their lives in the Christian church. There's no disputing that. The Christian
church it could stop you from a lot of things that he mentioned in his comment but that does
not allow us to know whether anyone is a wheat or tear. That's why the parable of the wheat and tears
is important because tears look identical to wheat until they are fully grown. So if these certain
habits one has is looking pretty righteous and holy it can make one feel like they're truly living for
our father. But what needs to be understood is that that is not a way anyone will be able to
discern or determine it. And maybe you're very much like this. You grew up in a church and you
know you're a different person than you were before. You believe you praise God and you live
for him. Now you hear that you could be a tear and now you're mad with me.
Saying things like how dare this man that doesn't even know me say such a thing. He doesn't even know
my heart. This man is just judgmental. I know Satan is saying this to many of you. Let me tell
you that I understand where you're coming from. But this is why I started this series off with a
test. Because there are many different ways to argue and debate about this. Being that this
subject is very deep and multi-layered. Not every Christian is the same. And that's because of
denominations and debates of separation within the religion. And that's why I started this series
off with a test. Because listen, you can agree or disagree. And we can go back and forth about it,
yeah. You can say I'm false all you want. But if there's no way for me to prove what I'm saying
or for you to prove that I'm false, we would just be going in circles. So we should go through the
test and review the best way to prove that I'm false. And that's why I started this series off
biblical answers. In part one of this series, I did not give the answers to that test immediately
because I was hoping that people would engage first and answer the questions. And praise
God, many people did. The questions from this test are a good place to start in determining
where you place in Christianity. You must test Christianity. Test all things. You must test
Christianity and understand the doctrines that were taught to you. I don't understand why that
would be so bad and harmful to do. So anyways,
we're going to do is go over the questions and answers on testing Christianity. And anyone can
review this and see where they stand. We'll review the test. Let's begin. Okay, so this is very
important. I honestly think that every Christian should take this test and review. There are many
people that want to come at me and speak against what I'm saying. And so be it. But here it is.
If I am false, and what I'm saying is false, all anyone needs to do is take this test and prove
what they are saying. Just prove it. And you can easily show that I'm false. As I said, I waited a
week to go through the answers because I like engaging in the comments. I don't run from my
comments. And I like understanding what people really believe. I've dealt with many people,
and it was proven that Christianity is not preparing those who follow it.
Most of the answers to the questions were pretty much the same thing. And in many cases,
people do backflips and hurdles to not actually apply what the scriptures actually say. I have
found that people make what they want to believe the basis and foundation of how they will apply
the scriptures, instead of letting the scriptures be the basis of what they believe. I will show you.
But first, let's review the questions. Question one. Who did our father, Yahuwah, the Most High,
make the new covenant with? Question two. What scripture gives the covenant for Christians?
Question three. What does our father plan to do in the last days before Messiah comes back,
and becomes king? Question four. What are you waiting for our father to do with Christians
during these last days? Question five. Are we trying to go to heaven or stay on earth?
These are very simple, basic questions. They are not hard theological questions,
not questions that should draw a great deal of debate, but they are fundamental to this faith.
Now, what I'm going to do first is show you some of the answers to these questions.
And let me say this first. I'm not posting the name of the person who answered these questions.
For those that did put their answers up, I appreciate you taking the test and putting
out your answers. This is not being used to judge you or embarrass you, which is why I'm not even
showing your name. This is just to help and illustrate the point. Your answers are a great
help in order to illustrate my overall point. And don't even worry if you are wrong. Most people
won't even take the test. So you being bold enough to take the test, you should be commended
for it. Again, I'm not against you. So let's get to it. Question one. Who did our father, Yahuwah,
the Most High, make the new covenant with? Let me read you a few of the answers.
One said, the new covenant Jesus gave to his 12 disciples. I don't even know what that means.
Another one. The new covenant is the promise that God makes with mankind that he will forgive sin
and restore communion with those whose heart believe in his son, Jesus Christ.
Jesus is the mediator of the new covenant and his death on the cross is the basis of the promise.
A lot of information, but not actually answering the question.
Another one.
He's basically saying that Yahuwah made the new covenant with everyone. And these are a few of
the answers. You know, people try to be deep or they're just way too simple. Some people,
they just don't have a clue. This is the first important understanding of this faith because
so many people say that they don't practice replacement theology and that that's not
their doctrine. But this question right here proves the belief of many. It proves that people
practice replacement theology, even if they don't actually recognize that they do.
If a person gets this question wrong, I already know that they are not in the truth and I know
what will follow after it with the rest of the questions. Please remember what I have said in
all these videos. Christianity rejects the way our father actually chose to reach humanity and
they make it only be about the way Christians want to receive him. And you will see that that
is exactly what people are doing when they're answering this question. You see, the answer
to this question is very simple and direct. If you're being biblical and you can always know
who's applying religion or the Bible to their beliefs, because the answer, again, it's very
simple. So what is the answer to this question? Who did our father, Yahuwah, the Most High,
make the new covenant with? Here. Our father, Yahuwah, the Most High, made a covenant with
the house of Yashareel and Yehudah, Israel and Judah, so there's no confusion. That's the answer,
very clearly given in scripture. I'll read it. Behold, the days are coming, says Yahuwah,
when I will make a new covenant with the house,
of Yashareel, and with the house of Yehudah, not according to the covenant that I made with
their fathers in the day that I took them by the hand to lead them out of the land of Egypt,
my covenant which they broke, though I was a husband to them, says Yahuwah. But this is the
covenant that I will make with the house of Yashareel after those days, says Yahuwah. I will
put my law in their minds and write it on their hearts, and I will be their Elohim, and they
shall be my people. No more shall every man teach his neighbor, and every man teach his neighbor,
and his brother, saying, Know Yahuwah, for they all shall know me, from the least of them to the
greatest of them, says Yahuwah, for I will forgive their iniquity, and their sin I will remember
no more. That's Jeremiah chapter 31 verses 31 through 34. And do you know what? This is actually
repeated and quoted in the book of Hebrews chapter 8 verses 8 through 11. This is who Yahuwah the
Most High made the new covenant with, Yashareel and Yehudah. And if we just let the scriptures
speak for themselves, then it becomes very easy. But because Christianity does not actually like
that answer, they go all around to make it fit with how they want to see it. This answer,
it does not reject salvation to the Gentiles. It's just the truth of the scriptures. But because
Christianity needs it to be all about Christians, they don't answer this first question accurately.
I mean, look how simple and clear the scriptures answer that question. There should not be one
person that does not answer this question correctly.
If they're actually applying the scriptures. And that's why this question is number one.
If you ask others this question, and they go all the way around this answer,
it's because they don't truly accept the covenant our father made, and they need to make their own
doctrines in order that they accept it. So listen, the new covenant was made with the house of
Yashareel and the house of Yehudah. As the scripture clearly states, you cannot make the
scriptures mean what you would like them to say. If you're going to be a part of this faith,
you have to take them based on how Yah
has given it. Now, does he provide a way for Gentiles to be partakers of this covenant and be
grafted in? Absolutely yes, because Messiah was prophesied to be a light to the Gentiles. But we
cannot just make our own doctrine and ignore what Yah did. When we do this, this is exactly how we
do not live aligned to his word and how we make another religion, which is exactly what Christianity
is. And you will find that this is what Christians do. They just make up their own doctrine to suit
how they want to believe.
Let's go to the next question. Question number two. What scripture gives the covenant for
Christians? After all the running around, I found that this was really when the answers got
interesting. One person answered, actually, Jeremiah chapter 31 verses 31 through 34. Yeah,
that same scripture I just used to explain who the new covenant was actually made with,
and it said nothing about Christians in that scripture. Nothing. Next person said,
everyone falls into that new covenant that Jesus gave to his disciples.
But again, that's not what I asked. Another one said, many scriptures, Luke 22 verses 19 through 20
and Matthew chapter 26 verses 26 through 29 are two places. Now, if you read those scriptures,
it says nothing about a covenant being made with Christians, but okay. Another one said,
for Christians, Jeremiah 31, Romans 9, Romans 11, Christians being Jews and Gentiles,
going all the way around making doctrine. And another one said,
there's no scripture that states a covenant to Christians. Jesus was the new covenant,
and he gave word to the Jewish people. Saul, who became Paul, who was Jewish, was raised up
to give it to the Gentiles. This topic is covered in Galatians chapter 3 verses 28 through 29.
And you see this last one right here, this person, he started off right,
but then he had to add more to it in order to put Christianity into it.
So what do we find here from these questions? You see, some people do know the scripture about
the new covenant from Jeremiah 31.
But instead of applying it correctly, what it actually says, they want to use it and make
their own doctrines. They said it applies to Christians and says nothing about Christians
in that prophecy. And then these other comments use all these other scriptures and not anywhere
in those scriptures do you find the answer to the question of, yeah, I'm making a covenant
with Christians, not anywhere. You see, the actual answer to this question is, again,
a very simple one. The answer is, there is no covenant,
made with Christians. It's really just as simple as that. There is not one scripture that makes
a covenant with Christians. You will not find this anywhere. And if the person is actually
treating the word with respect, the answer to this question should be simple. There is no
covenant. So if somebody is making doctrines and going all around the place, when it's clearly
not in the Bible that there's a covenant with Christians, people are making up their own
doctrines and their own belief. The truth is that Christianity is the faith of Gentiles,
hijacking the faith of Yahshu'el. And because they believe the faith is all about them,
them being Christians, they answer these questions with a false Christian mindset
that takes them out of the truth. Gentile believers in Yahushua can be grafted into
Yahshu'el as a wild branch. This is the way that they come to be received by Yah.
They are received by taking part of the blessing that was prophesied to come
through Abraham's seed. There's no taking away from that if you live in the truth.
But the covenant,
the way Yah put this together, it all is through Yahshu'el and Yahudah, the new covenant. This is
what he said. You just have to take his word. You can't apply how you want to look at it.
You know, another point to this, people keep using the scripture from Paul and they use it
incorrectly to make some false doctrine and add their replacement theology in. As one of the
people said, this topic is covered in Galatians chapter three, verses 28 through 29. That verse
reads,
You see, when people use this, they are applying it from a Christian perspective
that applies replacement theology. It is important to understand that when Paul is
referring to Greeks, he is not referring to all Greeks. He is not referring to the same people
that came and tried to conquer the Yahudim and killed many of their people. He is not speaking
about the same Greeks that worshiped Zeus and performed their wickedness, orgies, and sorceries.
Absolutely not. He is referring to the Yahudim whom assimilated into the Greek culture
voluntarily. This was during the Maccabean Wars. The history of the Maccabean Wars is important to
have if you're going to understand who Paul is speaking to when you see him speak to Greeks.
I've explained this in other videos. People use the scripture in Galatians
very falsely. There's a reason why he did not say Roman or Persian or a person from any other
that existed during that time. There is a definite misunderstanding when it comes to the
scripture. Be careful how you use it. It does not allow replacement theology. Anyways, let's keep
going. Question number three. What does our father plan to do in the last days before the Messiah
comes back and becomes king? You see, the answers from this really explain the Christian mindset
because people only can think about the book of Revelation. That's really all that they know.
Here are some of the answers. One person said, call out some of the world to follow his son
in spirit and truth. Another, the father will destroy everything and everybody that is not like
him. Another, there will be judgment. Another, put down the nations which invade Israel and bring
in the new millennium for a thousand years. That's close, but still. Last one.
Last day plans. Let the great tribulation go on for a while along with all that comes with that.
Apostasy. Appearing of the lawless one. He will also send the two witnesses. Heavenly signs too.
There will be bold judgments. Matthew 24, 1st and 2nd Thessalonians, Revelation.
Judgment. Listen, if you really go back, you'll notice that all these answers are all pretty
similar since question one. None of these people are connected to each other, but the doctrines
that you will see is that people believe in God. They believe in God. They believe in God. They
pretty much the same things because of their attachment to Christianity. Again, Christianity
does not prepare those who follow it to be ready for the truth of what our father plans to do. All
these Christians are waiting for judgment. And unfortunately, they are not aware that if they
do not change their beliefs, that judgment that they are expecting is coming straight for them too.
They only see judgment because Christianity leaves out the true promises our father has for us.
The Christian mindset does not live for the promises. They don't even teach it.
But for those of us living in the truth, we are not living in an expectation of judgment,
but we're living in an expectation of fulfillment of promises.
Our hearts should be set around the promises. The answer to question number three is,
what our father plans to do in the last days is gather Yashareel and Yehudah from the four
corners of the earth where he scattered them. Before he brings them in the land, he will bring
them into the wilderness where he will deal with them face to face and purge out the rebels.
This is called the judgment of God.
This is what happens before Messiah comes, and it's found in many scriptures. But Jeremiah
chapter 23 verses 3 through 8 is a good place to start, or Isaiah chapter 43 verses 1 through 6.
But again, there are many scriptures of the same prophecy all throughout the Old Testament
prophets. I've covered this in many videos. But if you notice, none of these answers speak of this.
Why do you think that is? You see, believing it's only about judgment is because Christianity
is preparing you for judgment.
These answers highlight the problem with Christianity. Christians are not prepared
for what our father has truly prophesied he would do. They don't even know to expect it.
And if you even bring it up to them, they may get confused. And if they're very prideful,
they'll try to find a way and justify that this has already happened and we shouldn't be waiting
for this. They just go all over the place to justify their own pride because they don't
actually know what it is that they're talking about. And that brings me to the next question.
Question number four.
What are you waiting for our father to do with Christians during these last days?
The answers here illustrate the problem of Christianity even more. One says,
Rapture, as in the book of Thessalonians. Another, expectation, Christians will be kept
preserved as they are sealed. Revelation chapter 7 through 9. Next one, repent and believe the
true Messiah. Another, give the Christians a spirit of repentance and obedience to his word.
Another, for Christians slash believers,
there will be judgment in the house of God. Chastisement and cleansing. Most are experiencing
this now. Then the rapture. Then judgment in full swing will move on the world. Second rapture for
the 144,000. Then wrath of God for the wicked and unrepentant. This guy in the comments was
extra prideful and he's just really just making things up, but whatever. For Christians, it's
either the rapture or revival. And listen, the revival part is not a bad thing because this is
exactly what Yah is doing with the dry land. It's not a bad thing. It's not a bad thing. It's not a bad thing.
But because they don't recognize Yashareel and the covenant Yahuwah has with them,
they don't even see that this revival is happening right now. It is happening right now. The others,
they're expecting this false rapture because again, without saying they believe in replacement
theology, that the church replaces Israel, they hypocritically believe that they are going to be
taken off the earth so that they don't have to go through the problems that the world is going to
go through. But Yashareel, they will. This is because these Christians believe that we're still
waiting for a Jacob. We're still waiting for a Jacob. We're still waiting for a Jacob. We're still
not realizing that Jacob has already been in trouble. Jacob is soon to be saved out of the
trouble. That's what those scriptures of Jacob's trouble prophesize. Christians, they live in such
a false mindset because it is a completely different religion. Here is the biblical answer.
The answer should be that you are waiting to be a part of the gathering that Yashorel will be in.
This is what you all should be waiting for. But because Christianity does not prepare those
in it for these promises, Christians, they are completely unaware. For those in the truth,
you should be waiting for Yashorel and Yauda to be gathered. And for you, if you are a wild
branch grafted into Yashorel, you come with us. Those who are not ready for this, they are the
ones that are going to be tested. And this is the whole point of these videos. It is about preparing
the true body of believers to be ready for the promises and not blinded by religion. Christianity
is not preparing those who follow this religion. If you really think about how nobody in the
religion is preparing for the gathering, in matter of fact, they don't even know about
it. If you really think about how nobody in the Christian religion is preparing for the gathering,
it, that should tell you all you need to know about the truth of Christianity. Why don't any
of these Christians have any expectation of true Bible prophecy and what they truly should be
waiting for? Do you think that's because of Yah or because of Satan? So, let's go to the last
question. Question number five. Are we trying to go to heaven or stay on earth? Let's look at some
of the answers. One says, it depends if you're a part of the first resurrection or the second,
Revelation 21 and 22. These chapters describe a new heaven and a new earth. This vision of the
future suggests a final destination for the righteous. Okay. Another one says, heaven.
Another one, we are trying to go with him no matter where he is. The Lord said, where I am,
there ye may be also. So, they're not even answering the question. Last one says, we will
spend eternity as described in Revelation, New Jerusalem. Okay. So, this is the last example and
these are the last two. So, let's look at the last two. So, let's look at the last two. So,
these answers are a clear illustration of the falsehood of Christianity. I keep repeating it.
They are not being prepared biblically for what our Father has promised. Their expectations are
completely unbiblical, like believing in the rapture. But then, in regards to where they
are trying to be in the end, they completely skip over a great deal of Bible prophecy and go to after
the millennial reign and after Judgment Day and they skip to the new heaven, new earth, and new
Jerusalem. Others, they just believe that they're supposed to just go to heaven. It's a completely
different faith than what we're used to. So, let's look at the last two. So, let's look at the
Here is the biblical answer. Our promise is to reign with Messiah on earth. I plan to celebrate
with Messiah as prophesied in Zechariah chapter 14. Messiah will reign as king on earth and those
who follow him and believe in him will be under his rule in our land. He will reign in justice
over Yashorel and Yehudah who will be restored as one kingdom again as Ezekiel 37 prophesies.
This is the prophecy of the rest of the world. So, let's look at the last two. So, let's look at the
restoration of Yashorel. After this rule for a thousand years, then Judgment Day comes and then
we have a new heaven and a new earth. Again, you see Christianity ignores the true reign of Messiah
on earth. You know why? Because it's preparing the masses for the beast. The Christian church is
not seeking to be with Messiah and his rule on earth. They're trying to go to heaven. They're
not seeking his kingdom. His kingdom comes down on earth. This is what it has always been prophesied
a kingdom on earth. They don't even know truly what is prophesied to come. And that is
Christianity. So, let me summarize this for you. What we're going to do is we're going to go through
these questions one more time. On one side, I'm going to go over what Christians may say. And then
on the other side, I will go over the biblical answers so you can compare. First one, who did
our father Yahweh the Most High make the new covenant with? Christians, they will say many
different things. It's all about trying to say that the new covenant is the new covenant. So,
the new covenant was made with Christians, though most will not actually use those words.
Regardless of what they say, you will notice that Christians will not answer the question
biblically accurate. The biblically accurate answer, according to scripture, is the new
covenant was made with Yahshu'el and Yehudah, Israel and Judah, according to Jeremiah chapter
31 verses 31 through 34 or Hebrews chapter 8 verses 8 through 11. Clear. Next question. Question
number three. What scripture gives the covenant for Christians? Christians, they will say many
things. They will use Jeremiah chapter 31 that does not even mention Christians. They will also
use other scriptures that don't even speak about a covenant with Christians. They will use
replacement theology, applying things like Galatians chapter 3 verses 28 and 29. They will
say many things, but avoid the most simplest but truthful answer. The biblical answer is there is
no covenant for Christians. Question number three.
What does our father plan to do in the last days before the Messiah comes back and becomes king?
For Christians, most are only going to speak about judgment and not about promises. They only see
judgment from the book of Revelation. They don't talk about the promises that we should be waiting
for. They only see judgment. But in regards to the biblical answers, what our father plans to do
in the last days is to gather Yahshu'el and Yehudah from the four corners of the earth where
he scattered them. Before he brings them in the land, he will bring them into the world.
He will bring them into the wilderness where he will deal with them face to face and purge out the
rebels. This is called the second exodus. This is what happens before Messiah comes. Found in many
scriptures, but Jeremiah chapter 23 verses 3 through 8 is a good place to start or Isaiah
chapter 43 verses 1 through 6 among many others. Question number four. What are you waiting for
our father to do with Christians during these last days? For Christians, they will speak either
about the rapture or a revival. They believe that they are still waiting for the Lord to come.
The biblical answer is waiting for Yahshu'el and Yehudah to be gathered back to Yah and for any
Gentile grafted in as a wild branch into Yahshu'el to be ready as well and come with us. Those not
ready will be tested. Simple. Question number five. Are we trying to go to heaven or stay on
earth? For Christians, most of them believe that they're trying to go to heaven or they're waiting
for the new heaven and the new earth. The biblical answer is our promise is to reign
with Messiah on earth. Messiah will reign as king on earth and those who follow him and believe in
him will be under his rule in our land. He will reign in justice over Yahshu'el and Yehudah who
will be restored as one kingdom again as Ezekiel 37 prophesies. This is the prophecy of the
restoration of Yahshu'el. After this rule for a thousand years, then judgment day comes and then
we have a new heaven and a new earth. You cannot get to the new heaven and the new earth without
standing on earth for a thousand years. So anyone ignoring this is just ignoring Yah's kingdom and
his plan. But all these are the answers. What I have done to make this very simple for you is I
have now made a copy of the questions and I've made a copy of what you can expect Christians to
answer and then I made a copy of the biblical answers. Take all three. I encourage you to test
every Christian that you know and see how accurate this all is. Test it. See how many people actually
believe in God. See how many people actually believe in God. See how many people actually believe in God.
And that is if they're even humble enough to answer the questions and not get defensive,
which I'm sure you will get as well because exposing the falseness of their belief
drives people to defense instead of humility and repentance. But this is it. This is the
answer to the questions. And listen, there are a lot of people that have come against me
and make this all about me and say that I'm false or speaking through pride.
Listen, anyone that wants to try to say this, I'm not running from you. I'm giving you a very clear
to prove whatever you're trying to say about me. Answer these questions. And if you disagree,
please do so directly with the word and not the twisting and the bending of scripture that
many people have done. Answer these questions. I've listed them in the description box as well.
Every question I have asked can be answered directly with scripture and not by mixing
concepts to make doctrine. Everything YAH desires us to know, he has spelled it out clearly in his
word. If you find that you have to borrow from here and borrow from there and make this together,
then bring that together. That's not actual doctrine. That's man playing with words in order
to put forth their own way of thinking. That's false doctrine. And it's exactly how the Christian
church got involved in all these false things. Everything that is false in Christianity is from
people playing with the word in that way. By answering these questions and going through
these questions with other Christians, especially other pastors, if you can ask them, you can test
Christianity and see if it truly is biblical or if it's religious. You don't have to just depend on
my word.
Here's a test. You will find that it is not an accident or coincidence that so many Christians
believe the same thing even though they are in different denominations and they're not a part
of the same churches. It's because this is the foundation of Christianity and this is why these
questions were asked. You will find that if you are believing in these things, you are being taught
by tares. You know, throughout all these people that have answered these questions, I found only
one person with true humility because as we were speaking about Christianity, I found only one
person with true humility. And that's because he knew that the problem was not only his own
acon. He knew that he was doing the right thing by doing it, but by doing it the right way.
He knew that he was called to do the right thing.
But he did not get defensive. He started realizing, maybe it's possible that he could be missing
something. This is what he said. I'm going to read it.
Truth Unedited
Wow. If what you're saying is true, then I am not ready. I will investigate for myself.
It's channels like this that helped me step away from that pre-trib nonsense, but I realize there
is some leaven in my beliefs, although I no longer expect to fly away before the great tribulation.
I thought I'll be watching from a distance as natural Israel goes through the great tribulation,
as I was taught.
it's the time of Jacob's trouble, so I thought this is exclusively the natural branch. I guess
I also have to look into the ones you call fake who are in Israel right now. And I have been going
there for some decades and really get serious about what is going on. All we get in the church
are motivational speeches. When I tried to share the gospel of Matthew verse by verse, exploring
it in context, and actually looking at the prophecies, I was stopped before I could even
get to the beginning of Messiah's ministry, as I was told we need to focus on the needs of the
people, i.e. give prayer points and give encouragement. I was beginning to learn a lot,
but that was halted. Thanks to channels like this, I have also changed my diet and stopped
celebrating those man-made festivals. And this is actually the first year I've learned about and
tried observing the appointed times. I want to get this right so that one day when I have family,
I can leave them in truth. And hallelujah, that is an answer and comment of humility.
He was going back and forth with me in real discussion. It was not conflict. He was trying
to unlock hisЫ
understand this in peace and not being defensive. He didn't automatically believe what I said but
he said he needs to look further and if this is true he realizes that he's not ready and that is
true. But now that he knows he can now get ready and his humility will serve him well. You see this
is not about pride. I want all both natural and wild branches to be ready and being attached to
the false doctrines of Christianity will leave the majority unprepared and that's why this series
is so important. I am challenging your faith yes because it needs to be challenged and listen if
it stands to the test then it's true but if your faith cannot be challenged and all you can do is
get defensive whether you agree with me or not it doesn't matter. Your faith is not strong and it's
not built in truth. I want to change that. So listen now that we have dealt with the answers
to the questions in testing Christianity it's time to now go deeper into Christianity and start
understanding the history of Christianity.
So you can understand how you came to into even being called a Christian because again it's not
by accident and it's not without influence. So in the next part I'm going to start by educating you
on the history of Christianity so that some misconceptions and just lack of knowledge can
be done away with. You see the more you know the less susceptible you are to lies and propaganda.
In the meantime please remember Christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical
but when you dig deep into the
doctrines it is not a doctrine of service to our father but a doctrine of abusing grace editing
covenants rejecting the way our father actually chose to reach humanity and making it only be
about the way Christians want to receive him. It lacks the love and reverence for our father that
he deserves and in the end it does not prepare those who follow it to be ready for what our
plans to do in the last days. If you desire to be ready for our father and his plan for us
you must come out of this religion of
tears and come to our father in truth. Please move to part five in this playlist and understand
the history of Christianity and how Christianity has come to be accepted by you. Click the link
to the next video and let's talk some more. Be blessed. Hallelujah. Praise Yah. Okay thanks again
for watching. If this has blessed you please like this and share this video with your family and
your friends. This video series is highly important for those trying to be ready for our father.
It's part four of the series. Click this link or just move on to the next video in the playlist.
As always I want to thank all who donate and contribute to this ministry.
This series would not be possible without your support. I thank you sincerely. Be blessed.
Okay thanks again everyone for watching. See you in part five. I love you all.