Okay, so you should be coming from part four of this series.
These videos are a part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is being presented.
So please, if you have not watched this series from part one, please stop this video and start back from the first video.
Okay, so in part four, we went over the test to review the doctrines that those who follow mainstream Christianity believe versus actual biblical doctrine and expectations.
In the first part of this series, I said this.
I'm going to give you simple questions, about five simple questions, and all you need to do is get the answer to them.
And at the end, if you review the answers to these questions and see how biblically wrong they are, then you will have to admit that there is a problem with Christianity.
Is that fair? I hope so.
So here are the questions.
Okay, and so in part four, we went over the questions.
In Praise YAH, I saw that there were many that understood what was being presented.
And they recognized that there was a problem, but there were still many that were not willing to understand yet.
And listen, I get it.
This is the big deal.
Going against religion that you've been born into and that everyone else believes is the actual truth is hard to go against.
And being that that is the case, there needs to be much more understanding given.
I get it.
I'm not just asking you to believe me blindly.
I'm going to go through this thoroughly.
And so that is what we're going to do.
But before we get into it, I need to explain something important.
Okay.
It needs to be understood why I am doing this and why this is so important that I'm bringing this up.
In case you are not aware, World War Three is approaching.
They are gearing up for it.
All the pieces are moving into place.
I don't know how much time we have before things begin to change.
There is no shortage of videos that are speaking about this, talking about war and all that's coming.
In this ministry, I could very easily transition to those type of videos and pump fear in as well because things are really heating up.
But the thing is that all these Christian truthers, while they know war is coming and they're talking about this and they're talking about that, the majority seem to be oblivious to the agenda against Christians.
And being that I know that there is an agenda coming that leads Christians to the doctrines of Lucifer, I want to make sure that I counteract that agenda now while there's still time left.
And so before I go into the history, I want to very quickly review what it is I'm speaking about.
I've spoken about this in many videos, but I want to make sure I place this in this series.
In 1871, 33rd Degree Freemason Occultist Grand Master Albert Pike wrote a letter to Giuseppe Mazzini, known as the Pike Letter to Giuseppe Mazzini.
It was on display in the British Museum Library in London until 1977.
The British Museum Library denies the letter exists.
This does not matter.
What matters is what is said in these letters.
The letters go over a plan using three world wars in order to bring the world into the light of Lucifer.
Now, there are many that want to deny that this letter is true because he speaks of the Nazis before they existed.
But I always caution everyone that feels this way because many don't recognize that all these things are planned way in advance.
Albert Pike, the man who wrote Morals and Dogma and explained that Lucifer is the god of Freemasonry, whose light they are bearing.
He went into detail about the three world wars before they ever happened.
These are excerpts from the letter.
I have this letter posted on my website so you can read it on your own.
What's important?
Is what is said about the third world war.
These are excerpts.
It says the third world war must be fomented by taking advantage of the differences caused by the agent or of the Illuminati between the political Zionists and the leaders of Islamic world.
The war must be conducted in such a way that Islam, the Muslim Arabic world and political Zionism, the state of Israel, mutually destroy each other.
Meanwhile, the other nations, once more divided on this issue, will be constrained to fight to the point.
of complete physical, moral, spiritual and economical exhaustion.
We shall unleash the nihilist and the atheist, and we shall provoke a formidable social cataclysm, which in all its horror will show clearly to the nations the effect of absolute atheism, origin of savagery and of the most bloody turmoil.
Then everywhere, the citizens obliged to defend themselves against the world minority of revolutionaries will exterminate those destroyers of civilization and the multitude disillusioned.
Any nation that will lose out to this pledge of Christianity will simply have to abandon itself and
try to throw away with a
вors지도.
Now, again, you can debate amongst.
yourselves if you believe this letter to be valid or not. I do believe it's valid, and I believe
their plan. And as I see the events unfolding, I believe that this is all a part of it. This is
what you're seeing in real time today. They are taking advantage of the differences caused by the
agentur of the Illuminati between the political Zionists and the leaders of the Islamic world.
Agentur means agency. So this secret society group has a rift, and they're taking advantage of it.
The war is to put the Muslim Arabic world and the state of Israel against each other so that
they mutually destroy each other. This is the chaos that they plan to start. And through this
chaos, the other nations of the world will be driven to desperation with no strong guidance
or leadership until the Luciferian doctrine comes into full light. What we are seeing right now with
Israel is literally them carrying out their plan that they have made public for all to see.
Whether you believe the letter is real or not, this is a plan,
right as they said it would. And it's what happens after they start the war that should
concern Christians. As Pike explained, these conflicts will bring the world into division.
And with them being completely divided on this issue, the people will be constrained to fight
to the point of complete physical, moral, spiritual, and economical exhaustion. They're
going to beat everyone down physically, morally, spiritually, and economically. I mean, you already
see this now. The world is divided on who they will support in all of this.
Mainstream Christians are all in support of Israel and what they're doing. But the real thing is
about the plan that they have for Christians. The plan for those that have been following
mainstream Christianity, they plan to bring the world to the brink of destruction and what people
think that they are preparing for will not work out for them. Like waiting for the rapture. It's
not going to work out for you. And just like many people fail the test during COVID, what is coming
will be much, much worse. And here's the plan. They're going to be tested. That's the plan.
Then they say everywhere, the citizens obliged to defend themselves against the world minority
of revolutionaries will exterminate those destroyers of civilization and the multitude
disillusioned with Christianity, whose deistic spirits will from that moment be without compass
or direction, anxious for an ideal, but without knowing where to render its adoration,
will receive the true light through the universal manifestation of the pure doctrine of Lucifer
brought finally out in the public view. What he's saying,
is that basically those who were following Christianity are not going to have a clue
of what to do, and they will need direction and understanding. And just like they had a plan to
guide us through COVID, you better believe they have a strong plan to guide the many lost in
Christianity to the beast and the satanic goals. Now, let me ask you, why do you think they believe
people are disillusioned in Christianity? You see, pride will tell people that it's because they are
evil and they just don't believe, but it's much deeper than that. It's why this series was made.
You see, they know these Christians are delusional, but they don't believe in Christianity.
They're disillusioned because these masons are the ones who are creating this Christian doctrine
and telling Christians what to focus on and what not to focus on. Remember, just in the last video,
I shared that there is a big difference between what Christianity is waiting for
and what biblically we should be waiting for. The difference comes from using all the scriptures.
Those in Christianity ignore the prophets and the art that we're preparing for they have no clue
about, and actually, many hypocritically have been attacking me saying I'm idolizing Israel
and teaching another gospel, all because they're preparing for it. So, I'm going to tell you a
story that I want you to see. If you know a Christian who's a Christian, you should understand
that they're a Christian and their pride does not allow them to see that they have ignored much of
what our Father has proclaimed. And so, not all will be led into the doctrines of Lucifer, but all
will be tested. And it is this test that I'm desperately trying to keep you out from taking,
because much of what comes with that test is major persecution because Satan won't have access to
those of us who are in the ark. When I speak of the ark, I'm talking about the gathering. And so,
I am making these videos and dealing with these subjects so that it helps prepare you for what
Christianity is not preparing you for.
easiest thing is that people are literally treating me like I'm the enemy because I'm trying
to expose them to the lies they have been told and showing them the scriptures that they aren't
reading. The main reason I'm making these videos is to prepare you for the end time agendas that
are coming. You know one thing that we all do that can often be a mistake is just assume that
something that we feel is short on is actually accurate and true. Like there are many people
that are aware of the end times and they are aware of the conspiracies and all of that and
they think they will be ready for what is coming but what is not understood is they have not checked
everything. They have not tested their actual faith and made sure that they know exactly what
they actually believe in and know that it's actually biblically accurate. What they know is
that they know religion but they haven't actually tested it. They know religion more than they
actually know our father and what he has actually planned and desires for us and so while they think
that they know what they're doing they don't know that there is a major deception coming and they
will not be ready for it.
For instance with that test from video four if you are actually being real with yourself how many of
those questions did you get wrong? How much have you actually even considered the gathering that
our father has prophesied many times over that he's going to do? How come most Christians don't
speak about it at all? Isn't that odd that the majority don't speak about it? Yeah because
Christianity is not preparing those who follow it for our father and they will be led to the beast
very soon. When I go back and look at how fast things change and how fast things change and how
quickly they transitioned everyone from fear into compliance I am reminded that that was just a
test run for the real agenda that they have been planning for centuries. When things change people
will be herded and if you have not been at least introduced to the truth whether you believed it or
not at the time that you heard it when they come with that agenda if you have not been introduced
to the truth it is highly likely that you're going to be following them to the beast. They have a
plan for you. Everything has to be done. You have to be ready for it. You have to be ready for it. You
have to be ready for what's happening right now is a part of it. The reason why this series is so
important is that you understand that there's another side to the truth that most people are
not on and it is the side of our father. Most people assume that they are on the side of our
father but unfortunately many people will find out that they are very much mistaken. There are two
major truths that most Christians fight against. You know when I was growing up I was always told
that there were three major topics you should stay away from when talking to people. That was
politics, race, and religion. I was always told that there were three major topics you should stay
away from. And you know what I know now that that was satanic guidance to scare people from
digging into the biggest agendas used against humanity. There are two main topics that the
world is blinded by that literally involve the biggest truths that we all need to deal with
and they deal with race and religion. This current series and the other like it the we are not black
people series are literally the most important topics in this world right now. Right now in
order to be prepared for what is coming in these end times the we are not black people series
and this testing Christianity series are literally the most important things you could be focused
on and understanding right now. It is highly important to break out of the lies that this
world has humanity in. And so it makes sense that these topics are highly avoided by the majority
and they call it divisive and whatever all in order to not understand what is being shared.
What I am explaining is that the lawless one is coming. The one that we call the antichrist
is coming and in order for him to be worshipped if you think that they don't have an agenda for
the largest religion that a third of the world population follows in some way. If you don't think
that there is an agenda for them you are not thinking clearly and you're being very naive.
There is an agenda and they have told us about it so according to their satanic doctrines they
cannot be blamed because it was not concealed from the public. Let me explain why these things
are important. First the we are not black people series is important because race has been created
in order to hide the agenda against Yahuwah and his people who rejected him.
So while people believe that the oppression of the people that they call black people is just
because they are black, which is really dumb, but while people only see skin color they don't see
the bible and the actual validation of the scriptures. They don't see true Yashareel.
They are a physical people. They rejected our father and rebelled against him. So what did he do?
He physically punished them, he physically scattered them, and he physically cursed them.
And here's what's most important. He will physically gather
them as he's promised. But because it sounds like a racial topic people avoid it. And plus they are
also tainted because of the wicked Israelites who were put up before the truth actually came out
and we were all awakened. These wicked Israelites were put in place to taint the truth and not make
it accepted. Because anytime you hear this truth you want to tie us to their wickedness and their
hatred. Satan really is at work. Too many people allow him to manipulate them. Either way the world
they do not see the truth.
And they do not accept it. And when our father does what he has actually prophesied it will be
disguised under many different things probably associated with hate or they will tie us to the
brand of wickedness that the Hebrew Israelites are already under. I am not with them. I am not
tied to them. But people assume my message is the same only because of how wicked they are. So the
major truth about what our father is doing is not truly received and it will be masqueraded by race
and lies.
But if you are a Christian who believes the people in the land are truly the biblical people they will be led to the beast.
All these people who voted in this last election regardless of party they were under severe mind
control. If you do not think that they don't have a mental program to lead people to the beast you
are being too naive. But that's why the we are not black people series is highly important. How will
you recognize the fulfillment of biblical promises if you don't recognize who he's doing this with?
Next.
The second most important topic because people don't realize that Christianity is a religion of
tares that was put in place to assist the world to drive it to the beast. And if you took that test
and you don't realize that what a majority of Christians believe is not actually biblical and
it's a lot of doctrine that's not actually backed up by scripture but it's just people doing a bunch
of backflips into falsehoods. If you don't realize that for the belief about our Messiah to be the
biggest religion in the world it's an absolute contradiction of scripture.
You should realize that because our Messiah said enter by the narrow gate for wide is the gate and
broad is the way that leads to destruction and there are many who go in by it. Because narrow
is the gate and difficult is the way which leads to life and there are few who find it. Matthew
chapter 7 verses 13 to 14. Not a third of the world a few who find it. If the narrow gate which
leads to life is difficult and there are few who find it. If the narrow gate which leads to life is difficult and there are few who find it.
But there are many who go in by the broad gate that leads to destruction. You actually believe
scripture and see that Christianity is the largest religion in the world. Do you think that this is a
broad gate or a narrow one? The point I'm making is that there is an agenda that most Christians
are not aware of and they are not speaking of. Compare my message to the majority of Christian
truthers on YouTube or whatever all the other social media platforms. Are there a great deal
of people warning against this topic?
You see, there is an agenda coming and it is clouded under two topics that people assume
that they understand and that they know everything that they need to know about it, but they do not.
I have proven biblically and academically who we, the Negroes scattered around the world,
who we are. If you don't agree, it can only be because you haven't watched it in full
and assume you know what you're talking about. I am 1000% sure that the religion of Christianity
is a religion of tares that Satan planted in the same field
as Satan planted in the same field as Satan planted in the same field as Satan planted in the same field
as Yahushua planted his good seed. And I'm trying to share this truth with as many that will listen
so that you are ready for what is about to come in this world. There is a strong delusion coming
that's even stronger than what people are under right now. And when the events in the world
happen and you're driven to the points like Pike said, constrained to fight to the point of complete
physical, moral, spiritual, and economical exhaustion, you will be driven to desperation.
And as Pike said, those disillusioned with Christianity,
mystic spirits will from that moment be without compass or direction. You'll be anxious for an
ideal, but without knowing where to render its adoration, you won't know where to go.
Then you will see the true light through the universal manifestation of the pure doctrine
of Lucifer brought finally out in the public view. And I'm here to tell you that this being
disillusioned with Christianity, it's a real thing. And most don't know it because it's not
mainstream opinion. I mean, why would it be when the biggest religion in the world is Christianity?
The only ones,
really challenging it are the ones who hate our Messiah. So why would you listen to them?
And the other ones that they hate the other races. This is the Hebrew Israelites that I'm talking
about. So again, why would you listen to them either? Though we have no shortage of truthers,
we are very short of actual truth. So you should know that there is a plan that is against
Christians. And if you're not aware of it and you're not ready for it, you will be led to your
enemy. So again, I don't expect everyone to agree, but at least a seed has been planted.
If you're not with us when we're gathered, you can at least recognize and consider that you made
a big mistake and you need to get off that train that everyone else is on. The crazy thing that I
have found is that most people have not learned their lesson from the last pandemic. And most
people don't want to admit that they made mistakes, even though it's very clear that they did.
What's coming is going to be even stronger. If you're not ready for it, you will be taken down.
This is what scripture says. The coming of the lawless one is according to the working of Satan
with all power, signs, and the will of God. And if you're not ready for it, you will be taken down.
And with all unrighteous deception among those who perish, because they did not receive the love
of the truth, that they might be saved. And for this reason, Elohim will send them strong delusion
that they should believe the lie, that they all may be condemned who do not believe the truth,
but have pleasure in unrighteousness. 2 Thessalonians 2 9-12. You see,
there is a lawless one coming. We call him the Antichrist in our modern day. I don't really
care what you call him though. Everything in this world today,
is all about leading up to him. The lack of leadership in the world, the great divide within
politics all over the world, the lack of young leaders, and the abundance of old men and old
ideas. COVID, dissolution, the United Nations assemblies, global citizens festivals, wars,
economic collapses, climate change, cryptocurrencies, etc, etc. All these things happening in the world,
too many to list and mention. All these things are put in place in order to bring about the
coming of the lawless one.
It is a massive world system built on lies and false foundations that were created in order to
drive the world that is stuck in the strong delusion to bring them into condemnation.
All these things leading to the lawless one, as the scripture says, are all according to the
working of Satan, with all power, signs, and lying wonders. Please remember, Satan deceives
the whole world. Why is he deceiving the whole world? In order to lead us to the coming of the
lawless one, his false messiah. And those who follow the strong delusion are the ones who are
perishing because they did not receive the love of the truth that they might be saved. Those that
follow and believe in the lie, they will be condemned because they did not love the truth
and Yah's righteousness. And so sadly, there are many that we all know that will perish and be
condemned because they do not love the truth. Again, remember this about Satan. Satan deceives
the whole world. He does not stand in truth. And when he speaks a lie, he speaks from his own
resources because he is the father of the world. He is the father of the world. He is the father of the
lies. Satan is the god of this world, blinding the minds of those who are perishing. He transforms
himself into an angel of light, and he has ministers who preach and teach about Messiah,
but they are actually ministers for his deceptions. He is our adversary, and he walks about like a
roaring lion, seeking whom he can devour. So if you're not vigilant and sound-minded, he very
likely can devour you. The coming of the lawless one is according to the working of Satan, with all
of Satan's lying wonders, and he is the one who can devour you. He is the one who can devour you.
He is the one who can devour you. He is the one who can devour you. He is the one who can devour you.
powers, and signs. He has built a world based on lies. Everything is a lie in order for people to
follow Satan and receive the lawless one that's coming. And that is what the majority of the
people in this world are under. And that is what these important truths that are being given are
all about. And so what I'm about to do is really break it all down historically for you. But before
I did, I wanted to present you with the why. Why is this important? Because I don't want this to
get away from you. You do with it what you will. I'm just sounding the alarm and dealing with these
hard truths that most people are not presenting to you. But I'm about to really go hard and prove
it to you in these next videos. I'm about to push them out. It's a lot of information and I'm about
to pour it in on different videos so you can watch it in pieces and not get really overwhelmed
throughout this week. Before I put it all out, I just needed to break down the why so it's really
understood before we really get into it. So again, in the next part, I'm going to start by educating
you on the history of Satan. And I'm going to start by educating you on the history of Satan.
Christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical. When you dig deep into the
doctrines, it is not a doctrine of service to our Father, but a doctrine of abusing grace,
editing covenants, rejecting the way our Father actually chose to reach humanity,
and making it only be about the way Christians want to receive it.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our Father that he deserves. And in the end,
it does not prepare those who follow it to be ready for what our Father plans to do in the last
days. If you desire to be ready for our Father and his plan for us, you must come out of this
religion of tares and come to our Father in truth. Please move to part 6 in this playlist
and understand the history of Christianity and how Christianity has come to be accepted by you.
Click the link to the next video,
let's talk about it some more. Be blessed. Hallelujah. Praise Yah.
Okay, thanks again for watching. If this has blessed you, please like this and share this
video with your family and your friends. This video series is highly important for those
trying to be ready for our Father. This is part 5 of this series. Click the link or just move
on to the next video in the playlist. As always, I want to thank all who donate and contribute to
this ministry. Please know that this series would not be possible without your support.
I thank you sincerely. Be blessed. Okay, thanks again everyone for watching. See you in part 6.
I love you all.