Okay, so you should be coming from part 7 of the series.
These videos are a part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you are going to understand what is being presented.
So please, if you have not watched part 1, please stop this video and start back from video 1.
Okay, so in part 7, we started getting really into the meat of the problem here.
I have been stating since part 3 that Christianity is a religion of tares that Satan planted in the same field as Yahusha planted his good seed.
If you examine that history, you will see how much of that information it just has flown by the masses.
There is a Greek influence in the faith of Christianity.
And most people like to just write it off because they have been told that the New Testament was written in Greek.
But we know that's not entirely accurate.
Like with the book of Matthew, we know that this was the first gospel written and it was written in Hebrew.
We know this from reading writings from Irenaeus, a Greek bishop.
In his writings, he wrote this about the book of Matthew.
Matthew also issued a written gospel among the Hebrews in their own dialect, while Peter and Paul were preaching at Rome.
Yes, he said Matthew wrote a gospel to the Hebrews in their own dialect.
Let's read another.
The writings of Origen, another Gentile who was known as the father of Christian theology, he wrote,
We will begin with Matthew, who is reported by tradition to have published his gospel before the others.
He wrote it to the Hebrews.
Namely, those of the Gentiles.
So they know that this gospel was not influenced by the Greeks.
And what should be understood even more is that they knew the name of our Messiah.
They knew of the culture that came from the Hebrews.
They just rejected it.
The problem was they rejected the Hebrews and decided that they were taking over this covenant.
They changed his name because they like Greek better.
And they said that they are the ones who are going to be the stewards of this covenant.
Now, I will prove this all soon.
But what I want to do is first to introduce you to the early church fathers, because I don't think enough is going about them.
Let's be clear.
It's these men that I reject.
When I have been saying I reject Christianity, it is because of these men.
What you will find is that their influence is what the doctrines of Christianity are built upon.
And it is why the religion of Christianity is not biblically aligned.
They are Christianity.
This is Christianity.
And because most people.
Ignore these men and believe Christianity is actually what the Apostles started.
This is why there's a disconnect.
People want to ask about biblical Christianity, but there is no such thing.
These men created Christianity.
The Apostles were disciples who followed the way.
This is what it's only written.
The early church fathers are the ones who started Christianity.
And again, it is them who I reject.
So let me introduce you to some of them.
This is not by influence, but just going.
In alphabetical order, just picking some out.
First, there's Eusebius, a church father of the third and fourth century.
He is one of the church fathers who formulated the church history of the tares and made it represent Christianity.
He was a bishop of the church in Caesarea during the time of Constantine's reign.
His ecclesiastical history is a principal source for the history of the church from the first century down to the time of Constantine.
When Constantine made Christianity the religion of Rome.
Eusebius is the main source of history that brings the story of the Christian church to the masses.
Whenever you hear about the history of Christianity from the early church fathers, most of it comes from Eusebius and his book about church history.
Next, Irenaeus, a Greek bishop from the second century, year 130 to 200 AD.
He was a Greek bishop noted for his role in guiding and expanding Christian communities in the southern regions of present-day France.
And more widely, for the development of Christian theology by combating Gnostic interpretations of scripture.
He is known as the Doctrine of Unity.
Remember, this Christian church is the universal church.
I will give more on that later.
Next, there's Justin the Martyr, also known as Justin the Philosopher.
His writings really irritate me.
He was an apologist from the early second century, year 110 to 165.
He was a Greek philosopher who converted to Christianity and was known as a tireless evangelist.
He died as a martyr at the hand of the reign of Marcus Aurelius.
They say much of his work is lost.
According to the Britannica, his writings represent one of the first positive encounters of Christian revelation with Greek philosophy.
And laid the basis for a theology of history.
Basically, his work tied in Christianity with Greek philosophy.
He was a pagan who converted.
To Christianity.
Another one.
Lactaneous.
This one right here helped create Rome as a Christian empire.
He was an early Christian author from the mid-third to early fourth century.
He became an advisor to Roman Emperor Constantine, guiding his Christian religious policy in its initial stages of emergence.
And he was a tutor to Constantine's son, Crispus.
Next, Origen.
I spoke about him in the other video.
You might have noticed that his work has changed.
He's a Christian and he's a diocesan.
He's a Christian and he's a disciples.
He's a Christians and he's a disciples.
is a 3rd century Christian scholar from 185 to 251 AD, a student of Clement of Alexandria.
He was a major contributor to Christian theology. He is widely regarded as one of the most
influential Christian theologians, also known as the father of Christian theology, this man.
He is known for his contributions to the development of the Trinity and the ransom
theory of atonement. He was also a pioneer of philosophical theology in the church.
Much of your Christian doctrine comes from this man. The last one that I'll mention is Tertullian,
another early church father of the 2nd and 3rd century. He was the first theologian to write
in Latin and has been called the father of Latin Christianity, as well as the founder of Western
theology. And these are not all the men, they're just some of the men. Do you notice the transition
though? This is all Gentiles from the Roman Empire and they were responsible for shaping
the religion of Christianity.
It was no longer in the hands of the Hebrews, but now in the hands of the Gentiles. These Gentiles
from the Roman Empire were responsible for shaping the religion of Christianity that the masses hold
near to them to this day. And let me make it clear, as I said in part 7, I wanted to be clear
that it's not really the problem that they were just Greek, that's not the issue. You see, if
these men, when formulating this religion, if they truly desired to bring about righteousness
in the world, then they would be all for what they call Christianity. But for me, what I have
found concretely is that this foundation is what has grown from weeds and it is a tear and is
leading one third of the world into the arms of Satan and many others as well because people tie
our father and belief in him to the faith of Christianity which was started by these men.
And so, as Yahushua said that many will prophesy in his name and cast out demons in
his name and he will say to many i never knew you depart from me you who practice lawlessness
there's going to be a lot of people in this world that actually feel that they actually knew our
messiah but they never knew him they never even were really introduced to him because they came
to him through the religion of tares and this is why this series is so important most people never
really knew our messiah because they knew of him through religion that came from the greeks who
never really understood yahweh and what he desires his people to be and that is obedient
to be set apart to be holy to follow his commandments to honor him to live according
to the way he desires us to live so listen when i'm speaking against christianity this is what i
am speaking against so please be clear on that and listen because you have not been taught about
these men and the others you may just assume that i'm speaking against the biblical faith
when
that's completely false i am speaking against the faith that these men these early church fathers
created if you're able to get away from your pride that you think that you know it all about
christianity you would be able to understand what it is that i'm presenting but i'm going to
prove it to you in part four we went over the test and in this test as we went over the answers to
the questions there was one major thing that we saw from those that were attached to christianity
and the other thing is that their expectations were completely off compared to biblical
expectations but just from the first question what we saw is that they did not actually
understand who the new covenant better said renewed covenant they did not understand who
our father made this renewed covenant with and they did not understand what our father plans
to do for us in the last days one major reason for this confusion and misunderstanding is because
of these men these men when creating
christianity they literally took control of the covenant and said that they are now the ones
responsible for it and they believed that the yahoodian influence should be ignored and taken
away when they made christianity they said that our father was talking about them all along so
it's their job to spread it so understand that when you don't understand who the covenant is with
even though the answer is right there in scripture it's right there if you don't understand it it's
because you are attached to the
doctrine of christianity you are attached to the covenant of christianity you are attached to the
doctrines and the spirits of these men and you don't even know it let me show you by reviewing
what they have said about yashorel in that book a dictionary of early christian beliefs
under the topic of israel of god let's read some of the quotes i want you to see how they feel
about yashorel and understand this is why so many of you feel the same way this is your influence
let's read some quotes christians from among the gentiles are both more new to the covenant than the
gentiles are both more numerous and more true than those from among the jews and samaritans
that's justin the martyr next for the true spiritual israel and descendants of judah
jacob isaac and abraham who in uncircumcision was approved of and blessed by god on account of
his faith and called the father of many nations are we who have been led to god through this
crucified christ justin the martyr you know when i talk to people in the comments so many
people speak about spiritual israel anytime they bring it up i ask them where is this in scripture
and no one really knows but they know that they have this doctrine people have these doctrines
but they don't know where they came from this is where it comes from they think these thoughts
are biblical but all they're doing is grabbing from tares that chose to hijack the covenant
and replace israel it's a wicked spirit look at what these people feel god blesses this people
i.e christians
calls them israel and declares them to be his inheritance so why is it that you jews do not
repent of the deception you practice on yourselves as if you alone were the israel justin the martyr
they have said that christians are the inheritance of yah this is how replacement theology started
in romans 11 paul spoke about boasting against the natural branches but this is exactly what
these early christians did
and what they built the faith on look at some more all through him have fled for refuge to the
father constitute the blessed israel but you jews have understood none of this and you are not
prepared to understand rather since you are the children of jacob after the fleshly seed you
expect you will be assuredly saved again justin the martyr here's more we who have been quarried
out from the bowels of christ are the true
israelite race so it is necessary for us here to observe that there are two seeds of judah and two
races just as there are two houses of jacob the one is begotten by blood and flesh the other is
begotten by faith in the spirit again justin the martyr this is again that spiritual israel talk
that christians speak today but this guy he literally said there's two seeds of judah
two races and they are the true israelite race this is replacement theology
this is why christians feel that yah is in covenant with them let's read more though
the elder nation rejected him saying we have no king but caesar but in christ every blessing
is summed up and therefore the latter people have snatched away the blessing of the former
from the father just as jacob took away the blessing of esau for this reason jacob suffered
the plots and persecutions of a brother just as the church suffers this self-same thing from the
jews this is a quote from iranius more should not the worshipers of the true god be of greater
antiquity than all the chaldeans egyptians and greeks for we must bear in mind that the father
of those gentiles was born from this jappeth he received the name of javan and he became the
forefather of the greeks and ionians another according to what had been foretold in advance
the jews had departed from god they had lost god's
which had been given them in times past and had been promised them for the future instead the
christians have succeeded to their place deserving well of the lord by faith they come out of all
nations and from the whole world as cyprian another one two peoples were foretold the elder
and the younger the elder people are the jews the younger one consists of us in genesis it says
and the lord said unto rebecca
two nations are in your womb the church which had been barren before is to have more children
from among the gentiles than what the synagogue had had before the jews were to lose while we
were to receive the bread and the cup of christ and all his grace the new name of christians is
to be blessed in the earth so the gentiles rather than the jews attain to the kingdom of heaven
in the gospel the lord says many will come from the east
from the west and will lie down with abraham isaac and jacob in the kingdom of heaven
that's cyprian he's actually speaking of isaiah chapter 43 verses 1 and 6 what we're waiting for
they are saying that that's the promise that they're going to receive and not the yahudim
let me read more our ancestors were the patriarchs of the hebrews lactanius his ancestors were the
patriarchs of the hebrews i don't even know where he gets it from but this is what they think
do you understand what i'm saying i'm not going to lie to you i'm not going to lie to you i'm not
what's going on though because of what was prophesied to happen to the yahudim because
of their rebellion these christians have created and believed in a doctrine that says that they
are the recipients of this renewed covenant and this is the reason why christians don't know who
the renewed covenant is made with it's because the heart of christianity has replaced those who
our father yahua has actually made the new covenant with and place christians as the ones
who are in the covenant only they
hijacked the covenant all these quotes right here prove they hijacked the covenant they said
forget about you yahudim we're the ones in charge now but oh you still don't believe me let's look
at these quotes the jews had formerly been in covenant with god but being afterwards cast off
on account of their sins they began to be without god that's tertullian they clearly reject that the
new covenant was made with israel and judah and they have made it to be all about themselves
listen to what they have to say about the restoration of yashorel the promise that we
right now are waiting to be a part of this is what they believe you jews deceive yourself for you think
that because you are the seed of abraham after the flesh you will fully inherit the good things
announced to be bestowed by god through christ just in the martyr you know one thing that many
people say in the comments is that when i'm talking about who israel truly is i'm looking
at things of the flesh i'm looking at things of the flesh i'm looking at things of the flesh i'm
these are things it's like a spirit from the christian church the early christian church
because this doctrine they don't get it from anywhere it's not scripture it's a spirit that
these people are attached to through christianity let me keep reading as there is a bodily race of
jews so also is there a race of those who are jews inwardly the soul having acquired this nobility
for certain mysterious reasons now there are many prophecies that predict things regarding israel and
concerning what is about to befall them do not these promises that are written concerning them
need a mystical interpretation for they are rather lowly in expression manifesting no elevation of
thought or anything worthy of the promise of god that's origin another one there is one fact that
proves that jesus was something divine and sacred it is this the jews have suffered severe calamities
now for a length in time on his account
with confidence that they will never be restored to their former condition, for they committed a
crime of the most unholy kind, origin. This is what they felt. They reject all prophecy that
our father has declared, and they made it all about them, all about Christians. And if you
actually understand the history of the Christian church and understand that they have been the main
oppressors of the children of Yashorel, you will see how crazy it is to be under their doctrines,
especially natural branches of Yashorel. From the oppressions that happened during the Crusades,
to the Spanish Inquisition, to the transatlantic slave trade, to the Jim Crow laws in the United
States, and systemic racism and oppression from those who call themselves Christians,
all these things that I just listed were done by Christians throughout Christian history.
The major fact of this world is that the Christian church has been the main oppressor
over the children of Yashorel, and they have
been the main oppressors of the children of Yashorel, and they have been the main oppressors
of the children of Yashorel, and they have been the main oppressors of the children of Yashorel,
sure that the children of Yashorel are continuously oppressed in order that the Christian church
stays in power. That time, it's over now, because the dry bones are awakened, and we are coming back
to our father and being what he desires for his children to be. He prophesied,
when you beget children and grandchildren and have grown old in the land and act corruptly
and make a carved image in the form of anything and do evil in the sight of Yahuwah your Elohim
to provoke him to anger.
I call heaven and earth to witness against you this day that you will soon utterly perish from
the land from which you cost over the Jordan to possess. You will not prolong your days in it,
but will be utterly destroyed. And Yahuwah will scatter you among the peoples, and you will be
left few in number among the nations where Yahuwah will drive you. And there you will serve the gods,
the work of men's hands, wood and stone, which neither see, nor hear, nor eat, nor smell,
for from there you will seek Yahuwah, your Elohim, and you will find him if you seek him, with all your heart and with all your soul.
When you're in distress and all these things come upon you in the latter days,
when you turn to Yahuwah, your Elohim, and obey his voice, for Yahuwah, your Elohim, is a merciful
elf. He will not forsake you, nor destroy you, nor forget the covenant of your fathers, which he swore to them.
Deuteronomy chapter 4, verses 25 through 31.
what? We are turning back to him right now, and we, Yashorel, could care less what the wicked people
of this Christian church believe and what they've made their foundation. If you want to, you can
attach to that wickedness all you want, but they are taking everyone to hell with them. This is why
I reject Christianity. Again, like I said, if they truly were about our Father and His will,
then I would not speak about them in this way, but they are built on a foundation of wickedness
and rebellion. It's built on people who never knew our Father and never actually truly wanted
to submit to Him. If they actually truly knew our Father and what it means to be in covenant with
Him, then I would accept this religion, but everything about their doctrines says completely
opposite, and that's why the religion of Christianity looks so different than what
you find in the Old Testament, and that's why they don't have you read the Old Testament.
Let me show you. Look at what they say about His law. This is what the Gentiles say about
Yah's law. If anyone preaches the Jewish law to you, do not listen to him, for it is better to
listen to Christian doctrine from a man who has been circumcised than to listen to Judaism from
one who is uncircumcised. That's Ignatius. We do not follow the Jews in their peculiarities
in regard to food, nor in their sacred days, nor even in their well-known bodily sign.
Tertullian. The same God, therefore, who prohibited meats, also restored the use of them,
for He indeed originally allowed them. Tertullian. These are all the wicked thoughts that Christians
have today. This, what I read here, is the beginning and the start of where they came from.
Everything that they were speaking against, it's not like they were speaking against
what the Yahudim, what they thought about on their own. Everything they rejected and spoke
against was how Yah had led.
The chosen people. If they actually cared about Yah, they would want to serve Him the way He came
to them. They said they're not following any of that, and they're the chosen people now,
and they're going to do what they want to do. Lawlessness. You who practice lawlessness.
Christianity is lawlessness. Let me keep reading.
Jesus wished to lead all men by His teachings about the pure worship and service of God.
He was anxious not to place any hindrance in the way of many,
who might be benefited by Christianity. So He did not impose a burdensome code of rules
in regard to food. Origin. This is why people call it burdensome. You don't trust our Father
and His advice and His guidance. You look at it as burdens. Yahshua was completely rejected by Yah
for rejecting His law, and these people reject it with pride and confidence. And this is what
people in Christianity follow. Here's more though. From these things, it is plain that all those
things,
i.e. clean and unclean animals, are returned to their original blessedness now that the law is
finished. That's novation. This is what they say. The law is finished. More. Certainly,
the introduction of Christianity is through the mosaic worship and the prophetic writings.
But after that introduction, progress takes place through the interpretation and explanation of
these things. Those who advance in the knowledge of Christianity do not, as you allege,
treat the things written in the law with disrespect. On the contrary, they bestow upon
them greater honor, showing what depth of wise and mysterious reasons is contained in these
writings, which are not fully comprehended by the Jews. Just because John the Baptist was a Jew,
it does not follow that every believer, whether a convert from paganism or from Judaism,
must literally obey the law of Moses. This is origin. This is where this stuff comes from.
They literally never grew up with the true respect that our Father desires and deserves.
All I see from their writings is a faith of fulfillment of prophecy, like I said earlier.
Not everyone who says to me, Adonai, Adonai, shall enter the kingdom of heaven,
but he who does the will of my Father in heaven. Many will say to me in that day,
Adonai, Adonai, have we not prophesied in your name, cast out demons in your name,
and done many wonders in your name? And then I will declare to them, I never knew you.
Depart from me, you who practice lawlessness. Matthew chapter 7, verses 21 through 23.
And sadly, this is what's going to happen to all these people practicing this lawless faith.
He's going to tell a whole bunch of people, I never knew you. Do you understand that? He never
knew them. That's the standard of Christian doctrine. The heart and love that our Father
desires for us to have for him, it is never taught in Christianity. I mean, look at how
they feel about the Sabbath.
No longer observing the Sabbath, but living in the observance of the Lord's day. That's Ignatius.
Another one. Is there any other matter, my Jewish friends, in which we Christians are blamed than
this, that we do not live after the law and do not observe Sabbaths as you do? That's Justin
the Martyr. There was no need of circumcision before Abraham, nor was there need of the
observance of sabbaths or of feast and sacrifices before Moses. Accordingly,
there is no need of the observance of the Sabbath. There is no need of the observance of the Sabbath.
There is no need of the observance of the Sabbath. There is no need of the observance of the Sabbath.
is no more need of them now just in the martyr if some through weak-mindedness wish to observe
the laws given by moses yet choose to live with christians and the faithful as i said before not
inducing the gentiles either to be circumcised like themselves or to keep the sabbath or to
observe any other such ceremonies then i hold that we should join ourselves with such persons
just in the martyr they'll join with anyone that doesn't require them and tell them that they need
to keep the sabbath they said we do not follow the jews in their peculiarities in regard to food
nor in their sacred days again that's two trillion this is a faith of lawlessness and they do not
know our father they took over his covenant and decided what they were going to follow and what
they were not one reason why we know that yahweh will accept the gentiles is because he prophesied
about this he prophesied in isaiah about the gentiles and him accepting them
listen to what he said thus says yahweh keep justice and do righteousness for my salvation
is about to come and my righteousness to be revealed blessed is the man who does this and
the son of man who lays hold on it who keeps from defiling the sabbath and keeps his hand from doing
any evil do not let the son of the foreigner who has joined himself to yahweh speak saying
yahweh has utterly separated me from his people nor let the eunuch say here i am
a dry tree for thus says yahweh to the eunuchs who keep my sabbaths and choose what pleases me
and holds fast my covenant even to them i will give in my house and within my walls a place
and a name better than that of sons and daughters i will give them an everlasting name that shall not
be cut off also the sons of the foreigner who join themselves to yahweh to serve him and to
love the name of yahweh to be his servants
who keeps from defiling the sabbath and holds fast my covenant even them i will bring to my
holy mountain and make them joyful in my house of prayer their burnt offerings and their sacrifices
will be accepted on my altar for my house shall be called a house of prayer for all nations
yahweh elohim who gathers the outcasts of israel says yet i will gather to him others besides those
who are gathered to him that's isaiah chapter
56 verses 1 through 8 and do you see what he requires from the gentiles those who desire to
serve him those who do not defile the sabbath and those who hold fast his covenant and everything
about the christian doctrine built by these early church fathers is in rejection of this
and this is what gentiles follow and this is why these videos are being made right now
in regards to what he also desires are those who love his name
so let me tell you what i'm going to talk about in this video and i'm going to talk about the
also show you what they have said you see this is not a faith that is in service to our father
and it's proven just by understanding how they deal with our father's name
under the topic of god name of it has these quotes god has no name for everything that has
a name is related to created things that's aristides another one he has as many virtues
as are distinctive to a god who is called by no proper name justin the martyr to the father
of all who is unbegotten there is no name given these words father god creator lord and master
are not names rather they are appellations derived from his good deeds and functions
justin the martyr another one as to the name of god the father and lord of the universe
if anyone dares to say that there is a name he raves with a hopeless madness that's justin the
martyr again
more from him god cannot be called by any proper name for names are given to mark out and
distinguish various subject matters because these matters are many and diverse however
no one existed before god who could give him a name nor did he himself take a right to name
himself for he is one and unique on this account he said to moses i am the being by the participle
being he taught the difference between the god who is
and the gods who are not justin the martyr but isaiah chapter 42 verse 8 says i am yahua that is
my name these people say he has no name and guess what in christianity this is why no one speaks of
his name this is why no one knows and calls on yah this is the doctrine in christianity they say
it's the lord they do not call on his name that's christianity listen i don't play about our father's
that one it really gets me bothered this is the belief of the early church fathers this is what
christianity was built upon i mean and there's so much more i could just share there is no way i
could follow this false religion and that's why i'm speaking against it look at what they have to
say about sun worship it is written that god has given the sun and moon to the nations to worship
as gods that's justin the martyr again and this man was made a saint by the christian church
not only the believer
but even the pagan is judged more righteously for god knew by virtue of his foreknowledge that the
gentile would not believe nevertheless in order that the gentile might receive his own perfection
god gave him philosophy however he gave it to him previous to faith and he gave the sun the moon
and the stars to be worshiped for the law says god made them for the nations so that they might
not become altogether atheistic and so utterly perish
nevertheless the gentiles even in the stance of this commandment became devoid of sense and
addicted themselves to graven images therefore they are judged unless they repent this was the
way given to the nations to rise up to god by means of the worship of the heavenly bodies
but there were those who would not abide by those heavenly bodies that had been assigned to them
rather they fell away from them to wooden blocks and stones so they were considered beyond salvation
clement of alexandria these people believed that our father gave them over to wickedness
because they would later teach them to believe in him they believed that he gave them the sun
and the moon to worship as a form of training to worship him these people were out of their minds
but you know what this is what christianity is built off of and this is what christianity is
today this is the foundation you see everyone skips over the early church fathers and just
believes that christianity is the faith that is the foundation of the church fathers and
the book of acts i have repeatedly said if it was i would not be speaking so passionately against
them after the true faith was set satan used gentiles from the pagans and he infiltrated
their minds to believe that the messiah sent to the hebrews was the same anointed one from the
mystery religions that they believed in and this is what christians are today i believe if you want
to read these quotes on your own you should get that book a dictionary of the early christian
beliefs but what i've done is i have made a pdf and i've made a pdf and i've made a pdf and i've
put these same quotes on there so you can look at them for yourself this stuff is not hidden it's
just not studied listen christianity is a hellenized version of the way they took the
covenant our father made with israel and judah and they hijacked it and rebranded it with their
hellenized which means greek they hijacked it and rebranded it with hellenized culture
it is a complete twisting and rebranding of the truth which is why their messiah is greek
when ours is hebrew it only sounds biblical because of the many biblical concepts that they
use but if you read your bible from the beginning you immediately begin to find that pieces they
just don't fit this is why they have you start in the new testament instead of the old this is
a religion of tears and the history proves it that information it's important but the evidence
it doesn't even stop there because we now need to review how christianity became a religion
these quotes are just
how the foundation started this is just how the early church fathers influenced in the faith
created it but it still had not become a religion yet and that history is also very important
because they still merged in pagan concepts when they let all of rome become christians
this is the belief of the foundation of christianity the early church fathers who
built this religion this is what they believed people have been so triggered because i have
spoken against christianity people making videos
about me speaking against christianity those same people should watch this video and look
how foolish they look you all have been proven to look very foolish i hope that you can see
that you were just triggered based upon a lack of knowledge not by my conclusions these people
are tears and i reject them completely and i reject this lawless religion of christianity
and i speak on it any time of the day we are coming back to our father and being what he
truly desires and it looks nothing like what these people are doing and i don't want to
people are talking about it never has which is why this world has been so evil while christianity is
the largest religion in the world i'm done with it i don't accept it and i completely reject it
we're going to continue in this series and we're going to review how this religion of tears
even became an accepted religion we need to go to constantine in the meantime please remember
christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical but when you dig deep into the
doctrines it is not a doctrine of service to our father but a doctrine of service to our father
abusing grace editing covenants rejecting the way our father actually chose to reach humanity
and making it only be about the way christians want to receive him it lacks the love obedience
and reverence for our father that he deserves and in the end it does not prepare those who
follow it to be ready for what our father plans to do in the last days if you desire to be ready
for our father and his plan for us you must come out of this religion of tears and come to our
father in truth
please move on to part nine in this playlist and understand how christianity became an accepted
religion click the link to the next video let's talk some more be blessed hallelujah praise yah
okay thanks again for watching if this has blessed you please don't forget to like this
and share this with your family and your friends this video it's highly important people really
need to understand this topic please share this with your family and speak with them this is part
of the series click this link or just move on to the next video in the playlist as always i want to
thank all who donate and who contribute to this ministry please know that this series would not
be possible without your support i thank you sincerely be blessed okay thanks again everyone
for watching see you in part nine i love you all