Okay, so you should be coming from part 8 of this series.
These videos are a part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is being presented.
So please, if you have not watched from part 1, please stop this video and start back from video 1.
Okay, so in part 8, we started dealing with the early church fathers and some of the beliefs that these men, who were founders of the Christian church, what they had.
You know, it's funny that for as long as I can remember, people used to talk about these church fathers and say they believe this and they believe that.
But the minute I go in and speak about what they actually believed, many all of a sudden distance themselves from these men and say that they did not build their faith.
People do not want to deal in the truth.
They say I was cherry picking beliefs.
Yes, I dealt with the beliefs that were the main problem that Christianity has today.
Replacement theology and hijacking the covenant.
This has always been the main premise and problem that I have started with.
And I use their writings to prove it.
It was their own writings.
But people still say that these men...
These men did not start their faith.
And that's absolutely just ridiculous.
Like, people really want to believe that they went from the assembly of believers in the book of Acts to them now believing it 2,000 years later without any other influence.
To them, it's basically the book of Acts and then skip over 2,000 years straight to them.
Absolutely ridiculous.
There is a reason why you call yourself a Christian.
There is a reason why Christianity is the largest religion in the world.
And if you want to ignore all that history, you only deceive yourself.
Now, here's the thing.
Through this period from the 1st century to the 4th century, over a span of a little less than 300 years, the doctrines of Christianity were being built.
When you review the writings from the early church fathers, you can understand how this religion came to be.
I am not saying that I disagree with everything that they believed, because that's not true.
But you have to understand that that is why they are tares.
Tares look like wheat until they are fully grown.
And this faith was not fully grown at that time.
The reason why these...
were important is because it proves that their foundation was false.
They were very clearly hijacking the covenant and speaking from a spiritual position of Esau, stealing Jacob's blessing.
If you're honest with yourself, it's very clear.
Now, my plan after that was to go to Constantine and how Christianity became accepted.
But I realized I was rushing through some important facts that needed to be understood.
There are things that need to be explained first before we get to the formulation of the Christian church.
Now, after part eight, we know what the church fathers believed.
But when I went over this, I was just glossing over their beliefs.
So it could be truly understood the foundation of their beliefs.
But things must be clarified because you can ask, well, what about the true believers?
What happened with them?
Because there, of course, were true believers.
You also may ask, what happened with the Yahudim that truly believed?
What you will find is that the religion of Christianity is the side of tares that won in greater influence.
And they became the face and representation of the faith.
And though this Christian church...
While they act as if they are just the stewards of the faith passed down from Peter,
it is very much not the truth.
For instance, let me read you a quote from Eusebius' book, The History of the Church.
This is from Book Three, Section Three.
He writes,
Of Peter, one epistle, known as his first, is accepted,
and this the early church fathers quoted freely, as undoubtedly genuine, in their own writings.
But the second Petrine epistle we have been taught to regard as uncanonical.
Many, however, have thought it valuable and have honored it with a place among the other scriptures.
Okay, so let's review that.
Eusebius wrote that of Peter's two epistles,
it's said that his first one was widely accepted by the early church fathers.
And if you read this epistle, these things spoken here in this epistle,
they were not hard to dispute against, so okay.
But then they say that his second epistle was disputed amongst them,
and many did not want to attach it to their accepted doctrines.
I wonder why.
Maybe it's because in this short epistle, only three chapters,
as Peter was approaching death, he spoke against destructive doctrines,
as well as the doom, depravity, and deception of false teachers.
And he also spoke about us waiting for our father's promise.
So, in this epistle, he was warning against the doctrines that would come from these same men,
and he was also telling people to continue to wait for Yah's promise,
which these same men are on record saying that that promise no longer applies with us.
These early church fathers,
accepted the writings of the Hebrew men that they agreed with,
and they rejected the writings of those that they did not.
And listen, for anyone trying to disagree with that,
I am just reading from Eusebius' writings.
That's not my own view.
You can read it for yourself.
Now, what I want you to understand is that there were believers in Messiah that were from the Yahudim,
but the early church fathers labeled them as heretics.
One group I want to call out are the Ebionites,
and apparently there were different sects of this group.
But as history has written,
we know mostly about the heretics,
because this is the way that the overall group is discredited.
Let me read from Eusebius again.
Still in book three, under the heresy of the Ebionites.
Eusebius writes,
The evil demon, however, being unable to tear certain others from their allegiance to the Christ of God,
yet found them susceptible in a different direction,
and so brought them over to his own purposes.
The ancients quite properly called these men Ebionites,
because they held,
a poor and mean opinions concerning Christ.
For they considered him a plain and common man,
who was justified only because of his superior virtue,
and who was the fruit of the intercourse of a man with Mary.
In their opinion, the observance of the ceremonial law was altogether necessary,
on the ground that they could not be saved by their faith in Christ alone,
and by a corresponding life.
Okay, so this group known as the Ebionites,
they are Yahudim that believed in Yahusha.
Now, as he begins in speaking about them,
he starts talking about the ones who are the true heretics,
those that did not believe in the virgin birth,
and only looked at Yahusha as a man,
and not the Son of God.
Okay, that's fine.
But there was another part of this sect.
Let me continue reading.
There were others, however, besides them,
that were of the same name,
but avoided the strange and absurd beliefs of the former,
and did not deny that the Lord was born of a virgin and of the Holy Spirit.
But nevertheless,
inasmuch as they also refused to acknowledge,
that he pre-existed,
being God,
word,
and wisdom,
they turned aside into the impiety of the former,
especially when they,
like them,
endeavored to observe strictly the bodily worship of the law.
These men, moreover,
thought that it was necessary to reject all the epistles of the apostle,
whom they call an apostate from the law.
And they used only the so-called gospel,
according to the Hebrews,
and made small amount of the rest.
The Sabbath and the rest of the discipline of the Jews,
they observed,
just like them.
But at the same time,
like us,
they celebrated the Lord's day
as a memorial of the resurrection of the Savior.
Wherefore,
in consequence of such a course,
they received the name of Ebionites,
which signified the poverty of their understanding.
For this is the name by which a poor man
is called among the Hebrews.
And okay,
here it is.
There were those of the Yahudim
who believed in Yahusha,
and they believed in the virgin birth.
But they rejected Paul
because they viewed his writings
as being against the Torah.
They called him an apostate.
But they did believe in Messiah.
They also believed in keeping the Torah,
not the sacrificial laws for atonement,
as Eusebius writes,
that they absolutely accepted the book of Hebrews,
which explains that Yahusha's sacrifice
took away the sacrificial law.
So they believed rightly in this.
They kept the Torah,
and they stressed this,
and they kept the Sabbath.
And as you read from Eusebius,
the early church rejected these men
because they kept the Sabbath,
and they believed in circumcision.
As Eusebius says,
Wherefore, in consequence of such a course,
they received the name of Ebionites,
which signified the poverty of their understanding.
For this is the name by which a poor man
is called among the Hebrews.
Yeah, they were called Ebionites
not because they were poor materially,
as what the Hebrews used this word for.
They were called Ebionites
because they lacked in understanding
according to their way of thought.
That was a jab at them,
calling them poor in understanding.
So this leads me to a point that must be discussed.
I must address the elephant.
The elephant in the room
that is pretty much avoided.
But I cannot proceed
without being fair and thorough here.
There was a conflict with the Yahudim
and with Paul.
Many people of Yashorel today
say that it is Paul
that started Christianity.
And from a bird's eye view,
I can understand where this comes from.
But I think it's important to review this.
So let's take our time to go through this.
I stated this in part six
that there are many that reject me
because I don't reject Paul.
I want to clearly provide my stance for this
and then decide.
I do not reject Paul
because I find it dangerous
to go against the word itself.
For me personally,
I feel that at some point
the books compiled
have made it to our hands
for us to know Yah through
and Paul's letters were included.
Now, I cannot deny that it is Paul
that brings all the confusion.
If the letters of Paul
were not included in our Bibles,
much of the excuses people use today,
they would not be able to be used.
It's why as Christianity was being built,
there were other sects of the Gentiles,
that only wanted to use Paul's writings.
For example,
we must look at the sect of the Marcionites.
According to the dictionary of early Christian beliefs
and reference to Marcion,
he writes this.
Marcion, who founded his own church,
was one of the leading heretical teachers
of the second century.
His teaching incorporated many Gnostic elements,
including the belief that the God of the Old Testament
was a different God from the Father of Jesus.
Marcion accepted only the Gospel of Luke
and the writings of Paul.
Marcion accepted only the Gospel of Luke and the writings of Paul.
for his New Testament canon.
And he was forced to alter even these to fit his teachings.
In the Britannica, it says this of Marcion.
Marcion is perhaps best known for his treatment of Scripture.
Though he rejected the Old Testament
as the work of the Creator God,
he did not deny its efficacy
for those who do not believe in Christ.
He rejected attempts to harmonize Jewish biblical traditions
with Christian ones as impossible.
He accepted as authentic all of the Pauline letters.
And the Gospel according to Luke.
After he had expurgated them of Judaizing elements.
His treatment of Christian literature was significant
because it forced the early church to fix
an approved canon of theologically acceptable texts
out of the mass of available but unorganized material.
Okay so this man Marcion,
the early church fathers they disagreed with heavily.
But because of these disagreements
he was a major influence on the development of Christianity
in the second century.
His church was divided into two.
church, and followers were known as Marcionites. Now Marcion, he was not a true Gnostic, but
considered himself to be a devoted disciple of Paul, who he felt was the only true apostle.
Though he was considered a heretic, he still had an influence on the early church.
The reason why was because of his devotion to Paul. He brought renewed attention to Paul's
writings. His theology was centered upon his conviction that Christianity was something
wholly new. He was unable to reconcile the God revealed in Jesus with God described in the Old
Testament. This is the same thought with many today that love the God of the New Testament,
but hates the God of the Old Testament like they're two different beings.
Please hold on to that because this is an underlying problem of Christianity.
Now Marcion, he severed and cut the belief from the Old Testament with his newfound religion of
Christianity. It was not that the Old Testament was rejected as untrue, it was just a revelation
of the Old Testament.
He felt the God who was truly revealed was the God of the Jews, and he felt our father
Yah was an inferior being who had fashioned the material universe, including man, and ruled it
on the principle of law and obedience. He was powerful, but not omnipotent. That was Marcion's
belief. He sounds like Satan. He rejected our father because he didn't like that our father
desired law and obedience. The absolute nerve of him. The reason I bring him up here is because
he was the first to arrange a Christian canon. Paul, with his focus on free grace, was by far
Marcion's favorite apostle. As a result, he rejected the writings attributed to all the
other apostles and relied on forms of Luke's gospel and ten Pauline epistles that he redacted.
You see, the impact of Marcion's doctrines on Christianity were tremendous. You see,
because of him came the establishment of an orthodox Christian canon of scripture,
which we know as,
the New Testament. He influenced the Christian church to specify what is considered to be
canon. He spurred debate about Paul's writings, and there were many different debates from the
early church fathers like Irenaeus, Tertullian, and Origen in rejection of Marcion's beliefs,
and they countered his teachings on Paul, and from this debate became a heavy reliance on Paul.
And Paul became the foundation of Christian doctrine and Christianity. Basically, this man,
Marcion,
had his own sect of Christianity that rejected the Old Testament and the foundation that the Messiah
came through, and he only applied the gospel from Luke and the epistles of Paul and made this
his version of Christianity. You see, when reviewing his influence, he can be seen as more
like controlled opposition by Satan because his approach was completely wicked, but it brought
about a debate about the doctrines of Christianity, and it particularly brought an emphasis of the
faith built around Paul. Paul is what was debated.
Now, as I was saying earlier, without Paul's writings, much of the confusion in regards to
the law would not be there. There are no other writers that people use to speak against the law
than with Paul. I consistently get messages all day about people advocating lawlessness
because of Paul. Going back to this early church history, the Ebionites, who were Yahudim,
they rejected Paul and said he was lawless and apostate, and there are many of Yashorel
that today hold this opinion.
As well, particularly when it comes to his view about circumcision. Now, we know that the apostles
discussed the circumcision of the Gentiles, and they did not agree to place this on believing
Gentiles. We know this, but this should not be a thought amongst the natural branches of Yashorel.
For me personally, I absolutely believe in the circumcision of the natural branches of Yashorel.
I don't believe this custom has ever gone away. Now, do I think that a natural branch will be
rejected because they were not circumcised and it was not by their choice? I don't think so.
No, I do not believe that because Yah knows that our people are growing up in a culture that is
without him. And right now, it seems that the hospitals and everybody else are doing their best
to not circumcise our children. If you're a child of Yashorel, I do believe that you should be
circumcised. I believe that because this custom has never gone away. But it's possible that this
has passed you by when you did not know who you were. And I do know the struggles with getting
this procedure done today. For me, it was a struggle for both of my youngest sons to get
circumcised. I believe that because this custom has never gone away, it's possible that this
I had to get them done as an outpatient procedure for both of my sons. It was something that I felt a
tugging on that it had to be done. That was me personally. And you know what? Yah found a way
for us to get it done. I prayed about it and he answered my prayer. I believe in circumcision for
the natural branches. That's period. That's what I believe. It was an ordinance made with Abraham
from the beginning. It says,
This is my covenant which you shall keep between me and you and your descendants after you. Every
male child among you shall be circumcised. You shall be circumcised in the flesh of your
foreskins. And it shall be a sign of the covenant between me and you. Genesis chapter 17 verses 10
and 11. And this has never gone away for the natural branches. Even when they discussed this
in the book of Acts, this was about the Gentiles that they were talking about. Never against the
natural branches. So I will never speak against circumcision.
But with the writings of Paul, there is a lot of controversy that surrounds this,
which is why many of Yashorel reject Paul. So I would like to address Paul as we discuss
Christianity because we can't avoid it. You see, if I were living during that time,
I would probably find myself amongst men like Peter telling Paul to stop talking as much as he
did. I personally think that Paul used a lot of words and sometimes was too deep for his audience.
Because of all those words, they're taken very much out of context because I don't think that
Paul was a hypocrite.
He himself was not a lawless man. He boasted in his knowledge and keeping of the Torah
as he was a Pharisee. So I don't think he was a hypocrite. For me, I probably, like I said,
I would have been with Peter more than Paul as we know they had a falling out. Again,
that's just me personally. My thing is that I cannot call Paul false because YAH allowed his
writings to be read by us and therefore I will not outright call him false. I don't believe the
problem is with Paul, but it's the people reading them. So I don't think that Paul was a hypocrite.
I look at Paul as Peter spoke and warned. He said,
And consider that the longsuffering of our done is salvation, as also our beloved brother Paul,
according to the wisdom given to him, has written to you, as also in all his epistles,
speaking in them of these things, in which are some things hard to understand, which untaught
and unstable people twist to their own destruction, as they do also the rest of the scriptures.
That's 2 Peter chapter 3 verses 15 and 16. And you see, this is exactly what has happened.
We have found untaught and unstable people that have twisted Paul's writings to their own
destruction. For me, as I read Paul's epistles, I understand what he is trying to communicate
and say many times. As many times, he's speaking about the condition of the heart,
having a circumcised heart. But the way that the Gentiles use his words,
this is what is wrong and what is dangerous. I mean, for me personally,
I see what Paul speaks about many times in our modern era, when many Israelites speak about
matters of their flesh, but they are not about serving Yah. But many Gentiles, many that are
in these comments, they focus on serving Yah with a pure heart. I understand many times what Paul
was trying to say. Like he writes in 1 Corinthians, Was anyone called while circumcised?
Let him not become uncircumcised. Was anyone called while uncircumcised? Let him not be
circumcised.
Uncircumcision is nothing and uncircumcision is nothing. But keeping the commandments of God
is what matters. 1 Corinthians 7, verses 18 and 19. You see, those words right there could have
been a problem, definitely with the Yahudim. I know he was speaking about the importance of
keeping our hearts right to Yah and live as we were called, because there were hypocrites who
are, of course, circumcised in their flesh. But then there were ones who were true that were
uncircumcised. But again, you can imagine that the Yahudim, who are circumcised in their flesh,
that heard these things of Paul, were very much against what he was saying. And we know this by
just reading the book of Acts. When Galio was pro-council of Achaia, the Yahudim, with one
accord, rose up against Paul and brought him to the judgment seat, saying, This fellow persuades
men to worship Elohim contrary to the law. That's Acts chapter 18, verses 12 and 13. Another one.
And when he had come to Jerusalem, the brethren received us gladly. On the following day,
Paul went in with us to James, and all the elders were present. When he had greeted them,
he told in detail those things which Elohim had done among the Gentiles through his ministry.
And when they heard it, they glorified Yah, and they said to him, You see, brother, how many
myriads of Yahudim there are who have believed, and they are all zealous for the law. But they
have been informed about you that you teach all the Yahudim who are among the Gentiles to forsake
Moses, saying that they ought not to circumcise their children. And they have been informed about
their children, nor to walk according to the customs. That's Acts chapter 21, verses 17 through
21. And now also in that same chapter of Acts 21, it says, Now when the seven days were almost
ended, the Yahudim from Asia, seeing him in the temple, stirred up the whole crowd and laid hands
on him, crying out, Men of Yashareel, help! This is the man who teaches all men everywhere against
the people, the law, and this place. And furthermore, he also brought Greeks into the temple
and has defiled this holy place.
Acts chapter 21, verses 27 and 28. You see, this is why the Yahudim were against Paul. And as I
showed earlier, there were obvious people that believed in Messiah that did not reject the
Torah. I believe that Paul was given a ministry to the Gentiles, and I do believe that it's very
hard to do. I know it's hard communicating to both the natural and wild branches just in this
ministry, so I can imagine the struggle Paul had. I do not believe Paul created Christianity,
but that his writings were
used to justify the doctrines of Christianity. And these are two different things. But this is
just as Peter predicted. Some things hard to understand, which untaught and unstable people
twist to their own destruction, as they do also the rest of the scriptures. I personally believe
that Paul's writings are a test for Gentiles, because what does our Father desire from us?
It says,
And you shall love Yahuwah your Elohim with all your heart, with all your soul,
and with all your mind, and with all your strength.
This is the first commandment. That's Mark chapter 12, verse 30. And when people only rely on Paul's
teachings and do not come back to understand our Father, it exposes their heart. They don't
actually truly want Yah, they want religion. You see, we have this complete Bible full of
our Father's words. The Old Testament is full of, thus says Yahuwah's. It contains all the words
our Father actually has commanded his children from. It is from the mouth of Yahuwah that our
doctrines come from.
But most Gentiles ignore Yah's word and make it that Paul's words are the authority.
When Paul was just another man like me. His writings are powerful and deep, but they cannot
be understood without understanding Yahuwah first. And that is the test of the Gentiles.
You see, if they truly love Yahuwah, once they found that they have been granted the ability
to be redeemed by Yah, they would receive this gift wholeheartedly and seek him out fully and
come to know him through the entire word.
Not just through Paul. And if you go back, you see, this was the reason for the agreement in Acts
15 when they said,
Therefore I judge that we should not trouble those from among the Gentiles who are turning
to Elohim, but that we write to them to abstain from things polluted by idols, from sexual
immorality, from things strangled, and from blood. For Moses has had throughout many generations
those who preach him in every city, being read in the synagogues every Sabbath. That's Acts
chapter 15 verses 19 through 21.
You see, if the Gentiles learned these basic rules, they would learn the rest because Moses
is read in every synagogue every Sabbath. And therefore, they would learn about Yahuwah and
his way and what he wants from them. You see, it was never about walking away from the Torah.
As they said, Moses was read every Sabbath, meaning the Torah was read every Sabbath.
And they expected these Gentiles to come to the synagogues and hear Moses being read.
This is the reason why they gave that agreement. If they come around the word and
hear it, they will learn it. You see, I can't tell you how many Christians I have spoken
to and they say, yeah, they read the Bible. But then they say, but they're real heavy
on Paul. Paul is the author of many of the Gentiles' faith. But most people have not
actually read their whole Bible first. You see, when I read Paul now compared to what
I read him before I read the whole Bible, I read him completely different. And I think
that's the determining factor. I don't think anyone can understand Paul without reading
their whole Bible first. But this is what Christianity does.
It's unlearned and untaught people making doctrines of destruction. The church fathers
proved Peter's warning, if you just read their writings. Here's a few. Paul was, after Jesus,
the founder of the churches that are in Christ. That's origin. And obviously, this is why people
believe Paul started Christianity. Here's another. Now with the view of branding the apostles with
some mark of ignorance, the Gnostics put forth the case of when Peter and those who were
with him were rebuked by Paul. Still, they would show from the circumstance, which they
allege of Peter's being rebuked by Paul, that Paul added yet another form of the gospel
in addition to that which Peter and the rest had previously set forth. That's Tertullian.
Now again, Peter himself wrote a warning that what men would do with Paul's writings. And
this is exactly what they're showing. They're saying that Paul put forth another form of
the gospel, untaught and unstable men.
Here's another one.
This is from the Disputation of Archelous and Mainz. You see, they said Paul's writings are
the foundation of the Christian church. And therefore, this is why people speak against Paul,
because all of the lawless is caused by his epistles. So what am I getting at?
What I'm saying is that you cannot understand Christianity without understanding Paul.
I believe that Paul is the main point of confusion and division amongst Yashorel and the Gentiles.
I do think that without his letters, there will be very less confusion. But that's not for me to
say. I don't believe that this argument will ever be settled until our father gathers us back to him
and sets us all right. As we discuss Christianity, it's important that you understand that most
Christians, they come from the spirit of Marcion.
They come from his spirit. They just don't recognize it. What I mean by that is that they
only understand our father according to the New Testament only, mostly by the epistles of Paul.
It should never be done this way, but this is the way many of them are. It comes from a spirit
that is not about doing the father's will, which is loving him with our whole heart, mind, soul,
and strength. So being that they only seek to understand him through Paul, they don't ever
come to truly understand him. And this is true. They don't come to truly understand him. And this is true.
They don't come to truly understand him. And this is true. They don't come to truly understand him. And this is true.
Christianity. I do believe that it is true that there would be no Christianity without Paul.
But can I blame Paul for that? Or can I blame those who took his writings and formed these new
doctrines? For me, I choose the latter. There's much about this that we do not know. But this is
what I do know. I know that it's important that as you build your faith, you do not start with
Paul. This is the error of most Christians. And then after they read Paul first, then they read
the Bible to formulate and fit their understandings.
You can only really understand Paul by reading the full scriptures for yourself first from the
beginning. Now, how can I say this with confidence? Because it's just what Peter warned about. He said
people being untaught and unstable, twisting Paul's words. You see, reading Paul when knowing
nothing else about Yah is a person who is untaught. And that is exactly what the problem
is in Christianity. So don't come at me because I said that. I'm using scripture.
From Peter. I'm just applying it. Again, at the end of the day, this is what I know with all
assurance. When it comes to Yah, there is no tolerance for lawlessness. There is no tolerance
for rejection of our father's Torah. There is no example in the scriptures of an apostle that was
lawless. Even Paul himself was not lawless. So if you're trying to use Paul as an excuse for
lawlessness, it's only because you're not reading his words clearly and you do not have an actual
grounded foundation based on the Bible. So if you're trying to use Paul as an excuse for
the word, when our father has prophesied that he will remember us and the covenant he made with us,
it's because he said we will obey his voice. In order to be what he desires, we must obey his
voice. Even in the scriptures where Paul is speaking about circumcision, look at what he
writes. He said, circumcision is nothing and uncircumcision is nothing. But keeping the
commandments of Elohim is what matters. First Corinthians chapter seven, verse 19. So he
clearly believes keeping the commandments of Elohim is what matters. So he clearly believes
keeping the commandments of Elohim is what matters. So he clearly believes keeping the
commandments matter. So people that advocate against the Sabbath and advocate against keeping
the commandments, they're not applying Paul correctly. The early church, they wanted nothing
to do with anyone who taught keeping the commandments. And so through Paul's writing,
they were able to adapt the doctrine that they were able to use. But they do not understand Paul.
They never really understood Paul because they never understood Yah. The point I'm making is
that though Paul's writings are the major source of confusion for Christianity, I believe that
in me teaching, I cannot reject Paul, but only how people have applied Paul. I recommend that as
you understand this faith that we are in, you do not read Paul before you understand Paul's
foundation, which means you must go to the Torah and start from the beginning first, if you're going
to understand Paul. The problem is that Paul's epistles, they're read like the Torah and they
should not be. These are letters. Paul's epistles are letters. His epistles could be compared more
to like my videos.
than to what Moses wrote in the Torah. Paul was addressing different people in different
circumstances that we do not clearly know. He was talking to people. He was trying to teach people.
We do not have all of the circumstances that Paul was responding to in the letters.
We do not have the correspondence back. We don't have a lot of information on the exact people
that were receiving these letters. We just have his letters and Christians use those letters
to form a whole new religion. We know that not all the Yahudim agreed with Paul.
I'm talking about amongst the ones that actually did believe in Messiah. What people do today is
that they take Paul's words and place them in emphasis before Yah's word even. I will write
back and say, thus says Yahuwah, and people will respond with, but Paul said, that is an improper
usage of Paul. And unfortunately, the Gentiles who took control of the faith did not have proper
reverence for Yah to enforce the proper attitude. They used whoever said what sounded better for
them to enforce the doctrine that they wanted to have.
You cannot put Paul over our father. You do not use Paul in that way.
We cannot get past Paul's influence. There were many Yahudim that believed in Messiah that were
against him. The sect of Yahudim that were called Ebionites, they were later moved out
of the picture when Rome made Christianity their religion. So when people ask, what about the
Yahudim who believed in Messiah? You can understand what happened to the Ebionites. I will discuss
them further in the next episode when we get to Constantine. What I wanted you to understand
is that Paul became the influence of Christianity. People chose him as the most true apostle and
debate and discussion about him made him the main focus of Christianity. And his letters were
approved most than all other epistles. As Eusebius writes about the compilation of the New Testament,
he writes, since we're dealing with this subject, it is proper to sum up the writings of the New
Testament, which have been already mentioned. First then must be put the Holy Quaternion of
the Gospels. Following them, the Acts of the New Testament. The Acts of the New Testament are the
of the apostles. After this must be reckoned the epistles of Paul. Next in order, the extant former
epistle of John. And likewise, the epistle of Peter must be maintained. After them is to be
placed, if it really seemed proper, the Apocalypse of John, concerning which we shall give the
different opinions at the proper time. These then belong among the accepted writings. Among the
disputed writings, which are nevertheless recognized by many, are the extant, the so-called
epistle of James.
And that of Jude. Also, the second epistle of Peter. And those that are called the second and third of
John. Whether they belong to the evangelist or to another person of the same name. Among the rejected
writings must be reckoned also the Acts of Paul and the so-called shepherd and the Apocalypse of
Peter. And in addition to these, the extant epistle of Barnabas and the so-called teachings
of the apostles. And besides, as I said, the Apocalypse of John, if it seems proper, which some,
as I said, reject.
For which others class with the accepted books. And among these, some have placed also the gospel
according to the Hebrews, with which those of the Hebrews that have accepted Christ are especially
delighted. And all these may be reckoned among the disputed books. And you see, these are the
men who made the New Testament. And they are the men who chose what it is we know in the New
Testament. I mean, there was disputes about the book of Hebrews and the book of Revelation. But
what was not disputed was their decision about the Bible. And they were not disputed about the
Bible. And they were not disputed about the Bible. And they were not disputed about the Bible. And
they were not disputed about the Bible. And they were not disputed about the Bible. And that is
something that we must understand. All of this is in reference to their religion. But Paul is not
the author of our faith. Yahweh is. And for us, we are coming back to serving Yah according to his
word. And that is what is most important. Anyone and anything teaching you lawlessness should be
rejected. But I do not believe that that is what Paul has been preaching. I just think that he's
misunderstood and not applied correctly. I needed to get through that because you cannot skip over
this information when understanding Christianity.
I felt that in order to be thorough, I could not ignore it. Now that we've got through that,
in the next part of the series, we will finally discuss Constantine.
In the meantime, please remember, Christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical.
But when you dig deep into the doctrines, it is not a doctrine of service to our Father,
but a doctrine of abusing grace, editing covenants, rejecting the way our Father
actually chose to reach humanity, and making it only be about the way Christians want to receive
him.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our Father that he deserves. And in the end,
it does not prepare those who follow it to be ready for what our Father plans to do in the last
days. If you desire to be ready for our Father and his plan for us, you must come out of this
religion of tares and come to our Father in truth. Please move to part 10 in this playlist and
understand how Christianity became the religion of the Roman Empire. Click the link to the next
video and let's talk some more about it. Be blessed.
Hallelujah. Praise Yah.
Okay. Thanks again for watching. If this has blessed you, please don't forget to like this
and share this video with your family and your friends. This video series is highly important
for those trying to be ready for our Father. This is part 9 of the series. Click this link
or just move on to the next video in the playlist. As always, I want to thank all who donate and
contribute to this ministry. This series would not be possible without your support.
Thank you for your blessings. I thank you sincerely.
Be blessed. Okay. Thanks again, everyone, for watching. See you in part 10. I love you all.