Okay, so you should be coming from part 10 of this series.
These videos are a part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order
if you're going to understand what is being presented.
So please, if you have not watched from part 1, please stop this video and start back from video 1.
So, in the last video, part 10, we went over how Christianity became the religion of Rome under Constantine.
Since the beginning of this series, I have been explaining that the religion of Christianity is a religion of tares.
And as we have been going over the history, I believe for anyone listening with an intent to understand
rather than just disagree, this should be made clear by now.
But there is so much more evidence and understanding that should be had so that when you go out to witness
and when you speak to others, you can speak from an educated point of view and bring about points
that they have never heard of before.
There is one topic that we need to get to, which is about the Trinity.
But in order to get there, I have been laying a foundation of understanding so that once we get to the subject,
the whole thing can be understood.
As we continue to understand Christianity, it is not possible to continue to understand the creation of it
without understanding a major concept that is a major influence in this world.
But it is something that is not spoken about in great detail.
So we need to go over it.
So let me make this point known clearly.
Christianity is a religion that is said to be built upon the foundation of the Yahudim who walked with Messiah.
But this is not true.
It is only part of the truth that is leaving out a great difference.
It is a great deal of information that makes all the difference.
You see, when you dig deep into the beginning foundations of Christianity,
you see something very different at the surface.
What we find is that the claim that Christianity is a religion that is said to be built upon the foundation of the Yahudim
who walked with Messiah,
this is a disguise that hides the truth that Christianity is a faith inspired by the foundation of the Yahudim
but it is actually grounded and built more upon,
Greek philosophy.
And this view right here must be the main understanding that's understood when understanding Christianity.
Because if you do not understand the Greek philosophical mindset,
you will not understand the main point of what I'm saying.
And here's the problem.
For many of us who live in the United States or a part of a colony or nation that has been colonized by Western civilization,
you have been taught and indoctrinated by the mindset of the Greeks.
And most of us don't even know it.
But this is what Christianity is.
And this is why it lacks true reverence for our father,
according to the way he has actually led and commanded his people.
So I alluded to this and spoke about this in part seven,
but it's important I really break this down.
So there is more than enough clarity given.
It's important that we review this so that there is a way to identify and discern between the wheat and the tares.
We want to understand the separation between the truth of the way versus when Christianity took over,
it became the main authority.
So we want to understand the separation between the truth of the way versus when Christianity took over, it became the main authority.
Because there is a lot of history that goes missing under the label and guise of Christianity.
And if this history was told properly, this world would recognize that it is being hustled and manipulated by Satan.
that is being hustled and manipulated by Satan. You see, the true assembly of the way that was
growing, they largely resisted the infiltration of the pagan converts to the faith, who were
bringing in their Greek philosophy and intertwining it with the faith. They were holding on firm to
the teaching of the apostles, drawing their doctrine from the writings of the apostles and
the holy scriptures, the books of the Old Testament, which, as Paul has stated, are able to make you
wise for salvation. That's 2 Timothy chapter 3, verse 15. You see, as the faith of the way began
to spread, there were two different plants that were growing from two different seeds. There was
a split, and as I have been repeatedly saying, this split was due to the planting of tares.
On one side was the truth, the ones who stuck to the plain and simple teachings of the scriptures,
and the other side was increasingly compromised with pagan thought and practices adopted from
the Greco-Roman religion.
As I have been explaining, the split that happened was the beginning of tares that began to be
spread. It became the main basis of the Christian faith, but it wasn't told to the masses. You know,
I get it, you may want to fight against this. Let me show you how you can see this is a real
thing in today's world. Let me show you. Early on, as this ministry began to grow,
as I was bringing out certain truths, all of a sudden, I was getting this label that I did
not understand why people thought this was a bad thing.
People were calling me a part of the Hebrew Roots cult, and at first, I was like,
I'm not a part of any group, so I know they're crazy, and they just needed a label.
But I couldn't understand why anyone would think that there was a problem
with the Hebrew Roots of the scriptures. Get it, our father did not deal with the Greeks.
He did not deal with the Romans. He did not deal with the English Anglo-Saxons.
He was in covenant with the Israelites, who were partakers of the covenant passed down from their
forefather, Jacob.
Who received it from his father, Isaac.
Who received it from his father, Abraham.
All of these men were Hebrews.
And therefore, everything about the foundation of the Bible is rooted from the Hebrews.
If you're saying that you worship the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob,
you're worshiping the God of the Hebrews.
Hebrew Roots.
Our father is only in covenant with Yashareel, who are Hebrews.
You'll see no other place that he made a covenant with no other people.
So when people have spoken against the Hebrew Roots, it never made sense to me
until I realized that what they're actually saying is that Christianity is not rooted from the
Hebrews. It's rooted from the Greeks. And that's why there's a problem. It's right in front of our
faces. But because they did not explain it, it was a little hard to gather. Christianity is a
religion of the Romans that is inspired by the Hebrews, but built around the philosophy of the
Greeks.
Let me say it again. Christianity is a religion of the Romans that is inspired by the Hebrews,
but built around the philosophy of the Greeks. Once this is made known to you and you understand
this, it will open your eyes to many things hidden right in plain sight. Now, here's the
thing. This period in time, there are more people with college degrees than any other point in time
in history, I believe. Most people that we know today have come through a formal education system
that they believe is a religion of the Romans. And so, if you're a Christian, you're going to
believe that the Bible has educated them. But the truth is that people are not educated. They are
indoctrinated. These schools and education system that has not taught us information, they taught us
how they want us to look at the world. We learned about the world through their influence. And the
better that we take that information, we get a higher score. And so, while there are so many
educated folks, not many people know that much about the subjects that matter. And one of them
that matters for sure is Greek philosophy. For the Western world to be so intertwined and influenced
by Hellenistic culture, it is absolutely crazy that we know very little about the Greek influence
on the world that was later adopted by the Romans. So, I would like to take time to break
this down to you by going over who the Greeks were. And so, what I will do is go back in time
and teach some history. We will go back to the first half of the 5th century BC. This was the
period in time after the Greek influence. And so, what I will do is go back in time and teach some
history. We will go back to that period. And so, what I will do is go back in time and teach some что
Now, we are pulled in the fifth century BC.
Now, at the same time, on a peninsula in the northern Mediterranean, the children of Yavan were growing in strength.
They were uniting to battle and face the Persian Empire.
The Hellenes, or Greeks as we know them today, these are the children of Yavan that descended from Yapeth.
These Greeks, under the leadership of the city-states of Athens and Sparta, fought and eventually defeated the huge Persian army in battles that we have been indoctrinated into celebrating.
Like, you know the movie 300?
This is the time period that I'm speaking of, when they battled the Persians and then became the dominant empire.
So before the Persian Wars, the Greeks were already building the civilization and were in the Golden Age.
They began innovations in their architecture, medicine, writing, poetry, sculpture, dramas and comedic plays, astronomy and government.
Their innovations in government laid the foundations of democracy as we know it today.
In their society, every male citizen was a member of the Ekklesia, which means assembly.
This group met about 40 times a year to make political decisions.
So all the male citizens were able to participate in meetings.
They were able to make the decisions they wanted for the city.
There was another body of 500 men called the Boulay, who dealt with the day-to-day business of the government.
And yes, this is who the first black Greek fraternity, Sigma Pi Phi, also known as the Boulay, were inspired by naming themselves.
A bunch of sellout Negroes inspired by cultures who came to oppress and hijack their own people.
So anyways, in Sparta, they developed a military culture.
Hence, like we said, the Greek culture.
As you know from the movie 300.
And Athens became a trading and seafaring power with a strong navy.
And from these two cities, Greek city-states started to spread Hellenistic culture by colonizing towns on the shores of the Aegean and Mediterranean seas.
So let's talk about what they believed in.
What did the Greeks believe?
The Greeks believed in the development of both mind and body.
They founded academies for teaching language, mathematics and the arts.
Athletes from Greece and Greece.
Athletes from all over Greece competed in sporting games honoring the gods.
The greatest of these events was the Olympics, which was held every four years.
The Greek religion was based in the belief that the gods and goddesses lived on Mount Olympus.
The chief Grecian god was Zeus, and he ruled over an array of super beings who displayed human weaknesses.
They followed the same pagan beliefs of all the other pagan empires before them with their worship of the father god, mother goddess,
who was Artemis, and their reborn sun god, who was Apollo.
There was Athena, who was the goddess of wisdom, Poseidon, the god of the seas, Aphrodite, the goddess of love and beauty, and Hermes was the messenger of Zeus.
The gods and goddesses were said to give cryptic messages to mortals through oracles.
The most famous of these oracles spoke from the temple at Delphi.
This was the period of mythology that controlled the world before the Greeks changed.
As I have explained many times, the world was influenced by pagans.
Those who believed in polytheism, they believed in many gods.
And it was through their belief in the many gods that they rationalized the world.
Myths were passed down orally, shaping cultural values and explaining the origins of the universe, human beings, and natural phenomena.
For instance, in mythology, Zeus is an example of a passive creator in the story of how he enshrines the gods.
Zeus instructed his sons to create humans and animals on earth.
Zeus is their creator. This is how they thought.
And that was the way of Greece, and all the other pagan empires before this time.
Like using Egypt as an example with Ra.
In the mythology religion, Ra is the sun god and was considered the primary creator deity.
He was believed to have brought forth all of life.
Ra is their creator.
This was their religion, and the way that they viewed the world.
This is what I'm speaking of when I speak about the sun god.
This is what I'm speaking of when I speak of mythology religion.
But in the golden age of Greece in the 5th century BC, this all changed, and it's this change that changed the world.
As I explained earlier, the golden age of Greece, also known as the golden age of Athens,
was a period of cultural, political, and economic flourishing in the 5th century BC.
And this culture was the foundation of Rome when Rome became a Christian religion.
And this golden age of Greece is what the United States itself,
is built and modeled after.
Everything we know today is intertwined with this golden age of Greece.
We are all influenced by Greek Hellenistic culture.
And of the many different parts of the culture that we're influenced by,
there is nothing more influential than what changed from the introduction to Greek philosophy.
So let's deal with it.
The name philosophy is itself Greek.
The word philosophy comes from the Greek words,
and Sophia,
which mean love and wisdom, respectively.
The term philosophy can be translated as lover of wisdom.
And so ancient philosophy must be understood by first understanding the creators of philosophy,
which are the Greeks.
And then history will show that this Greek philosophy continued during the Roman Empire period,
all the way down to the reign of Justinian, who was the Roman emperor from 527 to 565,
when,
it all was merged into Christianity.
And then from that point in history,
it was no longer discussed in the way of its origin,
which is why people today don't recognize how much Greek philosophy is intertwined in Christianity.
They just stopped speaking about their philosophy and it all was the way of the Christians.
So what is Greek philosophy?
Greek philosophy is a collection of ideas that originated in ancient Greece and is characterized by a focus on logic and rational thought.
It is a way of thought.
Greek philosophy opened the doors to a particular way of thinking that provided the roots for our current modern Western intellectual tradition.
The way that we think today comes from Greek philosophy.
Greek philosophy brings about the thought around many questions that people never get the answers to,
but will debate for eternity.
Questions like,
why are we here?
What is the meaning of life?
What is the nature of reality?
What is the fundamental substance of the universe?
What is the meaning of justice?
How can one live a good life?
What is knowledge?
What is the relationship between the mind and body?
These are questions that come through the Greek way of thinking.
This was never a way of thinking from the Hebrews.
Ancient Greek philosophy is a system of thought first developed in the sixth century B.C. by Thales of Miletus, 623 to 548 or so B.C.
This man is regarded as a man of justice.
This man is regarded as the first Western philosopher and mathematician.
He was born and lived in Miletus, a Greek colony in Iona, modern Turkey.
Iona is referenced as the birthplace of Greek philosophy because of him.
He is known as the first philosopher in Greek tradition.
So let's connect the dots.
You remember when I spoke about the original way of thought with the pagan world,
which was what we now label as mythology, the mythology religion.
It was through their mythological beliefs in their many gods that they rationalized the world.
That's the way they used to understand the world through.
Well, because of the influence of this man, Thales of Miletus,
because of his influence, the Greeks eventually broke away from the prior use of mythology to explain the world
and instead started using reasoning in natural philosophy.
And it's because of that influence why he is referred to as the first to have engaged in mathematics,
science, and deductive reasoning.
Now, in understanding this, I need to make this clear.
It's important to understand that they never actually really went away from their gods.
It's not like they just stopped believing in their gods.
No, they used a new way of thinking to rationalize the world.
That's all.
And this is very important to understand.
The way I see this time period, how when I'm analyzing it,
is that during this time period is when the northern tribes of Yashiro,
they were already exiled from the land when Assyria conquered them.
And then,
Judah was also exiled to Babylon.
The kingdom was broken.
And during this time, our father was giving prophecy to the prophets like Jeremiah, Isaiah, Ezekiel,
about the coming Messiah and Redeemer.
And Satan began to change his ways and his doctrines that he controlled the pagan world through from the beginning.
It began to use this people, the Greeks,
in order to create a new mindset that would lead the world to him.
And so he started to change their way of thought.
Away from the original way he showed them through their false pagan gods that started with Nimrod.
But with this doctrine, he never replaced or changed the gods.
He only changed the way the people thought about these gods.
And this is what Greek philosophy is.
For instance, I want you to think about this.
We say that Christos means the same thing as Mashiach.
We know the Hebrews had a prophecy of expecting a Messiah, a Mashiach to come.
Why did the Greeks?
Have an expectation or a word for an anointed one?
Again, they were using the label Christianos for the people that worshiped Serapis before Messiah ever even came.
They already had an expectation of an anointed one.
What I'm saying is that this idea to them, it wasn't new.
And it's a pagan culture.
So why wasn't it new?
You have to think about that.
But anyway, that's not my main point.
What I'm explaining here is what Greek philosophy is.
So.
As we're going to go through it, let me go through some major points in regards to Greek philosophy.
First of all, in Greek philosophy, it deals with reason and inquiry.
Greek philosophy emphasized the use of reason and logic and the idea of observing the natural world impartially.
It began a focus on deductive reasoning.
OK.
Next, it also deals with major contributions to math and science.
Ancient Greek mathematicians like Pythagoras, Euclid and Archimedes.
Made major contributions to math, including the concept of mathematical proofs and basic ideas about geometry.
I'll speak more about that soon, but understand that geometry, it's a big part of Freemasonry.
It's a big part of the occult.
This is where it comes from.
Also, in Greek philosophy, it contributed to breakthroughs in medical discoveries.
Hippocrates, an ancient Greek physician, is considered the founder of medicine, which is medical care based on observation of clinical signs.
And rational conclusions and does not rely on religious or magical beliefs.
He established a medical school.
He wrote medical treaties and is known for his systemic and empirical investigation of diseases and remedies.
Yes, the Hippocratic Oath is named after the Greek physician Hippocrates.
Also, it deals with the four elements.
See, Greek philosophy held that the universe was made up of four elements.
Fire, water, earth and air.
And this is where you start seeing the occult manifest in itself.
Also, like I said earlier with math, like geometry.
Those elements, this is what witches use.
This is occultic knowledge that they're talking about here.
Anytime you see people bring up these four elements, know that they're talking about witchcraft and the occult.
Also, in Greek philosophy, it includes mythology.
Again, they never did away with the mythological pagan gods.
They still believed in them.
They just believed that the mythical stories like Homer's Odyssey and Iliad.
Revealed allegorical truths about the cosmic order, human nature and the gods.
And they used their reasoning to understand it.
But they always believed in their pagan gods.
And then there's Socratic philosophy.
Socrates' philosophy focused on ethical matters and he taught that all virtue is knowledge.
He believed that people do not desire what is bad.
And that if someone does something bad, it must be out of ignorance or unwillingly.
And this is all the premise and foundation of Greek philosophy.
I wanted to introduce you to it first in this part of the series.
But I'm going to break this down piece by piece so that this history that has not been told to us can now be better understood.
I wonder in all these seminary schools, all these religious schools and all these people with masters and divinity, how many people understand how much Greek philosophy is intertwined in Christianity and they don't recognize that this is a problem.
It really is mind baffling to me.
I don't understand how you go to church for decades.
And nobody speaks about the intertwining of the Hebrew faith with Greek philosophy.
But we're done with that now.
I don't care what anybody's talking about.
This is done.
Our people fought major wars against the infiltration of the Greeks in the Maccabean Wars.
And I refuse to be in a religion that uses our Messiah and intertwines their nasty religion.
Absolutely not.
But let me get back to it.
The founders of Christianity, the early church fathers, they believed in this foundation of Greek philosophy.
They believed in it wholeheartedly.
But if you don't understand Greek philosophy, why would you think that it was wrong?
Or maybe you thought it's inconsequential.
It didn't matter.
I want you to remember, this is what the early church fathers said in regards to Greek philosophy.
Quote from Clement of Alexandria.
Hellenic philosophy does not comprehend the whole extent of the truth.
Besides, it is destitute of strength to perform the commandments of the Lord.
Yet it prepares the way for the truly right.
Royal teaching.
Clement of Alexandria.
Let me read another one.
Philosophy is not, then, the product of vice, since it makes men virtuous.
It follows, then, that it is the work of God.
Again, Clement of Alexandria.
The last one.
Not only the believer, but even the pagan is judged most righteously.
For God knew by virtue of his foreknowledge that the Gentile would not believe.
Nevertheless, in order that the Gentile might receive his own perfection,
God gave him philosophy.
However, he gave it to him previous to faith.
And he gave the sun, the moon, and the stars to be worshipped.
For the law says God made them for the nations,
so that they might not become altogether atheistic and so utterly perish.
Nevertheless, the Gentiles, even in the instance of this commandment,
became devoid of sense and addicted themselves to graven images.
Therefore, they are judged unless they repent.
This was the way given to the nations to rise up to God,
by means of the worship of the heavenly bodies.
But there are those who would not abide by those heavenly bodies that have been assigned to them.
Rather, they fell away from them to wooden blocks and stones.
So they were considered beyond salvation.
Clement of Alexandria.
So just get this here.
The early church believed that Greek philosophy prepared them to know our Father
and be ready to be stewards of this new faith of Christianity.
They ignored those verses when Paul said,
They just ignored that right there.
Ignored it completely.
You see, Christianity is a blend of the Hebrew scriptures mixed in with Greek philosophy.
And this is exactly why it is a religion of tares.
It is not based according to Messiah,
but a faith rooted in philosophy, traditions of men, and the basic principles of the world.
Everything that Paul warned against.
And as we go through this history,
you will see how the Greek philosophy was blended directly into Christianity.
And this is exactly why I reject it.
But I'm going to stop here because I don't want to overwhelm.
I want to give this in bite-sized pieces so information is able to be digested
and not missed by other major points.
The point that we're at in this series right now is we're introducing Greek philosophy.
In the next part, we're going to dig deeper and discuss the Greek philosophers
that were the major influence to the early church fathers.
Men like Plato and Socrates.
They cannot be ignored.
And we're doing all this to make our way to understanding the Trinity.
But as we discuss this and we make our way to understanding the Trinity,
I want you to do your own thinking.
I want you to ask yourself, now that you understand a little bit about Greek philosophy,
ask yourself about this question.
Does this question, is Yahushua God,
or even more relevant because they use his English name, Jesus?
Let's use that one.
Is Jesus God?
Ask yourself, is this question a question that came from the mind of the Hebrews,
the apostles that followed the way?
Or did this way of thought originate from Greek philosophy?
So again, did this way of thought originate from the Hebrews?
Or is it influenced?
Or is it influenced of Greek philosophy?
Ask yourself that question.
And if you start looking at this and asking yourself this,
you'll be better able to understand the ways of thinking that we must separate from.
But this is just the intro.
We will get deeper into it in the next video.
In the meantime, please remember,
Christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical.
But when you dig deep into the doctrines,
it is not a doctrine of service to our father,
but a doctrine of abusing grace,
editing covenants,
rejecting the way our father actually chose to reach humanity,
and making it only be about the way Christians want to receive him.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our father that he deserves.
And in the end, it does not prepare those who follow it to be ready
for what our father plans to do in the last days.
If you desire to be ready for our father and his plan for us,
you must come out of this religion of tares and come to our father in truth.
Please move to part 12 in this playlist and understand the Greek philosophers who influenced the early church fathers.
Click the link to the next video and let's talk some more.
Be blessed.
Hallelujah.
Praise Yah.
Okay, thanks again for watching.
If this has blessed you, please like this and share this video with your family and your friends.
This video series is highly important for those trying to be ready for our father.
This is part 11 of the series.
Click this link or just move on.
The next video in the playlist, as always, I want to thank all who donate and contribute to this ministry.
This series would not be possible without your support.
I thank you sincerely.
Be blessed.
Okay.
Thanks again for watching everyone.
See you in part 12.
I love you all.