Okay so you should be coming from part 11 of this series. These videos are a part of a topical
series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is
being presented. So please if you have not watched from part 1 please stop this video and start back
from video 1. Okay so in the last video part 11 we were introduced to Greek philosophy and beginning
to understand this foundation because this is what the current world is centered around. In part 11
we began to learn about the first Greek philosopher Thales of Miletus. He is known as the father of
Greek philosophy but as we continue to grow in this subject it is imperative that we learn more
about the other Greek philosophers and how their influence began to spread and grow. This part of
the lesson though it has nothing to do with the scriptures directly it has everything to do with
the history of the world and the main influences that are behind much of the mindsets that many of
us hold today. If you review the history of the Greek philosophy you will see that the first Greek
philosopher Thales of Miletus is known as the father of the Middle Ages also known as the Medieval
Period. This is a time period that generally spanned from around the 5th century following
the fall of the Western Roman Empire until the early 15th century at the time of the beginning
of the Renaissance. This 1000 year period is a time period that Christianity began to spread
around the world. You would not be Christians today without this history that followed during
this period. Whether you want to believe that or not it's just history.
During this time period amongst the Christians Aristotle was the primary influence of thought
amongst these people. Aristotle's philosophy had a profound impact on the intellectual world
of the Middle Ages influencing the fields of philosophy, science, and theology. Aristotle's
ideals became the foundation of Western scholasticism the philosophical system of the
Middle Ages. In the 13th century Thomas Aquinas combined Aristotle's philosophy with the
Christian dogma which became the basis for Catholic theology and science. Aristotle's ideas
influenced medieval philosophers in the natural sciences and philosophy of science. This philosopher
and his ideas was the main mindset of the Christian world during this time period. But you
see if you know nothing about him and the philosophers who came before him he's just a name
to you. But you do not understand the influence and that's the missing link in regards to history.
Here's some
more for you. Also during the renaissance period the Medici's as they influenced and built the
renaissance and began to spread their beliefs through the practice of humanism. I made a video
about this last year. The Medici's decided to go back to the occult of the Greeks and began to
embrace Plato instead of Aristotle. And even more important than that when Christianity was being
formed and the doctrine of the trinity was being formed men like Origen who was the founder of the
trinity doctrine he was influenced by Plato's philosophy to form the doctrine. I am getting
there so I will not rush through it but just understand when Origen adapted it it was called
neo-Platonism. They adapted Plato's view to fit Christianity. You see all of this it's not hidden
it's just not discussed. Once you take these terms and these people and just do a few google
searches all of a sudden you will see a whole new world in the realm of Christianity that's not
spoken about.
In mainstream Christianity it pretty much goes unnoticed but you have to ask yourself why? I've
been getting a lot of people challenge me right now trying to come against this ministry and
before I started this series I knew that when I started speaking against Christianity it was
going to happen. But you see every person that has challenged me about all this and why I'm
speaking against Christianity I always ask them straight up if they agree that their Christian
beliefs should be merged or influenced by Greek philosophers like Plato,
Aristotle or Socrates. Now while all these critics want to easily yell out that I'm a false teacher
not one of them actually want to deal with the elephant in the room. They just want to wipe off
all this Greek philosophy and all this Greek influence. They want to act like it doesn't exist
but it clearly does. So many people are being used because now that Satan and his influence
it's now being exposed he's now sending out his minions against me to either distract or deter me
but it's not working. I want you to understand that Satan has been hiding
in this whole little realm of Greek philosophy and he has not made it known to the masses which
is why people do not know it and if you bring it up they just want to act like it's inconsequential
but the more you start understanding this the more you will see how big of a deal this is and
that's what I'm going to bring out. You see the fact is that Christianity is heavily influenced
by Greek philosophy and if you don't know anything about the philosophers themselves
then why would you think that this even matters? This to me should be a subject
that every Christian pastor or one that tries to defend their Christian faith should be able to
deal with directly if they want to say my premise about Christianity being a faith of tares is
false. You see the Greek philosophy and the Greek influence being mixed in with the faith of the
Hebrews is the reason why people need to go to theology school and go to seminary training
because they need to be taught how to merge the Greek philosophy in with the Christian faith and
make it seem like it's just biblical beliefs. They are being merged and people aren't being
told. This is why they need training because why would you need training to read your Bible?
Why would you need training to be led by the Holy Spirit and understand what the scriptures are
saying? Everyone that is a pastor that says that they're in seminary training or in divinity school
they are being led by other influences but they think it's proper. It's not. All right so I want
to say a few introductory things about what we are going to do this semester and why it is
important to do them. This is a course in Old Testament interpretation. Loosely translated that
means that this is a course in which we try to help you understand what the Old Testament is, how
it has been interpreted, how it contributes to the lives of faithful people in contemporary
communities of Christians Jews and Muslims and most important we hope we will help other
How to Become Responsible Biblical Interpreters Ourselves.
We take the course title seriously.
I've already said that.
This is a course in Old Testament interpretation.
Anyways, I have men that comment on this channel often,
and they seem to come from a good place in their heart.
They just don't want to actually deal with the fact that they're being lied to,
so they think they're coming against me, and I'm the enemy,
or I just got to be misled, or whatever it is.
So they don't really want to deal with what I'm actually saying,
and they think it's more about me and less about the information.
They say things like this.
Christianity has been my religion for many years,
but I didn't receive my understanding from the early church fathers.
I've actually studied the Bible under the guidance of the Holy Spirit, not man.
This is what they think.
But then people will say that Christianity is their religion,
and that they receive their understanding from the Bible only.
But here's the thing.
There is no religion of Christianity,
in the Bible.
So just calling yourself being in the religion of Christianity
has to be with some kind of influence.
Somebody has raised their hand and said,
this is a religion of Christianity, and you have attached to it.
You can't say that you are influenced by nothing,
but then you're in the religion of Christianity.
It makes no sense.
It's double-minded.
You see, most people are unaware of how their belief in the Bible
has even been brought to them.
We are not without influence.
This is how Satan deceives the whole world.
And the thing is,
is that if people are so proud that they do not want to admit
that there could be influences and tricks from Satan
that they have come up against,
then they will always live in deception.
There is not one person awakened today
that cannot say that they have been lied to.
And if this is a hard thing for you to admit,
it's only because you are still very much trapped in lies.
I'm just giving out information about how the lies got there.
And these Greek philosophers are a major source
of how these lies got there.
They are not spoken about,
and they're not spoken about.
They're highly glossed over, though.
And so I'm going to teach about them and who they were
so we do not live in ignorance.
Hosea chapter 4 verse 6 says,
I simply want to do my part in providing knowledge
about important subjects that are a main influence
of the world that we live in,
but yet are not spoken about.
If people were just reading the Bible,
if people were just reading their Bibles
and applying what it says,
then there would be no reason to use these teachings.
But the thing is that all these people being trained
in seminary schools, going to divinity training,
they are learning about the Greek influence,
but it's being taught to them by people that they trust.
So they're not computing that they are being taught
a different way than what the basis of the scriptures
are actually based by.
And that's why they go against Hebrew roots
and say that this is wrong and this and that,
because they're not being rooted up in the scriptures.
They're being rooted up in the Bible.
They're being rooted up in the faith of Christianity
that is influenced by the Greeks.
And I have no tolerance for it.
And this is what you're seeing through these videos.
If anyone wants to challenge me and say
that this information is incorrect,
you actually have to deal with the information presented
and just say, all that I'm not influenced by.
I'm influenced by the Bible.
You're lying to yourself.
You can keep that lie.
Anyways, when we ended up in part 11,
we spoke about the father of Greek philosophy,
Thales of Miletus.
So now that we know about him,
let's look at the Bible.
Let's look at the Bible.
Let's look into those who come from his influence.
And that understanding will bring us
into the golden age of Athens,
which is also considered the golden age of Greek philosophy.
We are now in the 6th century BC.
Nebuchadnezzar and his Babylon
is said to have first destroyed the first temple in Jerusalem
in the beginning of the 6th century BC,
about 586 BC.
And the Persian king Cyrus the Great
is said to have freed the Jews from exile
in Babylon in 538 BC.
So you should have a period of reference point
biblically of what happened in the 6th century BC.
biblically of what was happening to Israel during this time.
Okay, so let's get into it.
So around 530 BC,
a philosophy based on the teachings of a philosopher named Pythagoras
was thriving in a Corinthian colony in southern Italy.
Pythagoras is best remembered for his mathematical formula
known as the Pythagorean theorem.
Pythagoras was influenced by Anaximander,
a Greek philosopher who was a student of Thales.
Pythagoras grew up on the island of Samos,
but traveled the Mediterranean,
with his merchant father.
He lived in Egypt,
where he studied its religion.
Pythagoras studied with Egyptian priests and thieves
and became the only foreigner that we know of
to be granted the privilege of participating
in their pagan worship.
There is a consensus that Pythagoras
learned the foundations of geometry,
mathematics,
and metempsychosis
while studying in Egypt.
Okay, so in 525 BC,
the Persian king Cambyses II
invaded Egypt
and Pythagoras,
was carried off to Babylon as a prisoner.
Remember, at this time,
Babylon was under Persian control.
It was just a decade and a half earlier
that King Cyrus let Judah go back
and rebuild the temple.
Again, just so you can understand
the time period that we're talking about.
All that history matters.
You see, because Yashura was split
and trying to rebuild itself,
the devil was busy creating his new religion.
He knew Yashura was prophesied
to have a redeemer,
and Satan began preparing his people,
for the change that Yahuwah would bring.
Anyways, back to Pythagoras.
It's said that he was treated well in Babylon,
and while he was there,
he learned astrology,
mathematics,
music,
and a very mystical worship of the gods.
You see, in his travels to Egypt and Babylon,
he was being initiated
into the mystery religions.
He was initiated into the Egyptian
and Chaldean mysteries,
and became well-versed in the esotericism
of both the East and the West.
And from this, he created a philosophy
containing elements from both science
and the mystery religions.
So understand this right here.
Greek philosophy is just the Greeks' adaptation
to the mystery pagan religions of the Egyptians.
All their knowledge comes from the Egyptians.
Make sure you understand that.
And from this influence,
he founded Pythagoreanism
and the philosophy of the Pythagoreans.
This was a philosophy that included the belief
in transgressions,
transmigration of souls,
a.k.a. reincarnation,
also a belief that the key to knowledge
is contained in mathematics,
and a belief that life of harmony
is obtained through contemplation,
music, and gymnastics.
Pythagoreans developed a complex doctrine
in the mystic meaning of numbers.
They also practiced vegetarianism.
In Albert Mackey's Encyclopedia of Freemasonry,
Pythagoras is mentioned in much of the symbols and items.
In the Encyclopedia of Freemasonry,
when reading about him specifically,
they write,
On his return to Europe,
he established his celebrated school at Crotona,
a Dorian colony in the south of Italy,
about 529 B.C.,
much resembling that subsequently adopted by the Freemasons.
His school soon acquired such a reputation
that disciples flocked to him
from all parts of Greece and Italy.
Pythagoras taught as the principal dogma of his philosophy
the system of metempsychosis,
or the transmigration of souls,
He taught the mystical power of numbers,
and much of the symbolism on that subject,
which we now pass as is derived
from what has been left to us by his disciples.
For of his own writings, there is nothing extant.
Okay, so what I'm saying is that Pythagoras
was a great influence of the occult
and esotericism for the Greeks.
His influence is well known even within Freemasonry,
but they say that it's not by his direct influence,
but by those who follow his work down the line.
And this is how Greek philosophy goes.
It goes from one teacher, and it goes past down the line.
And the reason why this is important, like I said,
is because in many ways, Pythagoras,
he laid the foundation for future Greek philosophers.
So that's why you need to understand him.
So let's keep going through these philosophers.
Let's go through their history.
Nearly a century after Pythagoras,
Athens and Sparta went to battle in the Peloponnesian War.
The war significantly weakened the Greek city-states,
particularly Athens,
and it left Greece divided,
and vulnerable,
with a major power shift that moved from Athenian dominance
to Spartan control,
and this led to widespread economic hardship.
Athens,
it was once a powerful naval and political force.
But now that it lost its empire
and its influence due to the war's outcome,
they experienced significant economic
and social disruption.
And so because of this,
a new philosophy fueled by the effects
of being overcome by war,
formed among a new generation that was made soft
because of the prior success by the Athens.
You see, these people, they were dealing with the great success of Athens,
and they became soft and spoiled.
But then after their fall, a new mindset began to emerge.
The people began to question the old ideas of absolute good.
And this new movement taught that virtue was defined by personal desires and personal feelings.
And this brought about materialism.
Materialism became the ultimate goal of life.
And these new philosophers that began to spread this ideology were called sophists.
Sophist is said to mean clever or skilled man.
The sophists traveled from city to city,
teaching various subjects like rhetoric, philosophy, and politics to wealthy young men,
often focusing on the art of persuasive argumentation and achieving erit or excellence in public life.
And of course, they did this for a fee.
Their teaching methods, often seen as prioritizing,
prioritizing winning a debate over absolute truth,
it eventually gained a negative connotation known as sophistry,
which now refers to intellectually dishonest arguments or manipulation of logic.
Now, let me say this.
You see, in Christianity today, everyone wants to debate this and debate that.
If you look on YouTube today, there's not a lot of teaching.
There's a lot of debate.
People want to debate this and debate that.
This is the culture in Christianity.
It is a common practice that is just accepted,
but people, they don't recognize where it comes from.
Understand, debate was not a mindset of Yashareel.
It did not come from them.
Nobody debated about Yaha and his ways.
They weren't allowed to.
He spoke what they needed to do.
They followed it.
They believed it.
In fact, understand, the rebellion of why Yahushua was murdered
did not start until the Pharisees and Sadducees began debating about him.
You see, while the Pharisees were largely resistant to Greek culture
and they actively rejected the faith,
the Hellenistic practices,
they still were influenced by some aspects of Greek thought.
And debate was a part of this.
And this practice is what led to the rebellion that actually crucified our Messiah.
What I'm saying here is that debating, it's not a culture of Yashareel.
It is a culture of the Greeks.
And every Christian that believes in this practice
is just showing their influence by the Greeks.
But because of lack of information, they don't recognize where it comes from.
These same tactics that people apply,
is what led to the crucifying of our Messiah back then.
And these same Christians that practiced this
will lead to the persecution of those living in the truth
when the time of the Antichrist comes.
Just saying.
This is why I reject the way of the Greeks.
Anyways, let me get back to it.
The Sophists, in regards to materialism,
believe that all matter was comprised of the smallest particles called atoms.
They believe that the material universe, including human life,
was a result of blind chance.
They claimed that all cultures and religions were human inventions.
The existence of the gods were debated,
and some Sophists, they even promoted atheism.
And the reason I bring them up,
and the reason they are important,
is because of who followed after them.
You see, the philosopher Socrates,
460 to 399 BC,
he was one of the philosophers who stood against the Sophists
by arguing for the existence of objective standards of good and evil.
Socrates is noted as the founder of Western philosophy,
and was known as one of the first moral philosophers
of ethical tradition of thought.
Though Socrates was not around after the time of Pythagoras,
he absolutely was influenced by Pythagoras.
Socrates' belief about reincarnation,
also known as transmigration of the soul,
was similar to those of Pythagoras and the Pythagorean society.
All this is, is the mystery religions being passed down.
Please don't forget this.
It's not just about a way of thinking.
It is the occult.
And dealing with spiritual demons
that are giving them this way of thought.
Socrates, he taught that instead of abandoning
oneself to passions, human emotions, and impulses,
the virtuous person controlled his thoughts and emotions
through the study of philosophy.
By living a virtuous life and doing good deeds,
a person could obtain true happiness.
But look, he was not well received at his time,
and he was a mockery to most Athenians.
The Athenians actually demanded
that he denounce his philosophy,
and when he refused, they demanded his suicide.
But through that, Socrates stated that he did not fear death
because it is the goal of philosophy
to reject material things
and prepare the soul for the afterlife.
You see, Socrates brings a divide in Greek philosophy.
When you understand philosophy up until the time of Socrates,
in history, it's labeled as pre-Socratic philosophy.
As I explained in part 11,
philosophy first started with becoming
a preference for rational explanations
and argumentation over mythology.
That's how it started.
They emphasized rational thought and arguments and logic
over using their mythological ways.
After Socrates, though,
philosophy shifted towards a greater focus
on individual ethics and the examination of personal virtue.
It has been said that Socrates' greatest contribution
to philosophy was to move intellectual pursuits
away from the focus on physical science.
As was once pursued by the so-called pre-Socratic philosophers
such as Thales, Anaximander, Anaximenes, and others.
So leading away from the focus on physical science
and into the abstract realms of ethics and morality.
So he brought the divide in philosophy.
And no matter the diversity of the schools
which claim to carry on his teachings,
they all emphasize some form of morality
as their foundational tenet.
And this right here is what paved the way
for the acceptance of philosophy.
So let me explain what this means.
Before Socrates, good and evil
was not really a concept thought of by these people.
That was not their way of thought.
They were lawless.
Now Socrates, he did not bring law to them,
but he did bring the thoughts surrounding good and evil.
And this is what began to prepare the Greeks,
which then was taken over by the Romans.
It provoked these people to a different way of thinking.
Socrates' belief was that people don't desire what is bad.
And as my brother Hakeem said in the comments,
it should all bring us back to the scripture
that we are all born in sin and shaped in iniquity.
Behold, I was brought forth in iniquity
and in sin, my mother conceived me.
Psalm chapter 51, verse five.
Socrates believed the complete opposite,
that people don't actually desire to be like this.
These philosophers did not know Yahuwah
and they made religion based on their own thoughts.
And that brings me to this scripture.
There is a way that seems right to a man,
but its end is the way,
the way of death.
Proverbs chapter 14, verse 12.
And that's Christianity.
And that leads me to explain exactly the importance
and relevance of Socrates
and how intertwined the religion of Christianity is
with Greek philosophy, because here it is.
The concept of morals as we understand them today
largely originated from the ancient Greeks.
This is a major thought in the Christian world today
about morals.
Hebrews, they didn't have morals.
They had a Torah.
It was just how Yahuwah guided them.
The Greeks had morals and morality and ethics,
and they were easily able to be debated,
which is how what was once considered evil
can now be considered to be good.
This is all Greek philosophy mingled into our lives.
Hi.
I was just reading the catechism
and I'm going over morality on the sources of it.
Yeah.
And I'm just kind of confused on the wording
that they have in the catechism.
Like, I'm not sure if it says that morality comes from God
or if it comes from a rational consideration
of, like, the consequences of our own actions.
So I'm just kind of confused.
Yeah, it's in different senses.
One of the classic problems in philosophy
is what's known as the Euthyphro dilemma.
It's called that because it's discussed
in Plato's dialogue, Euthyphro.
And in that dialogue, Socrates has a dialogue,
a question that he poses to people
about where morality comes from
and what morality is.
One of the ideas that's proposed to Socrates
is that morality is whatever is pleasing to the gods.
And Socrates says, well, okay,
but why is it pleasing to the gods?
Is it just arbitrary?
Or is it pleasing for some other reason?
And looking at that, you could say,
well, okay, if it's just because
the gods like it and there's no other reason,
well, then morality seems arbitrary.
And if it's, if it, on the other hand,
if there is some other reason,
then morality seems superior to the gods
because they didn't create it.
And it seems to be binding on them.
And so Christians, this has been a question
in philosophy all down through the ages,
and Christians looked at this and said,
okay, God is the fundamental bedrock
of all reality.
Nothing would exist if it wasn't for him
and his eternal nature.
We know, though, that God is intrinsically good
because he's all perfect.
He has all possible perfections,
including moral perfection.
He's all holy.
He's all good.
And that means that goodness itself
is part of God's eternal nature.
And that's the solution to the Euthyphro dilemma.
Morality is not independent of God,
and it's not arbitrary.
It's rooted in his own eternal nature.
And when we do things that are moral,
we're participating in God's own goodness,
which is neither arbitrary nor independent of God.
So we're participating in God's own goodness
when our actions conform to his moral will.
But then there's the question,
how do we come to know what God's will for us is?
And that's where reason is.
Reason comes into the picture
because God gave us intellects that allowed us,
unlike other animals,
he gave us intellects that allowed us
to scrutinize our own nature
and determine what the best course of action is
based on our own nature.
And so in that sense,
our knowledge of morality originates in that sense
from our intellect,
but more fundamentally,
it originates from God's own eternal nature.
You understand what I'm saying.
I understand now.
It took a while, but I got it.
You see, with Christians today,
Christians will tell you that it's all about morals.
They will tell you that.
But that is not the way of the Hebrews.
It is the way and the mindset of the Greeks.
The way of Yashareel was a Torah,
and it was the way Yahuwah led them.
You may say, hey, there's no difference.
Well, you see, morality, it has no law.
What was accepted yesterday can be changed tomorrow.
So now today in Christianity,
it's considered moralist to speak against homosexuality.
I'm not, this is not a bad,
I need y'all to hear my heart on this.
This is not a bashing.
This is not, he, if I was there,
maybe I would have told him,
is there something in the middle you could do?
Like kind of a, like a little, maybe if somebody,
well, I was born like this.
I don't know how I feel that I feel you.
And I wish that there was an option of other in the kingdom.
I know.
Honestly, I wish God would have made it so much simpler.
And it was like, A, B, C, or D, like frick, I'm serious.
As a pastor, like, so what do you think about gay men?
I don't know.
If you love people, how can you not accept homosexuality?
It's about morals.
If you love, you should love everyone
because it's about morals.
People don't understand what this Greek philosophy
intermingled in this faith has produced.
Morality is a mindset of the Greeks,
and it started with Socrates.
Christianity can of course compare its morals to the Torah
because of course, Yahuwah's law, they're perfect.
But Christianity has no actual laws.
And it's why morals can change,
which is exactly why we see it changing today.
The concept of morality and morals and ethics
is from the ancient Greeks.
People need to wake up.
Now back to Socrates.
He's noted as the founder of Western philosophy,
All the philosophical schools that were spread under the Hellenistic age can be traced back to Socrates.
After you understand these Greek philosophers, it's then important to understand how this all was spread.
After the doctrines were created, they then started spreading this and it's known as Hellenism.
And this is started through Alexander the Great.
Alexander still did not come on the scene yet through all this.
Not until this foundation of Greek philosophy was cemented.
Let's keep going.
Socrates challenged the mythical stories about the gods.
He attempted to motivate people to have as much concern for their souls as they did for their bodies.
I will get to him next, but in Plato's writing, Apology of Socrates,
Plato writes that Socrates claimed to have a demonian, literally a divine something,
that frequently warned him in the form of a voice against mistakes, but never told him what to do.
So he was guided by a demon.
And it was this man, Socrates, who was a great influence on the Greek philosophy that was intermingled with Christianity.
Christianity is influenced by a man, influenced by demons.
If you research Socrates and Christianity, the information and correlation, it's amazing.
I've read things like, was Socrates a Christian before Christ?
Stuff like that.
It's amazing.
And they want me to attach to this stuff.
Absolutely not.
Let's keep going so you can understand.
So Socrates.
Socrates left no original writings.
His legacy is known through his students.
One of his most known students was Plato, 427 to 347 BC.
Plato recorded his teacher Socrates' ideas in a series of dialogues in which Socrates asked questions and leads others to his conclusions.
This technique became known as the Socratic method.
Plato is best known as the author of philosophical works of unparalleled influence
and is one of the major figures of classical influence.
Plato continued to develop and build his philosophy based upon Socrates' ideas.
That was his teacher.
Understand how this all worked.
It went from Thales of Miletus to Anaximander to Pythagoras to Socrates, now to Plato.
Each philosopher built a foundation that the next philosopher built on.
And throughout it all, the mystery religions and their ideas were passed down through each of them.
With Plato, he believed in two realms of existence, mind and matter.
In the realm of the mind, or spirit, there are ideals or archetypes.
Plato called the creator god of the universe the Demiurge, meaning craftsman,
who was the idea of the good, also known as the form of the good.
The Demiurge was the creator.
And Plato's theory of forms, in which forms are defined as perfect, eternal, and changeless,
concepts.
Existing outside of space and time, the form of the good is the mysterious high form
and the source of all other forms.
I'll need you to remember that part right there, the theory of forms.
I'll get back to that soon, but we're about to get deep here.
Listen, all of this matters.
You may wonder where I'm going with all this information.
Maybe you're wondering, am I just drawing out a lot of history to you?
No, that's not the case.
This is a foundation of the Greeks.
And if you don't understand this, you will not understand what was done when Christianity
began to...
So dealing with Plato, let's say this.
According to Plato, after the Demiurge made the universe, he created the deities of Mount
Olympus, and then the souls of lesser beings.
Human souls first inhabited the heavens, but eventually desired to experience the
material world.
So the lesser gods prepared bodies for them to inhabit.
The earth itself was given a soul.
This is what he believed.
For Plato, the goal of human life was to become...
virtuous through philosophy and reincarnation, eventually returning to the original divine
state.
In Plato's writing, The Republic, he quoted Socrates.
He said,
Then this must be our notion of the just man, that even when he is in poverty or sickness
or any other seeming misfortune, all things in the end will work together for the good
of him in life and death.
For the gods have a care for anyone whose desire is to become a just and to like God
as far as a man can attain the divine likeness by the pursuit of virtue.
Here is another quote from Republic.
398a.
Then it seems that if a man whose wisdom enables him to take on every possible shape and to
imitate anything at all were to arrive in our city, anxious to put himself and his poems
on show, we would fall down before him as though he were a sacred object, a wondrous
and pleasing one at that.
But we would say...
That there is no one else of this sort among the citizens of our city, nor is it permitted
that there ever shall be.
We would anoint his head with myrrh and give him a garland of wool, but for our own benefit
we would ourselves employ the more severe and less pleasing poet.
Okay.
You see, in this writing, Republic, Plato writes of an anointed one, one that is anointed.
The idea of a just man being anointed is a metaphor signifying that the truly just
person will be recognized and honored by society, essentially being set apart as someone
of exceptional moral character, much like a person being anointed with oil in a ritualistic
way.
This imagery is used to highlight the high regard and respect such a person will receive
in an ideal society.
And this influence, it must be understood.
Let's take a look at another quote from the Republic.
From Book 2, Section 361E and 362A.
Tell it, then, and even if my language is somewhat rude and brutal, you must not
suppose, Socrates, that it is I who speak thus, but those who commend injustice above
justice.
What they will say is this, that such being his disposition, the just man will have to
endure the lash, the rack, chains, the branding iron in his eyes, and finally, after every
extremity of suffering, he will be crucified.
And you see, what you need to understand.
Is that the Jesus of the Greeks is just Plato's just man.
And it is these writings from the Greek philosophers, like Plato, that spurred the actual acceptance
of the anointed one that they call Jesus.
It was not an attachment to the Hebrew Messiah, which is why everything about him is attached
to the culture of the Greeks and not the Hebrews.
Consider this writing of Plato to be like the scriptures for the Greeks.
Consider Plato to be like their Isaiah or Jeremiah.
The Hebrews had the scriptures and the prophets.
The Greeks had the writings of these philosophers.
And so, Socrates would be like Moses, and Plato would be like Jeremiah, Ezekiel, or
Isaiah.
Plato put forth the idea of an anointed one, and this cannot be ignored.
Now, Plato, he founded the academy, which is an educational center that is considered
by many to have been the first university in the Western world.
The academy became the model for other schools of higher learning.
Later on, when the Medicis funded the Renaissance, you will see that they went back to Plato's
teachings in order to push forward their way of humanism.
His influence on our society cannot be understated, but unfortunately, it's not taught in this
way.
He's not taught about at all.
Cosimo Medici was so taken with Plato that he founded a platonic academy in Florence
because of his platonic influence.
Understand, the idea of the anointed one, or Christos,
comes from Plato.
People want to believe that this is just a Greek way of speaking about the Hebrew Messiah,
but it is way more than that.
As I keep explaining, there were people called Christians before Messiah ever came, those
who worshipped the cults of Serapis.
They were already called Christians.
Their use of Christos with the Hebrew Messiah is the Greeks adapting their philosophy to
the faith and prophecies of the Hebrews, but adapting it to their own ways and their
own thoughts, and it needs to be understood.
Plato's Republic.
The Republic is a major influence in our world, and we just don't know it.
In that writing, the Republic, not only is there talk about the just man, but there's
also the allegory of the cave.
This is what you get when you research this on Google.
Plato's allegory of the cave is a metaphor that compares people to prisoners in a cave
who are only able to see shadows on the wall.
The allegory is a way to illustrate the concept of idealism and how people can only understand
a small part of reality through their senses.
Plato's allegory of the cave is a passage from his work, The Republic, written around
380 BC.
It has been used as a metaphor by philosophers for thousands of years to help people overcome
materialism and superficiality, and that's what it's about.
And do you know that they put these philosophies directly in our movies, like the movie The
Truman Show?
In this movie, Truman is a prisoner in the cave, only able to obtain artificial and illegitimate
knowledge.
They say,
This movie is one of the most direct adaptations of the allegory.
Also, the movie The Matrix.
It's one of the many movies that uses the idea of Plato's cave.
The movie Interstellar.
In that movie, the other realm that they were going to is the exterior of the cave.
The main character, Cooper, must complete an arduous journey to reach it.
In further inspection, we see that the Tesseract also uncovers the cave of knowledge.
This knowledge not only is capable of saving the human race, but it also allows Cooper to
communicate back to Earth and share what he has learned.
They're teaching you Greek philosophy through their stories.
The idea of Plato's cave has been used extensively in storytelling.
It's the Greek philosophy being told to us through their stories.
So when people like to say that they're not influenced by Greek philosophy, but yet our
entertainment is filled with stories that use their Greek philosophy, you only say that
because you don't understand Greek philosophy.
The crazy plot twist to all this is that in our satanic world, it's influenced by the
Plato's philosophy.
This world is created around Plato's allegory of the cave.
The last thing I'll mention in regards to Plato is Plato had the theory of forms.
We talked about it earlier.
In this philosophy came one and the many.
One and the many.
Remember that.
It's a philosophy from Plato.
One and the many refers to the concept that a single perfect form underlies and gives
definition to the many individual imperfect things we experience.
Essentially the idea that a single, universal essence, the one, is the source of all the
diverse manifestations, the many, that we see around us.
That's the philosophy.
Now why is that important?
You see, this philosophy is the primary influence that Origen uses as he created the doctrine
of the Trinity.
Now I will be getting to that soon.
I'm getting close to it.
But I'm just dropping crumbs for you to follow on your own.
Let's continue on with discussing.
As I end with this study, I will end with the last philosopher, and that's Aristotle.
Aristotle, 384-322 BC.
He was a student of Plato.
He developed a system of logic and scientific exploration.
Aristotle divided philosophy into three categories, mathematics, physics, and metaphysics.
He further taught that practical philosophy is concerned with ethics and politics, while
poetic philosophy dealt with metaphysics.
He also developed the concept of virtue ethics, emphasizing the cultivation of good character
traits to achieve happiness, which continues to be a cornerstone of moral philosophy.
He began the wider Aristotelian tradition that followed, which set the groundwork for
the development of modern science.
Western philosophy, including occult philosophy, has its roots in Aristotle and Plato.
Until the Renaissance, the modern world was influenced by Aristotle's philosophy the
most, as I shared in the beginning.
You see, this information was hard to get through, but it had to be presented because
this is the influence of the early church fathers.
They were influenced by the writings and thoughts of these men before they ever heard
of the faith of the Hebrews.
What these men believed matters, and you can see that none of them were inspired by Yahuwah.
In fact, Socrates himself admits to being guided by a demon, and he was the main philosopher
who prepared the Greek thought for Christianity.
The work and thoughts of these Greek philosophers are highly involved with the esoteric and
influences from the occult in many ways.
We have heard of their names, but know very little about them.
Again, Plato literally helped prepare the minds of the Greeks for the acceptance of
a coming anointed one.
His writing literally writes of a Christos.
You can't understand how they started accepting the Messiah until you understand the influence,
and this is the beginning of that influence.
These were the scriptures and the prophets of the Greeks.
None of their views had anything to do with Yahuwah and his truths.
People want to believe that all of a sudden, people started believing in the resurrection
of the Messiah, and then from that, they started adapting to the Hebrew faith that
came through the apostles.
But they are ignoring the influence of the Greek philosophers that influenced the society
of the Greeks and the Romans, and this was the main influence that led the early church
fathers.
Justin the Martyr.
A highly annoying early church father.
I read about him in part 8.
He was a former pagan and highly influenced by Plato himself.
These people just didn't turn and start believing in the God of the Hebrews.
Absolutely not, but this is what we're meant to believe Christianity is.
Again, none of their views had anything to do with Yahuwah and his truths.
It was preparing for the seed that Satan was going to plant when the Messiah he was preparing
for actually came.
And today, the modern world uses the philosophy of these men.
To prepare the world for the Antichrist.
For example, the movie Man of Steel about Superman, which is highly suggestive to the
coming Antichrist and preparing the world for him.
For those who know Plato's philosophy, you know that the Man of Steel is Plato's just
man.
For those who accepted Yahushua, they accepted him as Plato's just man.
But that's why they adapted him to Greek, which is why you call him Aesus, then to Jesus,
and he does not have.
Hebrew identity.
The Jesus of the Greeks is Plato's just man, and he will be leading the masses to the Antichrist.
Many people just don't know because we're not educated to.
They don't teach this in our schools.
They don't teach this in the churches.
All this influence is right in our face, but because we are not taught about it, these
people can manipulate us.
Again, my people are destroyed for lack of knowledge.
Hosea 4 verse 6.
People argue all day about the word Christos.
And why it should be.
But they ignore the influence of the Greeks and why they were even expecting an anointed one.
This idea came from Plato's just man.
Let me say it like this.
People are completely naive to think that Satan did not know that the Messiah of Yashorel
was coming.
It was the first prophecy Yahuwah ever gave in the scriptures in Genesis 3 verse 15 about
who would defeat Satan.
Satan absolutely knew.
And the moment that Yahuwah started prophesying about this Messiah to the prophets is the
moment when these philosophers came on the scene.
And then what happened three to four centuries later after this way of thought was accepted
by the Greeks and then the Romans?
When our Messiah rose from the dead and news of him began to spread, these same people
already prepared by these Greek philosophers were now ready to accept the Messiah in their
own way.
Not how the Hebrews presented him, but through their own philosophical way.
And this was the basis for how they took over Christianity.
And then they got their own teachers and their own theology.
They were able to teach the people how to merge their Greek beliefs in with the faith
of the Hebrews.
And that is what Christianity is today, which is why people need to go be trained in theology
and divinity to even teach this stuff.
Paul says,
Let no one deceive himself.
If anyone among you seems to be wise in this age, let him become a fool that he may become
wise.
For the wisdom of this world is foolishness with Elohim.
For it is written, he catches the wise in their own craftiness.
And again,
Yahuwah,
knows the thoughts of the wise, that they are futile.
First Corinthians chapter three, verses 18 through 20.
The wisdom of these Greek philosophers were futile, but they were a foundation of the
early church fathers.
And the Christian world wants us just to ignore this, but we cannot and we should not.
As John says, they are of the world.
Therefore, they speak as of the world and the world hears them.
We are of Elohim.
He who knows Elohim hears us.
He who is not of Elohim does not hear us.
By this, we know the spirit of truth and the spirit of error.
First John chapter four, verses five and six.
What we're doing is uncovering the false foundation of Christianity and every church
that teaches should have this understanding.
The reason why Christianity is an accepted religion in this world is because it is a
spreader of Greek philosophy in the guise of the faith of the Hebrew scriptures.
People call on a Greek Messiah.
They use Greek philosophy.
When trying to teach our ways of morality, talking about things like the golden rule,
they use Greek philosophy to understand him and referring to the Trinity.
They reject the Torah and the commands of the most high.
They celebrate pagan holidays tied to the worship of the other pagan deities.
They rest on the first day, not the seventh.
I mean, I can keep going on and on.
Christianity is not a religion of the Hebrews.
It is a religion of the Greeks.
And the only way they were able to get the Hebrews to accept it was by taking our ancestors
in chains.
Enslaving them, wiping their memory clean for a couple hundred years, and then reteaching
to us through their foundation.
And the only way that we can learn about being a Christian is going through their theology
schools and their divinity schools.
People always ask me, what's his qualifications?
What divinity school did he go to?
What seminary training did he go to?
None of them.
And I'm free.
And because of this, we're almost at the end.
It is us who are waking up and rejecting these falsehoods and repenting from the sins
of our ancestors, whether natural branch or wild branch.
We are all turning back to Yahuwah in full truth and living the way he desires us to.
And it does not come through this false phony religion that is a religion of tares.
From this, you now have a foundation of the Greek philosophers, and you know more than
pretty much all these other Christians that are speaking as if they know the truth.
Anyone that feels they know the truth needs to be giving you an explanation about why
they feel Greek philosophy should be intertwined in Christianity.
This now gives you a great deal of understanding about this world, and now that you understand
how Greek philosophy was created.
And who the philosophers were, you need to understand how it was spread, and that brings
us to Alexander the Great and Hellenization.
All of this is leading you to understand truly what Christianity is, because most people
just don't truly know.
So in the next part, we will discuss Hellenization and Alexander the Great, and you will understand
how the Romans took over Greek culture.
From there, we will go back to after Christianity was created and read about Plato and Socrates
and how they intertwined into this faith of Christianity that the world holds on to.
So deep, and how they were used to create the doctrine of the Trinity.
All this goes back to them.
I appreciate all of your patience as you wait for me to bring all this out.
All of this is foundational.
If I do not explain all of this, there can be no real understanding, and this is why
people are so confused, because people want me to skip over to the answer without explaining
the foundation of how we got to that whole question.
So I'll get there.
Thank you for your patience with me.
In the meantime, please remember that Christianity is a religion that,
on its surface, seems biblical.
But when you dig deep into the doctrines, it is not a doctrine of service to our Father,
but a doctrine of abusing grace, editing covenants, rejecting the way our Father actually
chose to reach humanity, and making it only be about the way Christians want to receive
Him.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our Father that He deserves.
And in the end, it does not prepare those who follow it to be ready for what our Father
plans to do in the last days.
If you desire to be ready for our Father, please be ready for what He plans to do in
Father and his plan for us, you must come out of this religion of tares and come to our Father in
truth. Please move to part 13 in this playlist and we will discuss Hellenization and Alexander
the Great. Click the link to the next video and let's talk some more. Be blessed. Hallelujah.
Praise Yah. Okay, thanks again for watching. If this has blessed you, please don't forget to like
this and share this with your family and your friends. This series should be seen by all who
claim Christianity. This video series is highly important for those trying to be ready for our
Father. This is part 12 of the series. Click the link or just move on to the next video in the
playlist. As always, I want to thank all of you who donate and contribute to this ministry.
This series would not be possible without your support. I thank you sincerely. Be blessed.
Okay, thanks again everyone for watching. See you in part 13. I love you all.