Okay, so you should be coming from part 12 of the series.
These videos are a part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is being presented.
If you have not watched from part 1, please stop this video and start back from video 1.
So, in the last part, part 12, we were introduced to the Greek philosophers who were the actual prophets to the Greeks.
The Hebrews, they had Jeremiah, Isaiah, and Ezekiel, men like that.
The Greeks, they had Socrates, philosophies, and hypotheses, bars. That's for my New Yorkers.
Anyways, the Greeks, they had these philosophers who were being used by Satan to create the mindset that would prepare the Roman world for the acceptance of the new religion Satan would create.
From the beginning of this series, I've explained that Christianity is a religion of tares that Satan planted.
Messiah himself gave this prophecy.
The tares were planted when Satan used these prophecies.
And he began to correlate the foundation that he laid with the prophets, like Socrates and Plato,
and he began to correlate their philosophy in with the faith that the Hebrews presented.
We've gone over much of this history extensively.
Now, the thing is that there is a missing link to understanding this,
and it comes from a lack of understanding how the culture of the Greeks was spread.
Many people do not understand Hellenization.
And in order that we understand how these tares were spread,
we must understand the history of how the culture of the Greeks made it into the Roman Empire.
We also need to speak about the set-apart culture of Yashareel, specifically the Yahudim, who were in Judea, who met the Messiah.
People assume that because the culture of the Greeks was the accepted way of the majority,
that the Hebrews were just supposed to accept it as well.
But this comes from a false way of understanding the Hebrews and the word itself.
Because they were not a part of the world, and they were the only ones taught to be set apart.
This is something that someone said to me in correspondence about the Yahudim,
accepting Greek culture.
This is what he said.
The Greek language was the lingua franca of that day.
The overwhelming majority of people under the Roman Empire, including Jews, spoke Greek.
This is not even much of a dispute.
There is a reason there is no Hebrew or Aramaic Bible prior to the early 4th century.
You seem to equate speaking Greek with being Greek.
Your understanding is lacking and flawed.
That is the equivalent to believing that Spanish-speaking people are Spanish,
or English-speaking people,
or English.
And for the most part, what he's saying is correct,
including with Jews speaking Greek, because there were.
But while he says my understanding is flawed,
there are obvious pieces to the puzzle that he does not see.
And I get it.
This is how people feel.
But when I show them quotes from historians like Josephus
that totally prove that their way of thinking is incorrect,
because Josephus himself,
he said that the Yahudim did not have a culture of learning the other languages of the world.
It was something that they frowned upon.
And when I show them these things,
and prove that their way of thinking is incorrect,
they ignore it and move on to something else.
There is a lack of understanding of history,
and more importantly, a lack of understanding of the set-apart culture of Yashorel,
and why they were the only people in this world
that were commanded by our father to reject this culture of the Greeks that was being spread,
and they rejected the ones who did assimilate.
Today, in our modern world,
people just want to make assumptions that because Greek was overly accepted,
that it just makes sense,
that the Yahudim did this.
And when you feel this way,
it shows that you're missing an important understanding about our father
and the way that he led his people.
In another correspondence,
someone said to me,
God has gone by different names at different times.
The supreme name we have been given for the time is Jesus,
which is the English rendering of the original Aesis from the Greek.
Why do you think Hebrew is some special language?
Again, this is how people feel,
and leaving out dealing with the other false notion
about our father having different languages,
different names,
which is another doctrine that leads to Satan,
because it's Satan that has many names.
The reason why the Hebrew language is special
is because this is the language of the people that he chose
and is in covenant with.
It's the only people he dwelled amongst and that he led personally.
It's the only language he wrote the commandments in.
It's the only language his people spoke.
They were a set-apart people called to not assimilate
and learn the ways of the other nations.
Hebrew is the language of creation,
as the book of Jubilees tells us.
I'll read it to you.
And Yahuwah Elohim said,
Open his mouth and his ears,
that he may hear and speak with his mouth
with the language which has been revealed.
For it had ceased from the mouths of all the children of men
from the day of the overthrow of Babel.
And I opened his mouth and his ears and his lips,
and I began to speak with him in Hebrew,
in the tongue of creation.
And he took the sepharim of his fathers,
and these were written in Hebrew.
And he transcribed them,
and he began from henceforth to study them.
And I made known to him that which he could not understand,
and he studied them during the six rainy months.
And it came to pass in the seventh year of the sixth week
that he spoke to his father and informed him
that he would leave Haran to go into the land of Canaan
to see it and return to him.
That's Jubilees chapter 12, verses 25 through 28.
And this is talking about Abraham right here.
You see, Hebrew is the language of creation.
And scriptures like these,
are the reason why these books were decided
to not be put into our Bibles,
because people will know this.
Anyways, the point is that the Yahudim
did not assimilate with the Greeks.
Well, I'm speaking about the ones in Judea.
But if you do not know this history,
you will not understand this.
So it must be brought out.
So now that we know about the foundation of the Greeks
from the Greek philosophers,
we need to understand how this culture was spread later.
And the understanding of this
comes through understanding Hellenization.
So, what is Hellenization?
This is an important word and concept
that must not be forgotten,
because it is the main strategy of the enemy.
Hellenization is the adoption of Greek culture,
religion, language, and identity by non-Greeks.
Again, this understanding should not be glossed over.
Let me clarify Hellenization.
In referencing about the Hellenistic Age,
I will read from the Encyclopedia Britannica.
The Hellenistic Age in the Eastern Mediterranean
and Middle East,
the period between the death of Alexander the Great
in 323 BC
and the conquest of Egypt by Rome in 30 BC.
For some purposes, the period is extended
for a further three and a half centuries
to the move by Constantine the Great
of his capital to Constantinople, Byzantium, in 330 CE.
From the breakup of Alexander's empire,
there arose numerous realms,
including the Macedonian, the Seleucid, and the Ptolemaic,
that served as the framework for the spread
of Greek-Hellenic culture,
the mixture of Greek with other populations,
and the fusion of Greek and Eastern elements.
Okay, that's a lot of words.
But in summary, this is explaining
that the time period of this promotion of Greek culture,
language, and lifestyle,
which is called the Hellenistic Age,
was from 323 BC all the way to 330 AD,
basically spanning almost 600 years.
And this was merging Greek culture
in with the other populations of the world.
And this was merging Greek culture in with the other populations of the world.
So this brings us back to Greece.
In the second half of the fourth century,
the Macedonians, these were Greeks.
They were a diverse group of people living in northern Greece.
Their ruler, King Philip II, marched through the Greek peninsula.
If you remember in part 12, Athens and Sparta were divided
because of the Peloponnesian War.
But they were now united, even if it was against their will.
In 336 BC, when Greek unity was completed,
King Philip was murdered.
Then, his 20-year-old son, Alexander,
even though it was him that was under suspicion
of being the engineer of his father's death,
he replaced him.
This son is who we know as Alexander the Great.
Now, many of the Greek city-states
show little enthusiasm for Alexander's rule.
The animosity between the Macedonians and the Greeks
was so intense that some Greeks refused to participate
in Alexander's army of conquest.
Let's talk about Alexander.
So Alexander, he was a student of Aristotle,
and was said to display remarkable military skills.
His Macedonian Greek army conquered Asia Minor,
Egypt, Syria, Babylon, and Persia.
Alexander began to adopt Persian ways,
including a demand that he was to be worshipped as divine,
something many of his soldiers found repulsive.
In 323 BC, Alexander came down with a fever,
and within a short time, he died.
He was 33 years old.
His death threw the conquered territories into chaos.
You see, Alexander had plundered the Persian Empire,
Asia Minor, and Egypt.
But other than placing Macedonians
in charge of existing governments,
he did little to bring any central organization
to the conquered territories.
He just left them.
Alexander left his mark on every area he conquered, though.
Throughout his empire, him and his successors,
they constructed new cities or modified existing ones
to conform to a Greek model.
In these cities, Greek architecture, religion,
athletics, and culture were introduced to the population.
A number of Greek cities sprang up along the Mediterranean coast
of Judea and in Samaria.
Alexandria on the Egyptian coast would eventually become
the home of the ancient world's greatest library
until it was burned down by the Romans.
Okay, understand this about Alexander.
Alexander, he was a great conqueror,
not just because he took control of vast amounts of land,
but it was his method of control of these lands
that was special.
For instance, Egypt welcomed him as a liberator
because they hated Persian rule.
They placed Alexander on the throne of the pharaohs,
giving him the crown of Upper and Lower Egypt,
and named him the incarnation of Ra and Osiris.
This is when he set in motion the plans
for the second-largest city in Egypt named after him,
Alexandria.
Alexander's conquest introduced Greek culture
into the eastern Mediterranean world.
His rule introduced
Hellenism.
Again, Hellenism is the adoption of Greek culture,
religion, language, and identity by non-Greeks.
It's making non-Greeks, Greeks.
And this is why Alexander's rule was so unparalleled.
So because, though he conquered these civilizations,
he left the country to the people,
what he did mostly was import his Greek culture.
Cities such as Alexandria and Egypt
became influential centers of Greek learning.
This could be compared to, let's say, America
over a country, let's say Iraq.
And they left the government to themselves,
and let the Iraqis control the government.
But they started bringing in their shopping malls,
their movies, their churches,
their way of life.
Everything about the American way of life,
they brought it to Iraq.
Now, Iraq is still running the same,
but all of a sudden they start being,
living like Americans.
This is how Hellenism works.
It's the strategy of just bringing in the culture
and making people Greeks.
Let's keep going.
So like I said, Alexander died 323 BC.
His empire was divided among several of his generals.
One of these, named Seleucus,
took control of much of the old Persian Empire,
a territory we know as Asia Minor,
modern Turkey, and Syria.
Another named Ptolemy, he governed Egypt.
It's said that he hijacked Alexander's corpse
and used it as proof of his succession
and seized Egypt.
These two generals established the Seleucid
and Ptolemaic dynasties.
This was not a peaceful period for them.
But the spread of Greek culture persisted in society
since this period, and never stopped.
The Macedonian rulers promoted Greek language
and customs in the areas under their control,
exposing literate people from diverse cultures
to the philosophies of Socrates, Plato, and Aristotle.
One ideal that they did not spread,
since it would undermine their power,
was Athenian democracy.
That did not come through in those lands.
For nearly 300 years,
the lands conquered by Alexander
would be embroiled in warfare
between the competing Macedonian Greek dynasties
of the Seleucid and Ptolemaic dynasties.
And from this later,
came the takeover by the Romans.
Okay.
You should know,
the Roman culture is not Roman culture.
It is a continuance of Greek culture,
just with the Romans in control of it.
And as history continued to go forth throughout the world,
our culture today is still built upon
the same Greek influence that the Romans took over.
But let's keep going talking about the Greeks.
Because the Grecian Empire was split,
a new power was rising over the Mediterranean.
Eventually, the Romans came sweeping over the Greeks
in a series of second century BC wars.
The Romans,
they plundered every piece of Greek art and sculpture
that they could find.
Rome basically conquered the Greeks,
but took their culture as their own,
and they continued with the process
of Hellenization.
So even though it was not their culture,
they continued to spread the Greek culture.
Roman architecture,
art,
literature,
and religion,
all of it amongst the Romans,
showed influence by the Greeks.
It was all from the Greeks,
but under the banner of the Romans.
The Romans' upper-class families
imported Greek tutors to teach their children.
Some Romans sent their young men to Athens
to further their education in philosophy,
arts,
and science.
The Romans took over the culture of the Greeks.
You must understand that.
Now, I really want you to understand this.
And to do this,
we need to go back.
Go back to the book of Genesis.
In the beginning,
what did Satan try to do
to rebel against our father?
Let's read it.
And they said,
Come,
let us build ourselves a city
and a tower whose top is in the heavens.
Let us make a name for ourselves,
lest we be scattered abroad
over the face of the whole earth.
But Yahuwah came down
to see the city
and the tower which the sons of men had built.
And Yahuwah has said,
Indeed,
the people are one
and they all have one language,
and this is what they begin to do.
Now nothing that they propose to do
will be withheld from them.
Come,
let us go down
and there confuse their language,
that they may not understand
one another's speech.
So Yahuwah scattered them abroad
from there
over the face of all the earth,
and they ceased building the city.
And that's found in Genesis chapter 11
verses 4 through 8.
You see,
it was the goal of Satan
to rebel against Yahuwah
through the people
coming together under one tongue
to collectively work in rebellion.
That was Satan's goal.
Now after Yah confounded their language
and dealt with them,
do you believe that Satan
just abandoned that goal
and said,
I'm never going to do that again?
Absolutely not.
We see it today with English.
It's the culture being used
in the same way it was used in Babylon.
English today could be considered
the language of the world.
It's the most well-known language
amongst the world population.
Anyways,
the point I'm making is
that it's Satan's goal
to spread his ways
and unite men under it
to rebel against our father.
And so after he established himself
centuries earlier
with his prophets,
the Greek philosophers,
after the religion was set,
he then set in motion
the events that would spread his culture,
which is why a wicked empire
like the Romans
didn't feel the need to change
the culture of the Greeks.
They just said
that they would do a better job
of spreading it.
And so they just took control of it
and spread it further.
And the major understanding
that is not known
is that this process of Hellenization
has never stopped.
And one main way of spreading it
is through the religion of Christianity.
You see, understand this.
Christians are Hellenized disciples
spreading the culture of the Greeks
in the guise of their religion.
They argue all day
about the culture of the Greeks.
They say Jesus is our Messiah's name,
even though they know
that that's not true.
They protect the language
and the culture of the Greeks
at all costs,
and they don't want to hear
about the set-apart, holy way
our Father led his chosen people.
It's all because of Hellenization.
And if you're looking at the world
through the eyes of the Greeks,
it's because you have been Hellenized
and indoctrinated
on the side of the enemy.
The basis for the Greek association
with the people of Yasharel
is the claim that the New Testament
was written in Greek,
which we know is not true
because the early church fathers themselves
tell us that the first book of the Gospel,
the book of Matthew,
it was written in Hebrew.
The actual truth is that
it's not that the New Testament
was written in Greek,
but that there are no more
original manuscripts
and the only manuscripts we have
are written in Greek.
That's a very different thing.
But because of this claim,
people have chosen to accept Hellenization
instead of rejecting it.
What you have seen in my videos
with using our Father and Messiah's true name
and rejecting many churches,
traditions of the Greek culture,
is me rejecting Hellenization.
And so that is the main difference
that you will find with this ministry.
And while you say,
why do you use these names
and why do you always speak about the Hebrews?
It's because I reject Hellenization.
And the major difference
that you see with everyone else
is that they don't.
They accept Hellenization
and they spread Hellenization
because Christianity is a religion
of the Hellenized Greeks
and Christians are just disciples
of Hellenization.
You see,
Hellenization has never stopped,
as I said earlier.
To this day in America,
it is a major part of American society.
Like, of course,
look at the architecture
of the United States.
Why do you think it's built like that?
Many public buildings in the United States,
including the United States Capitol,
incorporate elements
of classical Greek architecture,
such as columns and pediments.
People like to say,
oh, it's built like the Romans.
No, it's actually built like the Greeks.
Why do you think
that they use that architecture?
It is all an embrace
of the mystery religions
and satanic goals
that are hidden
within their secret societies.
Satan is all in the midst of this all.
Satan is in the midst of this world
and it should be understood
that Greek culture
is the culture of Satan.
And as the world embraces it
and tries to attach to our Father
through the Greeks,
they are not recognizing
that they are embracing satanic culture.
I just said a lot,
so I'm going to repeat it.
I'm going to repeat it slow.
Satan is in the midst
of this world
and it should be understood
that Greek culture
is the culture of Satan.
And as the world embraces it
and tries to attach to our Father
through the way of the Greeks,
they are not embracing our Father,
but they are embracing satanic culture
that leads to Satan.
Many people will say,
well, God created all languages
when he confused them at Babel.
And yes, he did this, yes.
But that does not mean
that they were created
in a way to serve him.
That's why it's important
to read your whole Bible,
because if you read your whole Bible
from the beginning,
you will know that he dealt
with no other nation.
These people,
they never desired to serve Yah.
Yahweh, he just made it more difficult
for them to rebel against him.
That's all.
Satan has worked continuously
through the centuries,
slowly,
to bring the world back
to the goal of Babel.
And he's used these empires
like the Greeks,
the Romans,
the English,
all to do so.
Look at the influence of Hellenism
in our world today.
Our sporting contests
are all from Greek culture.
Sports like basketball and football,
though they may not be Greek games,
the sports competitions
are all a part of Greek culture.
The origin of soccer itself,
the football,
what they call it around the world,
its origins can be traced
to ancient Greece.
The Greeks believed that competition,
or agon,
was a fundamental part of life
and was expressed
in many aspects of Greek culture,
including sports,
music,
drama,
politics,
and culture.
And I'm not saying
that you're evil for playing sports
or that you're a Greek
for playing sports.
I just want you to know
where these cultures come from.
If you understand
how these cultures
have been passed down,
you can understand more
about the world
that you live in.
The Greek theater
was a major part
of Greek life.
Our practice of medicine
is influenced by the Greeks.
I mean,
just look at our education system.
The concept
of a formal graduation ceremony
with its emphasis
on academic achievement,
a symbolic rite of passage,
and the presentation
of a diploma
draw a significant influence
from the ancient Greece,
where education
was highly valued
and marked
by public recognition
of a student's completion
of studies.
The word diploma
comes from the Greek.
It means
double-folded paper.
Our culture
comes from the Greeks.
My point
is that there is
a great deal
of culture
that comes from the Greeks
that is still
in our modern world today.
We are Hellenized.
The whole government system
of democracy
comes from the Greeks.
And this government
system
is spread
all over the world.
Elections
plus a focused
foreign policy effort
that helps build
the institutions
of democracy
is what is going
to be necessary
to ultimately defeat
the hateful ideology
of those
who would do
our country harm.
So let us remember
that this is
a season of progress.
For the first time
in decades,
Tunisians,
Egyptians,
and Libyans
voted for new leaders
in elections
that were credible,
competitive,
and fair.
This democratic spirit
has not been
restricted
to the Arab world.
Over the past year,
we've seen peaceful
transitions of power
in Malawi
and Senegal
and a new president
in Somalia.
In Burma,
a president
has freed
political prisoners
and opened
a closed society.
A courageous
dissident
has been elected
to parliament.
And people
look forward
to further reform.
Around the globe,
people are making
their voices heard,
insisting
on their innate dignity
and the right
to determine
their future.
The turmoil
of recent weeks
reminds us
that the path
to democracy
does not end
with the casting
of a ballot.
What I'm trying
to say
is that the Greeks
did not mean
to run the world
by governing
over it.
They meant
to run the world
by spreading
its culture
and making the nations
live through
Greek culture.
And by making it
live through
Greek culture,
being that the foundation
of the Greek culture
was led through
the mystery religions,
it has never
gone away.
I'm just listing
out things
that are very easy
to see.
And so if you're able
to understand
how deep this goal
of Hellenization is
and then understand
that Christianity
is also a part
of that influence,
you can understand
the problem.
And this is why Christianity
is the major religion
of the world
because it spreads
Hellenization.
I really want you
to think about it.
It's why we want
to adapt
to a Greek savior
instead of a Hebrew one.
Our Messiah
was never named
Jesus.
He was Hebrew.
There was nothing
Greek about him.
It's all a part
of the same influence.
And listen,
though all of this
is important,
the major influence
that's overlooked
and that should not be
is the influence
on our mind
and the influence
of how we think.
And we can't
understand that
until we understand
the spread
of Greek philosophy.
And if you understand
this influence
from the beginning,
it will help you
understand
the mindset
of the Roman pagan converts
when they took control
of the faith
that came
from the Hebrews.
The Hebrews,
they were to apply
what was told to them.
The Greeks used
reason and logic,
saying,
well,
if it says this,
then it means this.
And if that means that,
then this must mean this.
And this is Greek reasoning.
It's logic.
It is the culture
of the Greeks.
And this is what goes
on with most major
false doctrines
in Christianity.
It's because of reasoning.
It's not because
the doctrine says this.
It's because people
hear this
and then they make
another reasoning and logic
that goes in
this whole big
logic puzzle
that leads to
a false doctrine.
And if you don't understand
that this comes
from the Greek mindset
of logic and reasoning
and not from the Hebrew mindset
that you read about
in the scriptures
from the beginning,
this is where confusion
comes from.
But this may be hard
to understand
if you don't understand
the actual culture
of the Hebrews.
So understand this.
There was only one nation
of people
that truly resisted
Hellenization.
And that was
the Yahudim
in Judea
So as I said,
Ptolemy took over Egypt
and shortly after that
in 320 BC
he went to Judea
to claim it as well.
It's said that
he anticipated
some difficulty
but to his surprise
the Yahudim
did not make
the slightest effort
to defend themselves.
Why?
Because they went
on the Sabbath.
You see to the Greeks
the idea of the Sabbath
was unknown
and they didn't
understand it.
To them it seemed
ridiculous for people
to not defend themselves
at all times.
They went
and they looked
at the Yahudim
as foolish people.
According to Josephus
Ptolemy
showed kindness
to the Yahudim.
According to the testimony
of Hecataeus
of Abdera
whom Josephus
cites in his work
against Apion
because of Ptolemy's
kindness
many Yahudim
felt impelled
to move to Egypt
and it's said
that in 311 BC
the high priest
Hezekiah
went with Ptolemy
to Egypt.
You see
there were many
Yahudim
who were in search
of new opportunities
and they chose
to leave their
homeland.
So slowly
Yahudim settlements
grew up along the coast
of the Mediterranean
on the islands of Greece
and even along the shores
of the Black Sea.
And this is when
you begin to see
the diaspora
of the Yahudim
being spread.
Because these Yahudim
left their homeland
and they were being
separated from their people
in a new land
these Yahudim
began to adapt
to Hellenization.
They learned
Greek language
and adopted
some Greek customs
and ideas.
One great example
of this
is what happened
in Alexandria
in Egypt.
Dealing with Alexandria
Alexander
he planned
and his successor
Ptolemy
he continued
to build Alexandria
as a commercial port.
In a very short time
this port of Alexandria
became one
of the most active
commercial centers
of the world.
And you did not need
to force anyone
to settle there
people came on their own.
This is what all
the business was.
The Yahudim
they spread there
and became
an important part
of the community
of Alexandria.
Now listen
to be a citizen
in a Greek city
it involved
to some extent
the matter of religion.
You see
each city
had its protecting
patron,
god or goddess.
Patriotic festivals
and even games of sport
of which Greeks
were very fond of
they were bound up
with sacrifices
to those pagan gods.
So obviously
the Yahudim
knew
they could not
take part
in any of these activities
and they excluded
themselves
from full citizenship.
But they could not
be called foreigners
for a great help
and great influence
in making Alexandria
what it was
under Ptolemy.
They had a great
influence there.
The first Ptolemies
understood all of that
and they permitted
these Yahudim
to organize
a separate community
within Alexandria.
And this is what
the Yahudim did
all over the world
as you see them spread out.
They had
Yahudim quarters.
They had their own
courts of law
and conducted themselves
under their Torah.
They built
their own communities
amongst their people
because of the need
of complying
and the desire
to be near
their synagogues.
And this is how
the synagogues began
to be spread
around Asia Minor
and Greece
which is where
Paul, Peter,
the Apostles
how they began
to spread
the good news.
It's all part
of the same history.
Now get this.
This was all
in the beginning
of the spread
of Hellenization.
But as the role
of Greece spread
in the world
and people became
more accepting
of Greek culture
in Alexandria
the time came
when Greece itself
and the Yahudim
began to adapt
and become
influenced
by the Greeks.
They began
to learn
the Greek language
began to admire
the Greek culture
but they insisted
on remaining
Yahudim
meaning living
by their Torah.
You see
the first generation
did not understand
much Greek.
Perhaps
the next generation
understood
both Hebrew
and Greek.
The third generation
understood
very little Hebrew.
Their native tongue
was now Greek.
They accepted
Greek books
and accepted
Greek ideas.
They could not
read Hebrew
and this was a problem
for many that still
did not want
to completely
walk away
from their faith.
So they encouraged
their children
to study the Hebrew language
so that they might
be able to become
acquainted with the ideas
of the Yahudim
in their original way.
So what they did
is they translated
the Torah
the five books
of Moses
in Greek
and it's called
the Pentateuch
simply meaning
which means
the 70
and because
70 learned scribes
were a part
of this translation
the Pentateuch
was called
the Septuagint
which means
the 70
and so these
assimilated
Yahudim
began to merge
with the Greeks
and this is where
the confusion
and the trouble
began.
There's a lot more
to this history
but it does not matter
honestly.
Now what happened
in Alexandria
can provide
understanding
for us
in the future.
On every side
of Judea
old cities
that used to
call themselves
Ammonite
or Syrian
or Philistine
assumed new Greek names
and practiced
the Greek way of life.
Everything began
to adapt
to the way
of the Greeks.
Hellenization
was ruling.
Even their old gods
were given
Greek names.
The Yahudim
were surrounded
by a changing world
that was all
becoming Greeks.
Those who took
part in this
as trade began
to open markets.
So if you took
part in this
Greek culture
and this Greek
way of life
you began to prosper
because you were trading
with everybody else.
It was the way of life.
The Yahudim
in Judea
they did trade
but they could not
keep up with that
of their neighbors
who actually truly
adjusted and assimilated.
And this is the way
that they got left behind.
And for this reason
is the reason why
many Yahudim
began to scatter
around Greece
and Asia Minor.
Now as we move
into the times
there is a period
that's not spoken about
in great detail
and you see
the lack of people
understanding the history
surrounding this
is a reason
why there is so much
confusion today
about things spoken about
in the New Testament.
For instance
the many times
Paul speaks
about the Greeks
because this history
is not known
people believe
that Paul is speaking
about these same Greeks
that were aspired
by these Greek philosophers.
Many people
don't understand
the history
and the rejection
that the Yahudim
had for the Greeks.
And so
I will continue
to cover this topic
next so that
there can be no confusion
and as I continue
to present my case
about Christianity
I will continue
to provide
more understanding.
We have to understand
the history
that they have kept
from us
and it's not like
this history is hidden
it's just not taught
and after you understand
the history
then you can understand
why they keep
this history from us.
So what we're going
to do next
is we're going
to understand
the Maccabean Revolt
and what took place
a century and a half
ago.
So that's what
we're going
to cover next
as we move
through understanding
Christianity.
In the meantime
please remember
Christianity
is a religion
that on the surface
seems biblical
but when you dig deep
into the doctrines
it is not a doctrine
of service to our Father
but a doctrine
of abusing grace
editing covenants
rejecting the way
our Father actually
chose to reach humanity
and making it
only be
about the way
Christians
want to receive Him.
It lacks
the patience
and reverence
for our Father
that He deserves
and in the end
it does not prepare
those who follow it
to be ready
for what our Father
plans to do
in the last days.
If you desire
to be ready
for our Father
and His plan for us
you must come out
of this religion
of tares
and come to our Father
in truth.
Please move
to part 14
in this playlist
and we will discuss
the Maccabean Revolt.
Click the link
to the next video
and let's talk
some more.
Hallelujah.
Praise
Yah.
Okay.
Thanks again
for watching.
If this has blessed you
please like this
and share this
with your family
and your friends.
This video series
is highly important
for those trying
to be ready
for our Father.
This is part 13
of this series.
Click this link
or just move on
to the next video
in the playlist.
As always
I want to thank
all who donate
and contribute
to this ministry.
All this is made
possible
because of you.
Okay.
Thanks again everyone
for watching.
See you in part 14.
I love you all.