Okay so you should be coming from part 13 of the series. These videos are part of a topical series
and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is being
presented. So please if you have not watched from part one please stop this video and start back
from video one. Okay so in the last video part 13 we went over the period of the start of
Hellenization with Alexander the Great. Many people want to look at that period as the time
of Hellenization and that would not be a wrong assessment but what that does is it does not allow
us to know that we are still in that period of Hellenization. The culture of the Greeks it's
still being spread except that it just evolves through our modern culture and though we are
under the influence of different empires from the Romans to Masonic England the culture of the
Greeks has never stopped being spread. Yes the culture of men changes with time but it's all
based upon the foundation of the way we are.
But here's the thing though the culture of the world evolves and changes the ways and law of
Yahuwah is never changing which is why Satan desperately wants us to reject it. Now in that
history as we began to go over Hellenization and how it affected the Yahudim I had to stop
because we were coming to a period where there was resistance to Hellenization and this was from
the Yahudim in Judea. This is a period of time that is very important to the world. You must
understand why we are still in that period of Hellenization. We are still in that period of
history. Without these events the Messiah would not have had people to come back to that would
follow him. Yahuwah used this time to preserve this people and it is a great deal of history
that provides an example of how we should be in this world and it's precisely why they did not
put the book of Maccabees in our Bible. Now I'm going to go over this history but in case you want
to study and research this on your own I want you to know the sources that I'm using which is from
the book of Maccabees as well as Solomon Grazel's book The History of the Jews and also Flavia's
Josephus' work from the Antiquities of the Jews. If you want to understand this history that I'm
sharing and research it for yourself these are my sources. Okay so let's deal with it. This video
is actually long overdue. As I explained in part 13 the third century BC was a wave of
Hellenization that was taking over the civilized world. Everything began to adapt to the ways of
the Greeks. Even their old gods were given Greek names. The Yahudim were surrounded by a changing
world. All becoming Greeks. Those who took part in this new Greek wave were taking part in a great
movement of prosperity as trade began to open new markets. The Yahudim in Judea they did trade but
they could not keep up with that of their neighbors who truly adjusted. You see the
Yahudim in Judea remained steadfast in their own faith and manner of living. They were not
attracted or enticed by the lewd lawless and cruel gods of Olympus. Looking at all the culture
of the world and the people of the world. Their land, their names, their bathhouses and their
festivals. The Yahudim saw lawlessness and immorality. The Yahudim who stayed in their land
of Judea never came in contact with the highest Greek civilizations like Athens. Not even with the
Greek culture from the surrounding areas like from Alexandria. And this point right here is extremely
important to understand but most people they just don't get it. Even if they had met the real Greek
culture and learned about the famous Greek philosophers and the poets. The Yahudim would still have rejected the
all of it as inferior to their culture of being Yahudim. Why? Because they know that they were
the only people in covenant with the Most High Yahuwah. The creator of all was in covenant with
them. Those who truly worshiped Yahuwah had no business following the ways of the other nations.
This was commanded by Yah to be holy and set apart. And so more than ever, the Yahudim,
they began to stick out and be different people from the rest of the other nations.
The rest of the world was becoming Hellenized and they were sticking to their culture.
Now, in regards to economics, based on what was going on in the world around them,
the Yahudim in Judea, at that time, they were considered peasants. Remember, they were
rebuilding. They only possessed one city worth mentioning, which was Jerusalem. The majority
of its population, the farmers, the small merchants, the artisans, they were all content
to remain as they were. They were good with their heritage. And like I said,
they had no business following the ways of the other nations. And so more than ever,
they had no desire to blend in with the outside world. Now, the devil did find his way up in there,
though. There were families of the upper classes in Jerusalem, the chief families among the priests
who lived in Jerusalem, and the exporters and the importers doing the trade, who were Judea's
great merchants. They associated with the upper classes of the other nations that surrounded them,
and they began to think in terms of economic prosperity. They wanted to make Jerusalem a
trading center. But this was impossible,
as long as the other people around the world looked at the people of Jerusalem as strange,
foreign, and barbarous savages. The upper class Yahudim, they didn't want to give up their faith.
They just wanted to make the Yahudim externally resemble the other nations around them.
They argued that dressing in Greek fashion, encouraging the young to play in Greek games,
or reorganizing the politics of Jerusalem to a Greek constitution would do no harm to their way
of life as Yahudim. And it might lead their nation to a new era. But they didn't want to
have their neighbors to look upon the Yahudim as people very much like themselves. They wanted
to blend in. Basically, they were trying to do the same thing that got them a king in 1 Samuel
in the first place. They were trying to be like the other nations. Now, it's said that the main
advocate of this Hellenization in Judea were members of a family which may have traced their
origin from Tobias the Ammonite, whom Nehemiah in his day had difficulties with. You can read
about this in Nehemiah chapter 13.
Now, this family, known as the Tobiads, for two centuries, though they were not originally
Yahudim, but they identified with the Yahudim and they intermingled with the family of the high
priests, they played an important role in the politics of the land. So basically, after they
came back to the land, some Gentiles intermingled with the Yahudim and they began to have influence
with the Yahudim. So about the year 230 BC, one of them, Joseph ben Tobias, brought from the
king of Egypt the right to collect the taxes from the entire district of Syria, which consisted
of Judea and all of its neighbors. Okay. So Joseph and his family took great advantage of this and
used the power that they gained and used it as an opportunity to permanently change the economic
position of Jerusalem by diverting trade to it from the other parts of the area. He was trying
to bring in new business, basically a new entrepreneur. And it was this power that brought
in the problems later to come. So understand,
something here. This is a very different time period from the times written in the Old Testament
and the times written in the New Testament. This history is not spoken of, but it is wildly
important to understand the context of the people who Yahushua came to, and then also how
the religion of Christianity began. And this brings us to the Maccabean Age. So the Maccabean
Age is something that is known today, but it's not overly taught. Just last week, everyone
celebrated Hanukkah, but most people don't even know what they're celebrating.
This is a period of time around 200 to 150 BC. Extremely important. Now remember,
the Greece empire was split between the Ptolemies and the Seleucids. During this time,
the Seleucids had an ambition of reuniting all of Alexander's conquest. By the year 198 BC,
Antiochus III, called the Great, he took the first step in that direction when he forced
Egypt to give up Palestine. Now, when the Seleucids tried to realize their ambitions
of reuniting the empire, one group of Yahudin, they favored the annexation of Judea, and
then another group wanted to remain part of the Egyptian empire with the Ptolemies. And
of course, Hyrcanus, son of Joseph ben Tobias, was on the side of Egypt because he was getting
the tax money. The thing, though, is that the common people of Judea, they did not care
because it made no difference to them whether it was the Ptolemies or the Seleucids taking
their tax. But as soon as their way that they worship Yah,
got involved, this is when things started to change and the common people began to take sides.
So, this is where things heat up. So, the side of the Yahudin who sided with the Seleucids,
the side of the Seleucids would also be known as Syrians. These Yahudin revealed to Seleucus IV
that much money belonging to his opponents in Egypt was stored in the temple. Seleucus,
being anxious to lay his hands on more money, sent out one of his officials, Heliodorus,
to confiscate the money.
Now, it's said that when Heliodorus went into the temple, he was confronted by a man
on horseback who had beaten him to within an inch of his life. Heliodorus was scarcely
able to leave and he left without taking any money.
And so, this pro-Seleucid group of the Yahudin, this was their first attempt to gain control
of Judea and it was defeated. But from this, there was a major rift because the Yahudin
saw how these Hellenized Yahudin would stop at nothing to achieve their goal of gaining control.
I mean, they sent Gentiles into the temple to rob it. It was crazy.
Now, Seleucus IV, he died and was succeeded by his brother Antiochus IV. And this is the
real problem one and the one written about in the book of Maccabees. Antiochus also desired
to conquer Egypt and reunite his empire. And he hoped to achieve this by means of attaching the
various provinces to himself as the embodiment of Greek culture. He gave himself the surname
Epiphanes, which means the god of the world. And he gave himself the surname Epiphanes,
which means the visible god. In other words, he was declaring that him and their god Jupiter
were to be considered identical.
Judea was important to Antiochus to have a loyal Hellenized population. But it didn't
matter because Judea was the one that made the least progress in Hellenization. They
resisted it. And so when a group of those sellout Hellenized Yahudin came to him with
a proposed plan to speed up Hellenization in Judea, Antiochus was eager to take part in it.
The plan was to remove the high priest that was already there and put in their Hellenized brother
in place. And then in return for a sum of money, Antiochus promised to grant Jerusalem a Greek
constitution and the right to coin money, which would help the city grow commercially.
This was all about business. Okay, so the plans were carried out and they replaced the high priest
with their sellout version. And the common people of the Yahudin were outraged. It was the first
exile that a non-Yahudin government had interfered in the succession to the high priesthood. This is
a major office, treating the office as if it were nothing more than ordinary governorship.
And worse than that, now that the Hellenized Yahudin had full control of Judea's government,
they began to build gymnasiums within Jerusalem in which young people were
encouraged to spend a great deal of time there. The young priests began to neglect their duties
in the temple in order to play sports. This new culture that was being introduced to the
people was distracting them. The Greek styles in dress, the Greek names, the Greek language became
stylish in Jerusalem. And worst of all, the Hellenized life brought looseness in their
application of the Torah, as well as the well-known looseness of morals of the Greeks.
Now listen, though things were changing to the sellout Yahudin, they were not changing fast
enough. They were trying to get their business going. The Hellenized Yahudin aligned to Syria,
they were not happy with the
pace of Hellenization, and they complained to Antiochus that Jason the high priest, the one
that they put in, he was not moving with enough purpose. They promised Antiochus an enormous sum
to appoint a radical Hellenist to the high priesthood. So this high priest Jason was forced
to flee, and this time they appointed Menelaus. Menelaus was not even a member of the high
priestly family. He was a man without sympathy or care for any of the Yahudin ways. He just desired
power.
Now to Antiochus, the way he saw it, the unwillingness and rejection of the Yahudin
to be Hellenized and come to the Greek culture, it was something that he couldn't comprehend.
Basically the nerve of these people to resist. And because he did not respect Yahuwah and the
Yahudin, he basically resolved that if it was the way of the Yahudin that stood in his way
of reuniting his Greek empire, the way of the Yahudin must be destroyed. And he gave the order
to destroy the culture and practice of the Yahudin and force them to be Greek.
He was outlawing the Torah. So he sent an army. A part of the Syrian army marched into Jerusalem
to support Menelaus and his policies. Many of the inhabitants were killed and others escaped to the
hills. This happened on the 25th of Kislev. Only the known Hellenists remained. Orders were given,
making it illegal to observe the Sabbath, the feast days, and circumcision. They forced them
to eat unclean meats like pork. In the temple of Yahuwah, they were forced to eat unclean meats
like pork. In the temple of Yahuwah, they were forced to eat unclean meats like pork. In the temple
of Yahuwah, they were forced to eat unclean meats like pork. In the temple of Yahuwah, they were forced
to eat unclean meats like pork. In the temple of Yahuwah, they were forced to eat unclean meats like pork.
Above the altar was placed a statue of Jupiter bearing an obvious resemblance to Antiochus.
They even brought pigs to be sacrificed on the altar before the statue,
straight up defiling the temple. The common people of Judea watched these things in horror.
They looked at it all as a result of the influence of Hellenism and the abandonment
of the principles of the Torah from the upper classes. Basically these upper class,
they abandoned the Torah and this is what happened after that. And so a group began
to emerge that resolved that there were only two courses that remained. Either they die fighting
or they die as martyrs. This group was known as Hasidim. They were the lower class among the
Yahudim and they were not organized as any army. They resolved that they could let themselves be
slaughtered for their ideals, but they could not lead in fighting for them. Now an interesting point
to note is that among the Revtunites are a group known as the Hasidics. Where I grew up in New York,
there were a bunch of them. They belonged to the Hasidic sect. They were a group of people who were
considered to belong to a special movement within Orthodox Judaism, a movement that, at its
height in the first half of the 19th century, they claimed the allegiance of millions in Eastern and
Central Europe. Perhaps a majority of the Eastern European Jews. They to this day wear traditional
clothing styles from the 18th century in Eastern Europe. For example, Hasidic men often wear black
coats and big furry hats. Hasidic women dress very modestly and cover their hair in public with a wig
on. This group have taken on this name from the Hasidim, but they would like people to believe
that they are this actual group that's been since the time of Maccabees. But no, this is a movement
that originated in Eastern Europe in the 18th century. And the craziest point is that the
founder of this movement, Rabbi Israel Ben Eliezer, a Jewish mystic, basically a practitioner of Kabbalah,
he is also known as Be'el Shem Tov, which is said to mean Master of the Temple.
The master of the good name. That is, one able to work miracles using the secret name of God.
The secret name of God. Listen, if you dig into who these people are, it truly exposes itself.
It's right in plain sight. So when you see them, know that they just are ones who took over the
name of this group of Yahudim who stood for the Torah. It's just another part of hijacking our
culture. And they want the world to believe that they are truly following Yah, but this group,
they're founded by those who practice Kabbalah. I thought that that was a good thing.
That would be an interesting point to share, but enough of that. Let's get back to the history.
And so when the way of the Yahudim was declared illegal and the soldiers of Antiochus
spread their net over Judea, those who persisted in being Yahudim and living
according to the Torah, the result for them was martyrdom. Men, women, and even children
gave their lives rather than violate the Torah. I'm going to read about it from the
Sefer in the book of Maccabees. And having subdued them, he established a decree that if
any of them lived according to the Torah of his country, he should die. And when he could by no
means destroy by his decrees the obedience to the Torah of the nation, but saw all his threats and
punishments without effect, for even women, because they continued to circumcise their
children, were flung down a precipice along with them, knowing beforehand of the punishment.
When therefore his decrees were disregarded by the people, he himself compelled by means of tortures
everyone of this race, by tasting forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden
meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by
eating forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by eating
forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, and by eating forbidden meat, to abjure
the Yahudic faith. Then, in the next chapter, the Greek Antiochus tortures a well-known old man
of Yehuda Eleazar, the priest. But in chapter 8, this is what really got me. Then, indeed,
vehemently, swayed with passion, he commanded to bring others of the adult Hebrew, and if they
would eat of the unclean thing, to let them go when they had eaten. But if they objected to torment
them more grievously. The tyrant, having given this charge, seven brethren were brought into his
presence, along with their aged mother, handsome, and modest, and well-born, and altogether comely.
Whom, when the tyrant beheld, encircling their mother as in a dance, he was pleased at them,
and being struck with their becoming an ingenuous mean, smiled upon them, and calling them near,
said, O youths, with favorable feelings, I admire the beauty of each of you, and greatly
honor so numerous abandoned brethren. I not only counsel you not to share the madness of the old
man who has been tortured before, but I do beg you to yield, and to enjoy my friendship. For I
possess the power, not only of punishing those who disobey my commands, but of doing good to
those who obey them. Put confidence in me, then, and you shall receive places of authority in my
government. If you forsake your national ordinance, and, conforming to the Greek mode of life,
alter your rule, and revel in youth's delights,
for if you provoke me by your disobedience, you will compel me to destroy you, everyone,
with terrible punishments by tortures. Have mercy, then, upon your own selves, whom I,
although an enemy, compassionate for your age and comeliness. Will you not reason upon this,
that if you disobey, there will be nothing left for you but to die in tortures? Thus speaking,
he ordered the instrument of torture to be brought forward, that very fear might prevail upon them
to eat unclean food. If you disobey, there will be nothing left for you but to die in tortures.
And when the spearmen brought forward the wheels, and the racks, and the hooks, and catapults,
and cauldrons, pans, and finger racks, and iron hands, and wedges, and bellows,
the tyrant continued. That's 4 Maccabees chapter 8 verses 1 through 12. And what happened was
that each one of them resisted, from the oldest child to the youngest child, all the way to the
mother. They all resisted not to eat pork and to go against their Torah. This is what they were about.
They all went down the line.
And dealt with the tortures so that they could stand for Yah. And this is what was happening to
the Yahudim. So as this was happening, thousands, they abandoned their homes as the news of the
Greek soldiers was coming to enforce the edict of the king. They knew they needed to get out of
there. They fled to the hills where they hid till the soldiers departed. And worse, the Hellenized
Yahudim began to snitch and inform the Greeks who the Hasidim were that were betraying the people
further. The Yahudim of Judea hated these Hellenized Yahudim. They were afraid of the
Hellenized Yahudim. Now the Hasidim did not put up a fight, and they died as martyrs. But many other
Yahudim put up a fight. They did not permit themselves to be slaughtered without resisting. But the
Hellenized Yahudim knew how to get around them. Because as long as they were under the influence of the
Hasidim, they would not defend themselves on the Sabbath. So the result was that these wicked Greeks
learned to wait until the Sabbath in order to attack these Yahudim and destroy them. The end of the
Yahudim was in sight.
Now, among the Yahudim were some peaceful farmers northwest of Jerusalem and a little town of
Modin. Among the most respected were the descendants of a priestly family called the Hasmonians. The head
of the family at this time of Antiochus was an aged Mattathias who had five sons, Simon, Eliezer,
Yehuda, Yohanan, and Yohanathan. Mattathias and his sons, they were increasingly dreadful
thinking about the time when the Greeks were going to come and deliver their royal edict.
And the moment soon came. In the marketplace of the little town of Modin, the Syrian soldiers
put up an altar. The men of Modin were assembled there. A pig was produced, which the soldiers
had brought with them. And Mattathias, as a priest and elder, was ordered to sacrifice it
to Jupiter in honor of Antiochus. Mattathias, he did not move. From out of the crowd, a young
Yahudim stepped forward, who, judging by his dress, he was a Hellenizer. He asked to perform the sacrifice.
There was no doubt what would happen next. The other Yahudim would be asked to eat some of the
sacrificial meat, and those who refused would be executed. So the sellout Yahudim, he approached
the animal. The soldiers were standing side by side on one side of the altar. The Yahudim stood
there watching the performance, and then suddenly everything changed and the entire scene was
transformed. The aged Mattathias, standing closest to the captain of the troops and to that sellout
Yahudim, he snatched the sword.
Out of the captain's hands and ran it through the body of the traitor. As the captain quickly
moved forward to stop him, Mattathias stabbed him too. Obviously, by impulse, his sons rushed
the other soldiers before they could even realize what happened. The other Yahudim ran
to aid them, and the soldiers were killed and their altar completely destroyed. Mattathias
says, whoever is for Yahuwah, let him come unto me. The call echoed over the land, across
the hills of Judea and in the caves, wherever the Hasidim were hiding. Mattathias and the
rest of the people of Modin were themselves compelled to abandon their homes in the face of
larger forces of Syrians that would come to avenge the death of the first group. They needed to go.
But they didn't go just to hide. They regrouped and formed a strategy. The band of Mattathias
began to attack small troops of soldiers or communities in which the Hellenist
Yahudim were strong. And the Yahudim rallied behind Mattathias in hopes to preserve themselves.
Eventually, living in the hills, it became too much for old Mattathias.
Before a year was up, around 167 BC, he died. The leadership went to his son,
Yehudah, who distinguished himself above all the others. And for some reason, he acquired
the surname Maccabee. Some say it derived from Maccabet, the Hebrew word for hammer.
Either way, under Yehudah's leadership, the Yahudim began to win against the Syrians.
This Maccabean army, they were a small army in number, but mighty in power and quality.
In time, as the size of the forces
increased, Yehudah Maccabee, he felt emboldened to measure his strength with the other larger groups
of the enemy. And so he went right at them. The local Syrian commanders, they gathered their
forces, including the Hellenized Yahudim. And each time they thought that they had Yehudah and
his camp cornered, the Maccabeans prevailed. Now, Antiochus, he realized he had a full-size
rebellion on his hands in this province. It was obviously necessary for him to suppress it.
Fortunately for the Yahudim, at that same time,
the Syrians in the northeast, they also rebelled against Antiochus and sought independence from
the Seleucid Empire. Antiochus hurried off to fight them. He appointed a general by the name
of Lysias. He gave him full power to stamp out the Judean revolt. Now, like those before him,
Lysias underestimated the strength of the Maccabean forces. Instead of sending a full
army to crush the rebellion in Judea, he dispatched two subordinates, smaller groups.
Yehudah, he was familiar with the country,
and the mountain, and was able to surprise and annihilate the Syrians in the dead of night.
This was called the Battle of Amos. And the great result of this victory was that the road was now
open to Jerusalem. In high spirits with songs of praise, hallelujah on their lips, the Maccabean
army approached the sacred city which had been in the hands of the enemy for almost three years.
The high priest Menelas, the Hellenizing Yahudim, and the new pagan residents? They fled from
Jerusalem just three years from when they first started to live in Jerusalem. They fled from the
city of Bethlehem, who initially served there for more than nine years. The simple
peasants, whom the love of Yahud and their freedom had turned them into soldiers, now dropped the
sword in order to do what they had been fighting for—cleansing the Temple and reestablishing their
worship. They removed every sign of paganism. They took part of the altar which had been
defied by pagan sacrifices, and put aside its stones. They erected a new altar in its place.
Exactly three years after the desolated abomination had been introduced into the Temple,
They destroyed the statue of Zeus and Tychus into dust
and rededicated the temple to the worship of Yahuwah.
Beginning on the 25th of Kislev in 165 BC,
they celebrated the dedication feast for eight days,
which is why it's called the Feast of Dedication,
what we all know as Hanukkah.
And from this victory,
the Yahudim were able to preserve their way of life,
their worship of Yahuwah,
and continue to live how they were called to,
Baya.
We even see Yahusha celebrate this in John chapter 10.
It says,
And it was at Jerusalem the Feast of Hanukkah,
and it was winter,
and Yahusha walked in the temple in Solomon's porch.
That's John chapter 10, verses 22 and 23.
You see, many people don't understand the celebration of Hanukkah.
And for me, as I'm relearning our heritage,
I am relearning this time as well,
because I don't want to do it in any way that the current Rev 2 Nines do it.
So I'm relearning this myself.
But I do understand the reason for the celebration.
And now, if you understand this history that we just went through,
I hope you understand it now as well.
You see, three years earlier,
the Yahudim were killed,
and the temple was desecrated
and made unholy by Antiochus and the Greeks.
Three years to the day after it happened,
the Yahudim who revolted won back their freedom to worship Yahuwah,
and through the power of Yahuwah,
they rededicated the temple and recommitted themselves to Yahuwah.
And if this did not happen,
we would not have been able to have our Messiah,
come and fulfill prophecy.
It all leads to Messiah because without this event,
the Yahudim, they would have been fully assimilated into the Greeks,
very much how it is today.
Antiochus wanted to wipe them off.
He wanted to get rid of all worship of Yah and remove them all.
Because of their commitment to Yah,
they did not allow this to happen.
And this is exactly why they kept this out of the book.
They recommitted themselves to Yahuwah and rededicated the temple that was
desecrated back to Yahuwah.
And this is what is celebrated.
This is not the worship of Yahudim.
This is not the worship of gods,
but a celebration of rededicating themselves back to Yahuwah.
Again, without this event,
Yahushua, he would not have had a place to come back to,
and his ministry would not be possible.
Yahuwah used the smallest people that truly loved him,
and he gave them power to defeat a great foe.
When you read about this in the Sefer,
you can see why they removed these books from our Bibles,
because this history can provide us a great deal of influence for us.
I know whenever I read it, I get revved up.
We know that if we serve Yah,
nothing can come against us, and we win.
We know that our people took great sacrifices to live according to the Torah
that the majority of people today want to say it doesn't matter.
We know that the history of the Hellenized Yahudim
is something that's not truly understood,
because we only know about it from a Hellenized point of view.
We only look at the Hellenized Yahudim scattered around Asia Minor,
but we don't look at it from the people that were actually in Judea
that were there when Messiah walked the earth.
They hated these Hellenized Yahudim.
These Hellenized Yahudim, they were not respected,
and they were hated, and they called them Greeks and Gentiles
because they did not associate them with the Yahudim any longer.
You see, when you remove this history,
it allows other people to create other doctrines
and not truly understand the times that followed
when the good news of Messiah began to be spread.
The Hellenized culture was a problem for the Yahudim,
and if allowed, it would have replaced them
and removed the Yahudim
and the potential for Bible prophecy to be fulfilled.
But these events are one of the reasons why we're here.
Or why we are here talking about Yahushua,
and we are blessed by him.
Without understanding this history,
it's why people can embrace Hellenization
and act as if the blending and assimilating with the Greeks
was something that was accepted.
Do you realize what they went through over this Hellenization?
People were killed.
I mean, it was just really bad.
Imagine China taking over the United States,
and hundreds of years later,
you're learning about American history
from the point of view of the Chinese.
This is how people treat the Bible.
Yes.
Of course, among the Yahudim, there were sellouts,
and they tried to enforce the selling out
and spread the selling out.
But the true people, guarded by Yahuwah,
did not allow this culture of Hellenization to go forth.
And so for us, we should have no tolerance for Hellenization
because Hellenization was only put forth
in order to push away the Torah
and the influence of Yah's people.
And it still is being used in the same way today.
It's just that the Hellenists are in the abundance,
and they are uneducated and indoctrinated,
and they don't even know
that they're Hellenists.
Christians are the Hellenists of our modern day,
and their movements seek to do the same thing
as the Greeks of the time of Maccabees.
It's why they're called Christians and not Messianists.
They identify with Christos of the Greeks
and not the Messiah of the Hebrews.
They adapt to the ways of the Greeks.
Now, there's a lot more to say about this,
but I wanted to make sure I covered this
because as we discuss Christianity,
if you have no context of what happened before Messiah came,
there are certain things you will not understand later.
And this is why there's so much confusion today
because this history is just not taught.
So now that this is understood,
there should be a clear understanding
of the separation there is
between the Greeks and the Yahudim.
And it should be understood
why there is a rejection of merging Greek culture
in with the faith of Yashareel.
If you don't get it by now, you don't want to.
The Yahudim fought a major war
to reject the spread of Hellenization.
They hated the Greeks,
and that's why they rejected the Hellenized Yahudim
all around Asia Minor.
And if you need proof,
for that, let me show you.
Remember when Yahushua said he will go to a place
that they cannot follow?
Let's go to John chapter seven.
It says,
Then Yahushua said to them,
I shall be with you a little while longer,
and then I go to him who sent me.
You will seek me and not find me,
and where I am, you cannot come.
Then the Yahudim said among themselves,
where does he intend to go that we shall not find him?
Does he intend to go to the dispersion among the Greeks
and teach the Greeks?
What is this thing?
That he said, you will seek me and not find me,
and where I am, you cannot come.
That's John chapter seven, verses 33 through 36.
You see, they assumed he was talking about going
amongst the dispersion of the Greeks.
Think about it.
They thought he was going to a place
that they couldn't come,
and they instantly thought it was about the sellouts.
Why?
Because they did not get down with them,
and there was a complete rejection of them.
And this is why you keep hearing about Paul,
there's no difference between Yahudim and Greek.
But everyone today,
thinks he's talking about the pagan Greeks.
It's absolutely ridiculous.
That's not who he's talking about.
You see, because we don't know this history,
we now want to accept Hellenization,
and we rationalize and say,
because the only manuscripts of the New Testament
are written in Greek now,
not that they were actually all written in Greek,
but that that's the only manuscripts that we have
that's in Greek.
Because of this, we believe
that they should erase the history of the people
and conform to a different culture.
Again, it's like the story of, let's say,
Donald Trump, but China takes over America.
It becomes the dominant culture in this world.
Now, they changed Donald Trump to a Chinese man.
They make him look Chinese,
and they adapt his ways to Chinese culture.
And they say, hey, it's okay,
because China is the main influence now.
That's absolutely ridiculous.
But this is exactly what people do today.
They changed a Hebrew messiah to Greek,
and they gave him a Greek name.
They made him look a whole different way.
And they say that you're wrong and a part of a cult
if you go back to the Hebrew roots,
which makes no sense.
This is the kind of thing that people allow
with the messiah who they claim is their God.
They changed the culture of the people
and adapted it to the Greeks,
even though the Greeks were the absolute enemy
of the Yahudim,
and they hated everything about them and their ways.
The overall majority in Christianity
adapt their faith to the way of the Greeks
rather than the way of the Hebrews.
Matter of fact, there is a major rejection
of the Hebrew roots,
even though everything about the scriptures
is rooted from the Hebrews.
The Bible speaks against the Hebrew roots,
speaks against the actual faith that they say they have.
This is able to happen because people don't know this history
and they don't understand the truly set-apart culture
that our Father led his people through.
Which is why people argue to be called Christians
according to the way of the Greeks,
and they reject anything about the Hebrews.
Though this faith, again, it's actually rooted from the Hebrews.
I'm going to keep repeating it.
Now you know.
The Greeks were against the faith of the Hebrews,
and they tried to make their influence
no more.
If it were up to the Greeks,
you would not have the Messiah.
Now that we understand this,
I'm going to go to the times of the church fathers
and break down how they blended the Hebrew scriptures
with their Greek philosophers.
And that will lead us to the Trinity.
So we will deal with that next.
In the meantime, please remember,
Christianity is a religion that on the surface seems biblical.
But when you dig deep into the doctrines,
it is not a doctrine of service to our Father,
but a doctrine of abusing grace,
editing covenants,
rejecting the way our Father actually chose to reach humanity,
and making it only be about the way Christians want to receive Him.
It lacks the love, obedience, and reverence for our Father that He deserves.
And in the end,
it does not prepare those who follow it
to be ready for what our Father plans to do in the last days.
If you desire to be ready for our Father and His plan for us,
you must come out of this religion of tares
and come to our Father in truth.
Please move to part 15 in this playlist
and we will discuss the early church fathers
and break down how they blended the Hebrew faith
with the Greek philosophers,
creating Christianity.
Click the link to the next video
and let's talk some more.
Be blessed.
Hallelujah.
Praise.
Yah.
Okay.
Thanks again for watching.
If this has blessed you,
please like this and share this with your family and your friends.
This video series is highly important for those trying to be ready for our Father.
This is part 14 of the series.
Click the link or just move to the next video in the playlist.
As always,
I want to thank all who donate and contribute to this ministry.
This series,
it would not be possible without your support.
I thank you sincerely.
Be blessed.
Okay.
Thanks again everyone for watching.
See you in part 15.
I love you all.