Okay, so you should be coming from part 14 of this series.
These videos are a part of a topical series and should be watched from the beginning in order if you're going to understand what is being presented.
So please, if you've not watched from part 1, please stop this video and start back from video 1.
Okay, so in the last video, part 14, we went over the Maccabean Revolt and the events that brought back a rededication to Yahuwah in Judea.
We saw how the Yahudim rejected the Greeks and how much trouble the Greeks brought the Yahudim.
These were some of the events that happened in Judea that separated the Hellenized sellout Yahudim from the true Yahudim in Judea.
You see, there is so much confusion today based upon the scriptures because people lack information and understanding.
And it's not always the fault of the people, but more so the churches and religious leaders, the seminary schools, etc.
Christianity tells the people what they want to hear and not all the details that can provide clarity.
And this is the reason why the book of Matthew...
are not in the Protestant or King James Bible.
They're in the Catholic Bibles, but not in the Bibles of the Protestant Church.
And because of this, confusion is able to be had amongst those in Christianity.
For instance, people use scriptures like...
And people believe that this is talking about pagan Greeks that did not know Yahuwah and served him.
If the book of Maccabees was included in the Bibles, this misunderstanding would not be had because there would be more context and understanding of history.
You see, when Paul was speaking of the Greeks, he was speaking about these scattered Yahudim all over that were called Greeks.
That's why Paul, he didn't say Greeks and Romans, being that this was the period of time in the Roman Empire and he was a Roman citizen.
He didn't say Greeks and Romans, he said Greeks because of who he was talking about.
But if you're not properly taught the history,
and given understanding,
you can make doctrines that are not biblically sound,
but are believable because everyone around you is missing historical context.
And this is precisely what has happened today.
History is important.
I have had recent discussions with people who have spoken against me for reading historical books.
I want to make this clear that historical books do not ever take precedent over the scriptures.
But knowing history is important and it should never be frowned upon to understand the past.
The events in the Bible talk about one...
the same people who are Yashorel,
because they are the only ones in covenant with Yahuwah.
And so what is written in the scriptures is all about them.
But right now, we are in a world that hates Yahuwah and have hijacked and oppressed Yashorel.
Matter of fact, they even erased Yashorel's history and put in a whole other group of people as their replacement.
And to add to my point, the world is not ruled by Yashorel.
It is ruled by the intermingled children of Esau and also heavily influenced by the children of Japheth.
And if you don't understand their history and what they have done, you leave yourself to be deceived.
As quoted from Winston Churchill,
history is written by the victors.
And so with that understanding, we know things from the victor's point of view.
We do not know history from the perspective from those that lost many of the battles.
Now also, the scriptures stop at a certain point in history in the first century.
After the apostles who walked with Yahushua,
we have a gap of history between when the religion of Christ...
Christianity was created and us today.
And that's a huge gap.
So many people want to look at their faith
and believe that they are in a biblically sound faith that has no influence.
I was speaking with a pastor who has a sincere heart
and I believe that he truly loves Yah.
But I also know that the hardest thing to do is admit that you were living in and surrounded by lies.
That is normally the difference with those living in the truth and those who are not.
There has to be humility enough to say, I was deceived.
And if you're not willing to believe that, then you're not going to believe that.
And if you're not willing to believe that, then you're going to believe that.
If you're not willing to admit this to yourself,
you can never break the chains Satan has placed on all of us.
And when you dig down, it all comes down to pride.
Many people don't want to admit that they could be deceived.
And this is a weakness that our enemy likes to exploit to his benefit.
We are not without influence.
So let me illustrate this for you so I can be clear
because like this pastor was trying to say to me,
he says that I don't understand the difference between biblical Christianity and false Christianity.
And he went through a lot.
He went through a lot of history showing that he saw the falsehoods.
But the only thing is that when it came to his Christianity that he follows,
of course, that was the biblical one.
But the question no one seems to want to deal with is
how any kind of Christianity, whether you feel it's biblical or not,
how do you think it came to you?
Meaning, how do you feel that the Christianity that you believe in made it to your influence?
And that question is what people are not properly dealing with.
I'm going to illustrate it for you.
When I'm talking against Christianity, this is what I'm talking about.
For me, you or anyone, and let's just use the United States as an example.
We will use this by illustrating a tree.
Right now, I personally, I'm a leaf on a branch of a tree.
What I'm going to do is lead you to the root.
I was introduced to Christianity from my parents, specifically my mom.
But it's not about her, but it's about the churches that she went to.
We didn't just sit at home and read the Bible only.
We went to church.
In the United States, there are Christian churches everywhere.
Many different denominations, but mostly Protestant.
Right now, I'm not speaking about the Roman Catholic churches.
All these different denominations are different branches on the tree.
Now understand, it does not matter the denomination.
Most pastors, not all, but most, had to go to seminary or theology school to learn how to be a pastor.
For me personally, I've never had a pastor that did not go to some form of seminary training.
From the seminary training,
they were taught how to understand the scriptures.
But let's leave that out and just follow this path.
Christianity in America did not get here by accident.
Both the Roman Catholics and Protestants brought their version of Christianity to America.
You would not be a Christian today without Christianity being brought here.
Does that make sense?
America very well could have been a Muslim nation,
but it was the Christians who found this country and brought the religion here.
The Roman Catholics were first,
and the Protestants from England shortly after.
And in America, the different Protestant denominations,
like the Puritans, the Presbyterians, Baptists, Methodists, etc.,
they came here and spread their beliefs.
And then there's other people that started new branches of denominations here,
like the Pentecostal Church, the Seventh-day Adventists, Jehovah's Witnesses, etc.
They all started here in the United States.
But it would not have been possible without the Protestant church's influence
bringing Christianity here in the first place.
All these denominations come from the foundation of the Protestant church
that they were influenced by.
What I'm trying to explain is that there is a foundation.
You would not be a Christian without the foundation that the Protestant church brought here.
So leaving the Roman church alone for right now,
the Christianity in America is from the foundation of the Protestants in England.
So this branch of United States Christianity that I was influenced from
is developed from a different branch that comes from Christianity in England.
So we must take a look at this.
We must take Christianity from America and bring it to England,
which is why we have been trained to believe that the King James Bible
is the only Bible that we should read.
But Christianity in America is traced back to England,
and they had the English Reformation.
And most denominations here in America, like the Methodist and Presbyterian,
were started in England.
But this Christianity in England is also not without influence,
so we must trace its roots.
When we do this, we see it was spurred from the Protestant Reformation
in Germany for Martin Luther.
And this is a major branch of the tree.
And it's split between other major branches like the Roman Catholic Church
and the Eastern Orthodox Church.
But the branch that I was influenced by in America
is connected to the Protestant Reformation.
And we know it was this event that transformed Europe in the 16th century,
the Protestant Reformation I'm talking about.
And this event influenced denominations across Europe,
like Calvinism in Switzerland and in Amsterdam,
the Baptist denomination was created and later brought into England.
All from the Protestant Reformation.
Now there are, of course, differences in certain doctrines.
But nonetheless, they all come from the same root of the same tree.
And that's what I'm illustrating here.
But if you're not able to correlate that the Christianity that you have been influenced by
has a 500-year span of history that started from the Protestant Reformation,
you're just rejecting history.
So, okay, if you follow these branches,
this covers a 500-year span of history of how Christianity came to you.
Got that.
That's not debatable.
You would not be calling yourself a Christian without this history.
And it has a foundation.
So if we track it further,
the foundation of the Protestant Church is a foundation from the Roman Catholic Church.
Now, I have proved this in the Hijacker series.
I've walked the history down on the Protestant Reformation and proved it.
The Roman Catholic Church is the foundation of the Protestant Churches,
except there were some differences and the biggest change is the authority.
There would be no Protestant Church without the Roman Catholic Church.
So if you follow this branch of Christianity from the Protestants,
you will see that it actually grows out from the Roman Catholic Church from the trunk.
So if you follow how Christianity got here and follow the branches,
you are now attached to the Roman Catholic Church.
And from this, we can track the history of the Roman Church back to the 6th century,
when Pope Gregory I consolidated the lands controlled by the Pope's authority to the papal states.
We are here, right in the trunk of the tree.
And if you just track the history of the Roman Catholic Church,
if you just track that history up from the 6th century to the Protestant Reformation branch,
that's another 1,000 year span of history of Christianity.
But okay, now that we are in the trunk,
as we go through the history of the Roman Catholic Church,
as we go further back to let's say the 4th century to the Council of Constantinople,
or even earlier when Constantine brought unity of doctrines in the Council of Nicaea,
we are still in the main trunk, but getting closer to the roots.
But we're still in the trunk.
Now what the Roman Church wants everyone to believe,
is that the roots of this tree of Christianity are from the church being built on Peter.
But what an understanding of history does,
is it shows that there was a break of influence,
where Roman pagan converts broke away from the influence of the Yahudim apostles,
and they began to take the authority,
and they were the ones who created the religion of Christianity.
You see, the roots of Christianity do not start with the Yahudim apostles.
The roots of Christianity start from the early church fathers,
and it was Satan,
who planted these early church fathers as seeds,
and let their influence grow.
But due to the practice of syncretism,
we discussed this in part 10,
they were able to merge the Hebrew scriptures into this new faith of Christianity,
and make it seem like the roots starts with the apostles,
but it does not.
It's just a version of what the apostles were spreading,
and that's why they're tares.
They are seeds that grow at the same time as Yahusha's seeds,
but when they are fully grown,
we see the fruit that they produce are totally different,
and that's why they're tares.
Christianity is built from the root of tares,
and they are attached to the seed that Satan planted,
and those seeds are influenced by Greek philosophy,
which goes back to the mystery religions of the pagan empires before it,
like Persia and Egypt.
It's why Christians focus on the Hellenized Greek name of the Messiah,
and the Hellenized Greek branding of the faith.
So just follow all that history through,
following the growth of the tree,
and you can see where your influence stems from.
And I challenge anyone who disagrees,
to clearly show what you think I'm missing.
Separate the roots from the time of the scriptures and the early apostles,
and understand that there is a break in history that we are not educated fully about.
And there was a time when others took control of the faith of the Hebrews,
and began to be the ones who spread it to the world.
And if you follow it from these early church fathers,
to the Council of Nicaea,
to the founding of the Roman Catholic Church,
which later became the Holy Roman Empire,
which then there was a split 700 years later,
creating the Protestant Church,
now we're off the trunk and into a new branch,
which then made it to England,
a new branch, which then made it to America,
making smaller branches,
which then was taught to the Americans who live in this country,
and also taught to the slaves who were brought here.
Bring it to this modern day,
the Christianity that everyone knows,
you would not know it if it was not for Rome.
And it is what happened when this religion was created that I reject.
It's not about false Christianity,
or biblical Christianity,
it should not even be called Christianity.
Someone decided to take the influence of the Greeks,
and it was not the Yahudin.
It was actually decided by the leaders of Christianity,
that they did not want any influence from the Yahudin.
Christianity is a bait and switch.
You think it's about the faith that the apostles spread,
that's biblical,
but there is a mixture of leaven that the majority wants to ignore.
And the thing is that I'm just exposing it,
and the only way that is done is going to be through history.
People can debate doctrines all day long,
but if you don't look at how you became influenced by something,
and recognize that it's possible that you were steered by your enemy,
you will always be a tool for your enemy.
Some people just don't want to go as far as I am,
because they feel it's dangerous or radical.
It's hard for them to recognize that the whole foundation is tainted,
because that means that everything you were about and doing for a majority of your life was tainted.
All your degrees, all your training, all the influence you had,
the people you introduced to the scriptures,
they all had leaven.
And the thing is that instead of making it about the ultimate truth,
it's easy to just ignore it and make it about me, the one who's exposing it.
And I get it, but it does not change the truth.
It just determines what side of it you are on.
Many of you choose to be comfortable rather than an enemy of this world.
Because you know what?
You do not really know what our Messiah truly meant when he says the world will hate you,
until you start going against Christians.
I have never experienced the kind of hate and people looking to come against me,
until I spoke against Christianity.
When you go against Christians,
none of them walk in those fruits of the Spirit like they like to proclaim.
None of them try to save my soul because they think I'm wrong.
They literally hate me.
Some of them, I'm all that they think about.
It's the fruit that Christianity produces,
and as we are in the last days,
the fruit is becoming easier to see and discern.
And people need to come to terms with it.
But here's the thing.
If you don't know the history, it's easy to deflect.
And that's why I'm bringing this all out and testing Christianity.
And nowhere since the beginning of this series has Christianity stood up to the test.
And when it is exposed,
when you bring it up to other Christians,
it's only deflecting and ignoring facts and then them giving personal attacks.
What Christians cannot deal with, they just ignore.
Cognitive dissonance.
So I want to be clear that this is why I reject Christianity.
Because it stems from the root that began from the early church fathers,
that were tares that Satan planted through his spreading of Greek philosophy.
This is the beginning of my problem.
My problem has nothing to do with the scriptures,
but how the early church fathers applied these scriptures.
And this is what I have been showing.
But what I'm going to do now is walk it all down and directly prove it.
So let's start here.
The second century.
All the apostles are now deceased,
and the faith known as the Way is being spread.
This is the beginning of the root that's beginning to grow.
The apostles went to all the synagogues spread around Asia Minor
to speak the truth about repentance and the kingdom of Elohim that was coming.
They told everyone about what happened with the Messiah
and how he was raised from the dead.
Now let's be clear that I am not saying that there was not sincere and true followers
that converted and truly followed the Way.
That's not what I'm saying.
I'm just saying that the influence that Christianity is based from
does not include and does not come from that influence.
They suppressed that other influence.
When Christianity was started,
there were many changes from the influence of the Yahudim apostles
versus the ways of the early church fathers.
For instance, a great place to start is with the Sabbath.
Now, we know from Acts that they were called Christians first in Antioch.
Okay, well, it's less about what they were called
and more about what they called themselves.
But either way, people were called Christians.
And in the second century, there were Christians
who were not influenced by the apostles but by others.
And it is these Christians,
that I have the issue with.
Here's the thing.
Many of these people, they have writings.
It's not lost or hidden.
It's all accessible.
The majority of Christians who disagree with me
have never really read the writings of these men.
I have and therefore this is why I speak passionately against them.
Let me give an example.
We will start by understanding this
by discussing Justin the Martyr.
Now, Justin the Martyr has writings
where he describes himself and his conversion.
What I'm about to go through is from his writing
Dialogue with Trifold.
Now, please note, I'm placing a link to all the downloads
to these writings that I'll be using
for anyone who wants to study this for themselves.
You can take these writings and look at them yourself.
I'm not just out here giving you information
but I'm also giving you the resources
that you can review yourself.
Now, in this writing, he speaks about his conversion.
Now, before his conversion, he describes himself
as an earnest searcher after the truth
among the various philosophies of the time.
Stoic,
peripatetic,
which means Aristotelian,
Pythagorean.
He was amongst all that philosophy.
That is, until the day that,
as he was meditating by the seaside,
he met one who showed him the unsatisfying character
of philosophy as such
and bid him turn to the Bible
with prayer for a comprehension of such matters.
This he did and he found that in the prophets
and the friends of Christ was true philosophy.
He writes,
In this way and for these reasons
am I a philosopher.
He then began to desire that all should find the truth
and know Christ.
You can find that on chapter 8, page 16 on the PDF.
Now, after his conversion,
we know he felt very strongly
the duty of imparting his knowledge of the scripture
and his responsibility towards all
with whom he came in contact.
And in order that he might have more opportunities,
he continued to wear his philosopher's cloak
and he traveled widely.
Okay, whatever.
In this writing,
he speaks a great deal about philosophy.
He says,
But without philosophy and right reason,
none can possibly have practical wisdom.
Therefore, every human being ought to study philosophy
and deem it the greatest and most valuable act of all,
putting all other things in the second and third place.
For if they are made dependent on philosophy,
they are of some value and worthy of acceptation.
But if deprived of it and lacking its accompaniment,
they are, for those who pursue them,
only burdensome and vulgar.
And that's on chapter 3, page 7.
So he clearly believes in philosophy.
There's a lot more I can show,
but that's not my main point right now.
He was once a pagan,
but converted to Christianity.
Now, let me make my point.
The early believers,
the followers of the Way,
from the first century,
they observed the seventh day as the Sabbath.
The apostles rested on the Sabbath.
But the Christians,
the true Christians,
the root I have been talking about,
they started observing Sunday as their day of worship
because they believed that Yahushua was resurrected on Sunday.
Justin the Martyr, in his writing,
The First Apology,
in the 67th chapter,
named Weekly Worship of the Christians,
he writes,
But Sunday is the day on which we all hold our common assembly,
because it is the first day on which God,
having wrought a change in the darkness and matter,
made the world.
And Jesus Christ, our Savior,
on the same day rose from the dead.
For he was crucified on the day before that of Saturn,
Saturday,
and on that day after that of Saturn,
which is the day of the sun,
having appeared to his apostles and disciples.
He taught them these things,
which we have submitted to you also for your consideration.
Okay, so what I'm doing here is providing historical evidence
from the writings of the early church fathers
that explain the history of why Christians go to church on Sunday.
But even more so,
in the writings of Justin the Martyr,
we see why Christians reject the Sabbath.
In his writing,
Dialogue of Trypho,
in chapter 10 on page 20,
Justin speaks this about Christians.
In the dialogue,
Trypho asks him about why he does not keep the Sabbath.
And Justin responds with this,
Is there any other fault you find with us,
my friends,
save this,
that we do not live in accordance with the law,
and do not circumcise the flesh as did your forefathers,
and do not keep the Sabbath as you do?
Or are also false accusations against our life and morals made among you?
Understand,
at the time of the beginning of Christianity,
from its foundation,
these Christians rejected the ways of the Yahudim,
and they made their own doctrines.
And the same debates that we are having today
are the same debates that they had at the beginning of Christianity.
It's because of the lawless fruit that Christianity produces.
Let me show you.
In the same writing,
the Dialogue with Trypho,
Trypho,
a Yahudim,
says this to Justin,
still in chapter 10 on page 21,
But we are especially at a loss about this,
that you,
saying you worship God,
and thinking yourself superior to other people,
separate from them in no respect,
and do not make your life different from the heathen,
in that you keep neither the feasts,
nor the Sabbaths,
nor have circumcision,
and,
moreover,
though you set your hopes on a man that was crucified,
you yet hope to obtain some good from God,
though you do not do his commandments.
Now have you not read,
That soul shall be cut off from his people,
which shall not be circumcised on the eighth day?
The charge refers alike to strangers and to purchased slaves.
It follows that when you have directly despised this covenant,
you neglect the commands that come afterwards.
And as persons who know God,
you attempt to persuade us,
though you practice none of these things which they who fear God do.
If therefore you have any defense to make with reference to these points,
and can show us how you have any hope at all,
even though you do not keep the law,
we would very gladly hear from you.
So Trypho,
who I'm not even sure is a real person,
but either way,
he is arguing the same exact things that we are saying to Christians right now.
Literally having the same conversations I have with Christians today
in the comment section of these videos
is what this man Trypho was saying to Justin.
And this is where Justin responded.
Chapter 11, page 22.
There will never be any other God, Trypho,
and there never was from all eternity.
So said I to him,
save he who made and established this universe.
Nor do we consider that we have one God and you another,
but him only who brought your fathers out of the land of Egypt
by a mighty hand and a stretched out arm.
Nor have we set our hopes on any other,
for there is none,
but only on him on whom you also have set yours,
the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.
Yet our hope is set on him,
not by means of Moses,
nor by means of the law,
for then we should assuredly be doing the same as you.
For in fact I have read,
Trypho,
that there is to be both a final law
and a disposition that is superior to all others,
which now must be observed by all those
who lay claim to the inheritance of God.
For the law given that orb
is already antiquated
and belongs to you alone,
but that other belongs to all men absolutely.
And a law set over against a law
has made the one before it to cease.
And a disposition coming into existence afterwards
has in like manner limited any former one.
And as eternal and final law was Christ given to us,
and this disposition is sure,
after which there is no law or ordinance or command.
If therefore God proclaimed a new disposition
as about to be established,
and this for a light of the nations,
we then see and are sure that by the name of him
who was crucified,
Jesus Christ,
men part from idols and all other iniquity
and draw near to God,
and make confession of him,
and worship enduring unto death.
And from their works
and the power that accompanies them,
all can understand that he is the new law
and the new disposition
and the expectation of those
from among all the nations,
who await the good things
that come to them at the hands of God.
For we are the true
and spiritual Israelitish nation,
and the race of Judah,
and of Jacob,
and Isaac,
and Abraham,
who when he was still uncircumcised,
received witness from God for his faith
and was blessed
and was called father of many nations.
We,
I say,
are all this,
who were brought nigh to God
by him who was crucified,
even Christ,
as will be demonstrated in the course of our discussion.
So many things were said in this response,
but it was down to the major problem of Christianity,
which is replacement theology.
And the main doctrine of Christianity
they reject our father's laws
and believe that everything is now about them.
And they are the new spiritual Israel.
You know,
Christians today use the spiritual Israel nonsense
like it's scriptural.
It's not.
It's just doctrine from the early church fathers.
This is the mid-second century
when this writing was created.
And this was what the mindset around Christianity
was being built upon.
If you review the mindsets of Christians today,
it's not hard to see that they are clearly influenced
by men like Justin.
It's just that they don't know it.
They believe that they are spiritual Israel
because they are taking over the covenant
and making it be about them.
Spiritual Israel is a complete false doctrine of men
that comes from the early church fathers.
In Justin's writings,
he taught that God,
as he refers to him,
God instituted the keeping of the Sabbath for Israel
as a sign because of their unrighteousness.
He states that it was never intended to be moral law.
He taught that the observance of the Sabbath
was a denial of the new covenant.
The new law required a perpetual Sabbath.
In chapter 12, page 25, he writes,
A second circumcision is now necessary,
and ye are making much of your flesh.
The new law wishes you to keep Sabbath all the time,
and you think you are acting piously
by being lazy for one day,
not considering the reason why it was commanded you?
And if you eat unleavened bread,
you say you have fulfilled the will of God?
It is not in these things
that our Lord takes pleasure.
If any among you is a false swearer or thief,
let him cease.
If any adulterer, let him repent.
Then he has kept the delightsome
and true Sabbaths of God.
If any has not clean hands,
let him wash, then he is clean.
He is talking about morals instead of the Torah.
If you remember,
this was discussed in part 12.
And this is the foundation of Christianity.
And people believe this today.
They believe that keeping the Sabbath
is about doing what's morally right.
This was from the mindset from the second century.
They justify why they don't keep the commandments,
and they believe this is what the God of Israel desires.
They do not know him.
And what I'm proving here
is that the reason why Christians,
they go to church on Sunday and reject the Sabbath,
is not from actual biblical doctrine
that comes from the apostles.
No.
There is no doctrine in the scriptures
for the rejection of keeping the Sabbath.
The doctrine actually comes
from the early church fathers' doctrines
that have been passed down through Christianity.
And Justin the Martyr,
he proves it.
This goes to the discussion about the eighth day.
He believes that the eighth day
possessed a certain mysterious meaning,
which the seventh day did not possess,
and which was put into law by God.
In the same writing,
Dialogue with Trifo,
in chapter 24, page 29,
he says,
This too I could therefore prove to you,
gentlemen,
I said that the eighth day
had a certain mystical meaning
which was proclaimed by God
by these means,
rather than the seventh.
You see,
he believed that Yahuwah
saving eight people on Noah's Ark
signified the relationship
between the number eight and salvation.
He believed that
Yah's instruction for Israel
to circumcise their boys on the eighth day
was a literal command
picturing the future Christian circumcision of the heart.
And now,
they recognize Sunday
as a new eighth day.
This is all philosophical thinking.
When you hear people use numbers like this,
especially talking about the mystical meaning,
they're going back to the philosophy
of Pythagoras.
In chapter 41,
on page 82,
he writes,
For the first day of the week,
the first indeed of all the days
there ever were
is further called the eighth,
according to the number of all the days
of their cycle,
and thus it ever remains the first.
I don't know what he's talking about,
but that's what he believes.
And more of them believe this too.
Clement of Alexandria
in the second century,
in his writings,
first off,
he clearly speaks about
how he blends Greek philosophy
with the Christian faith.
But not to get off track with it,
let's deal with what he said
about the eighth day.
Towards the end of the second century,
he went as far as to claim
that in Plato's writing,
The Republic,
Plato himself had prophesied
the significance of the Christian eighth day.
He basically prophesied of it.
On page 777,
in the book Stramata or Miscellanies,
Clement of Alexandria writes,
And the Lord's day,
Plato,
prophetically speaks of
in the tenth book of the Republic.
In these words,
And when seven days have passed
to each of them in the meadow,
on the eighth,
they are to set out
and arrive in four days.
You see, this is what they believe.
They have changed the Sabbath
to what they call the eighth day.
Now, they've masked this
by not calling it the eighth day,
but they call it the Lord's day.
And it just so happens
that the Lord's day
is on their Sunday.
And this is what the foundation
of Christianity is built upon.
And we all know this
because Christians all go to church on Sunday,
but nobody really knows why.
You see, Christians,
they don't observe the Sabbath.
What they do
is they keep what they call
the Lord's day.
And if you don't believe this,
let's look at the catechisms
of the Roman Catholic Church,
where the roots formed
into the trunk of the tree.
In the catechism,
number 2174,
it writes,
Jesus rose from the dead
on the first day of the week.
Because it is the first day,
the day of Christ's resurrection
recalls the first creation.
Because it is the eighth day,
following the Sabbath,
it symbolizes the new creation
ushered in by Christ's resurrection.
For Christians,
it has become the first of all days,
the first of all feasts,
the Lord's day, Sunday.
We all gather on the day of the sun,
for it is the first day,
after the Jewish Sabbath,
but also the first day,
when God,
separating matter from darkness,
made the world.
And on this same day,
Jesus Christ,
our Savior,
rose from the dead.
Sunday,
fulfillment of the Sabbath.
This is what they believe.
This is what Christians do.
The other catechism,
number 2175,
Sunday is expressly distinguished
from the Sabbath,
which it follows chronologically
every week.
For Christians,
its ceremonial observance
replaces that of the Sabbath.
In Christ's Passover,
Sunday fulfills the spiritual truth
of the Jewish Sabbath
and announces man's
eternal rest in God.
For worship under the law
prepared for the mystery of Christ,
and what was done there
prefigured some aspects of Christ.
Those who lived according to
the old order of things
have come to a new hope,
no longer keeping the Sabbath,
but the Lord's day,
in which our life is blessed by him
and by his death.
And again,
this is the doctrine
that Christians hold.
It's just that they don't know it.
And what they do
is they make excuses.
They use scriptures
like Acts chapter 20.
Now,
on the first day of the week,
when the disciples came together
to break bread,
Paul,
ready to depart the next day,
spoke to them
and continued his message
until midnight.
Acts chapter 20,
verse seven.
This is what they use
to justify
why they go to church on Sunday.
But that scripture right there,
that's not a doctrinal statement
that has determined
that the Sabbath
is no longer valid
and you need to keep the Lord's day.
People do not know
what they're doing.
Christians don't keep the Sabbath
not because it's scriptural,
but because they follow
the tares that were planted.
This is doctrine
that was given from the foundation.
Christians don't know the influence,
but the writings are all given
and made plain is right there.
The roots from Christianity
changed the Sabbath day
and made a whole new doctrine of men.
And Christians follow this doctrine
more than they follow the word.
And they make as many excuses
that they can to justify it.
You want to be biblical?
This is what's biblical.
The Sabbath was a commandment
etched in stone
and in the new covenant,
instead of Yah
writing the commandments on stone,
he is writing it on our hearts.
But because people
are being led by tares,
they're not actually having
Yahweh write anything on their hearts,
but they are following tares
that are religious,
but don't truly know our Father.
Most Christians
do not know our Father.
The scripture says,
remember the Sabbath day
to keep it holy.
Six days
you shall labor
and do all your work.
But the seventh day
is the Sabbath
of the Sabbath day.
The Sabbath day
is the Sabbath
of the Sabbath day.
The Sabbath day
is the Sabbath
of the Sabbath day.
The Sabbath day
is the Sabbath
of Yahuwah,
your Elohim.
In it,
you shall do no work,
you,
nor your son,
nor your daughter,
nor your male servant,
nor your female servant,
nor your cattle,
nor your stranger
who is within your gates.
For in six days
Yahuwah made the heavens
and the earth,
the sea,
and all that is in them,
and rested the seventh day.
Therefore,
Yahuwah blessed
the Sabbath day
and hallowed it.
That's Exodus chapter 20
verses 8 through 11.
It also says,
Then Elohim
blessed the seventh day
and sanctified the Sabbath day.
The Sabbath day
sanctified it,
because in it
he rested from all his work
which Elohim
had created
and made.
Genesis chapter 2
verse 3.
And even more
for Gentiles,
they should know this
and they should keep this.
They shouldn't say,
well, the Sabbath
was not made for us.
We don't have to keep
those commands.
You should read this.
It's prophesied about you.
Also,
the sons of the stranger
who joined themselves
to Yahuwah
to serve him
and to love the name
of Yahuwah,
to be his servants,
everyone who keeps
from defiling the Sabbath
holds fast my covenant.
Even them
I will bring
to my holy mountain
and make them
joyful in my house
of prayer.
Their burnt offerings
and their sacrifices
will be accepted
on my altar,
for my house
shall be called
a house of prayer
for all nations.
Adonai Yahuwah,
who gathers
the outcasts
of Yahshu'el,
says,
Yet I will gather
to him others
besides those
who are gathered
to him.
That's Isaiah chapter 56
verses 6 through 8.
This is the Gentiles
that he was
talking about
and that he will accept
those that do not
defile his Sabbath.
By following Christianity
you are being led
to be rejected
and your Christian
churches
are not telling you.
Now let me ask you,
have I,
therefore,
become your enemy
because I tell you
the truth?
Christianity
has made
a whole new day.
New doctrines
amend
and Christians
they follow it blindly.
In their defense
everyone wants to say
that they don't follow
the early church fathers
and they aren't
influenced by them
in all of their doctrines.
People say this
because they just don't know.
And you know what?
The time of ignorance
is over.
This should be very clear
that Christians
are following doctrines
of men.
This is why
Christians go to church
on Sunday.
It's been made
very clear.
If there is not
a more clear example
of the break
that Christians have
from the scriptures
I don't know
what else can prove it.
I challenge you
to ask your family
and your friends
why they go to church
on Sundays.
Don't make an argument.
Just ask the question
and listen to the answers.
Have a discussion
with them.
Ask them
if there is
any verse
that they have
that distinctly tells them
that we are not
to keep the Sabbath anymore.
Just listen to what
they have to say.
Make it a discussion.
And then
if they allow you to
share with them
where this doctrine
actually comes from.
Ask them
do they believe
that they are following
the eighth day?
Do they even know
what that is?
Ask them
where you get
the Lord's day from.
Just ask them questions
and then
ask them
if you can prove
that it is not found
in the scriptures
but from doctrines of men
from the early church fathers
would they be willing
to listen?
So I have provided
the PDFs
with these writings
from these early
church fathers
and I have made a PDF
with their quotes
and where you can find them
in the writings.
It's all right here.
If you are subscribed
to the email list
you should have
got an email
but the link
is in the description box
for anyone else.
If someone sincerely
wants to understand
it's all documented.
The homework
is done.
And I hope
it breaks
many chains.
I did not intend
to go here
with this message
but this is where
Yahweh took it
and I'm glad.
We must continue
so we will go
into more of how
these early church fathers
built this faith
of Christianity.
Please
don't follow these tears.
Keep the Sabbath holy.
We will continue
to discuss
how these early Christians
created Christianity.
In the next video
we are going
to discuss
the Trinity.
In the meantime
please remember
Christianity
on the surface
seems biblical.
But when you dig deep
into the doctrines
it is not a doctrine
of service to our Father
but a doctrine
of abusing grace
editing covenants
rejecting the way
our Father
actually chose
to reach humanity
and making it
only be
about the way
Christians
want to receive Him.
It lacks the love
obedience
and reverence
for our Father
that He deserves.
And in the end
it does not prepare
those who follow it
to be ready
for what our Father
plans to do
and if you desire
to be ready
for our Father
and His plan for us
you must come out
of this religion of tears
and come to our Father
in truth.
Please move
to part 16
in this playlist
and we will discuss
more about
how the early church fathers
created Christianity.
Click the link
to the next video
and let's talk some more.
Be blessed.
Hallelujah.
Praise
Yah.
Okay.
Thanks again
for watching.
If this has blessed you
please like this
and share this video
with your family
and friends.
Share this with Christians
that still go to church
on Sundays
and let them see
how this doctrine
is not biblical.
This video series
is highly important
for those trying
to be ready
for our Father.
This is part 15
of the series.
Click the link
or just move on
to the next video
in the playlist.
As always
I want to thank
all who donate
and contribute
to this ministry.
This series
it would not be possible
without your support.
I thank you
sincerely.
Be blessed.
Thanks again everyone
for watching.
See you in part 16.
I love you all.